<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Asteroid comet of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/asteroid_comet</link><description>RSS feed of the asteroid comet of the day.</description><item><title>2024 YR4</title><description>2024 YR4 is an asteroid with an estimated diameter of 40 to 90 metres (130 to 300 ft) that is classified as an Apollo-type (Earth-crossing) near-Earth object. From 27 January to 20 February 2025, it had an impact rating of 3 on the Torino scale, with a maximum estimated probability of 3.1% that it would impact Earth on 22 December 2032. The threat peaked on 18 February 2025, but later predictions generated from additional observations produced a negligible chance of an Earth impact in 2032 and reduced the asteroid's Torino rating to 0. It retains a small chance of impacting the Moon in 2032.
The asteroid was discovered by the Chilean station of the Asteroid Terrestrial-impact Last Alert System (ATLAS) at Río Hurtado on 27 December 2024. When additional observations suggested it had an impact probability of over 1%, it triggered the first step in planetary-defense responses, which prompted several major telescopes to gather data about the asteroid and led United Nations–endorsed space agencies to begin planning asteroid threat mitigation.
The asteroid made a close approach to Earth at a distance of 828,800 kilometres (515,000 miles; 2.156 lunar distances) on 25 December 2024, two days before its discovery, and will be moving away from the Sun until November 2026. Its next close approach will take place on 17 December 2028. Analysis of spectral and photometric time series suggests that 2024 YR4 is a stony S-type (most likely), L-type or K-type asteroid, with a rotation period of approximately 19.5 minutes. A number of known asteroids, including other virtual impactors, follow orbits somewhat consistent with that of 2024 YR4.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_YR4</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 05:08:03 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>