<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Astronomical event of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/astronomical_event</link><description>RSS feed of the astronomical event of the day.</description><item><title>The Twilight Saga: Eclipse</title><description>The Twilight Saga: Eclipse (or simply Eclipse) is a 2010 American romantic fantasy film directed by David Slade from a screenplay by Melissa Rosenberg, based on the 2007 novel Eclipse by Stephenie Meyer. It is the sequel to The Twilight Saga: New Moon (2009) and the third installment in The Twilight Saga film series. The film stars Kristen Stewart, Robert Pattinson, and Taylor Lautner, reprising their roles as Bella Swan, Edward Cullen, and Jacob Black, respectively.  Bryce Dallas Howard joins the cast as returning character Victoria, who was previously portrayed by Rachelle Lefevre in the first two films. In the film, Bella explores her comprises with both Jacob and Edward, and form an alliance between them, werewolves and vampires, as they battle an army of newborn vampires. 
Summit Entertainment announced it had greenlit the film on February 20, 2009. Principal photography began on August 17, in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, and finished on October 31, with post-production beginning early the following month.
The Twilight Saga: Eclipse premiered at the Nokia Theatre in Los Angeles, California on June 24, 2010, and was theatrically released in the United States on June 30, by Summit Entertainment. It became the first The Twilight Saga film to be released in IMAX.  The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $698.5 million worldwide, becoming the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2010. Critics praised the action sequences, visual effects, Dallas Howard's performance, and Shore's musical score, but criticized its pacing, most of the other performances, and the screenplay. It held the record for biggest midnight opening in the United States and Canada, grossing $30.1 million, beating The Twilight Saga: New Moon until it was surpassed by Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 2 (2011). The film then scored the biggest Wednesday opening in the United States and Canada with $68.5 million, beating Transformers: Revenge of the Fallen (2009). The Twilight Saga: Eclipse has also become the film with the widest independent release, beating The Twilight Saga: New Moon, and the widest domestic release, playing in 4,416 theaters, beating Iron Man 2, which released the same year until it was surpassed by Despicable Me 2 (2013).
The film received two sequels, The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn – Part 1 and The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn – Part 2, in 2011 and 2012, respectively.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Twilight_Saga:_Eclipse</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 05:02:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>