<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Astronomy fact of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/astronomy_fact</link><description>RSS feed of the astronomy fact of the day.</description><item><title>Amateur astronomy</title><description>Amateur astronomy is a hobby where participants enjoy observing, studying, or imaging celestial objects in the sky using the unaided eye, binoculars, telescopes, and other gadgets. Although scientific research may not be their primary goal, some amateur astronomers contribute to citizen science by monitoring variable stars, double stars, sunspots, and occultations of stars by the Moon or asteroids, as well as by discovering transient astronomical events, such as comets, galactic novae or supernovae in other galaxies.
Amateur astronomers do not use the field of astronomy as their primary source of income or support, as well as typically having no professional degree in astrophysics or advanced academic training in the subject.  Most amateur astronomers are hobbyists, while others have a high degree of experience in astronomy and may often assist and work alongside professional astronomers. Many astronomers have studied the sky throughout history in an amateur framework; however, since the beginning of the twentieth century, professional astronomy has become a clearly distinguished activity from amateur astronomy and associated activities.
Amateur astronomers typically view the sky at night, when most celestial objects and astronomical events are visible, but others observe during the daytime by viewing the Sun and solar eclipses.  Some observe the sky using nothing more than their eyes or binoculars, while more dedicated amateurs often use portable telescopes or telescopes situated in their private or club observatories. Amateurs commonly join amateur astronomical societies, which can advise, educate, or guide individuals towards ways of finding and observing celestial objects. Astronomical societies also promote the science of astronomy among the general public.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amateur_astronomy</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:29:30 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>