<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Astronomical event of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/astronomical_event</link><description>RSS feed of the astronomical event of the day.</description><item><title>List of lunar eclipses in the 21st century</title><description>During the 21st century, there will be 228 lunar eclipses of which 86 will be penumbral, 57 will be partial and 85 will be total. Of the total eclipses, 24 will be central, in the sense that the Moon will pass through the very center (axis) of the Earth's shadow (for more information see gamma). In the 21st century, the greatest number of eclipses in one year is four, in 2009, 2020, 2038, 2056, 2085, and 2096. The predictions given here are by Fred Espenak of NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center.
The longest measured duration in which the Earth completely covered the Moon, known as totality, was during the lunar eclipse of July 27, 2018. This total lunar eclipse had a maximum duration of 1 hour, 42 minutes, and 57 seconds. The longest possible duration of a total lunar eclipse is 1 hour and 47 minutes.[a]

The table contains the date and time of the greatest eclipse (in dynamical time, which in this case is the time when the axis of the Earth's shadow passes over the Moon; this is in (Ephemeris Time). The number of the saros series that the eclipse belongs to is given, followed by the type of the eclipse (either total, partial or penumbral), the gamma of the eclipse (how centrally the Moon passed through the Earth's shadow), and both the penumbral and umbral magnitude of the eclipse (the fraction of the Moon's diameter obscured by the Earth). For each eclipse, the duration of the eclipse is given, as well as the eclipse's contacts (the points at which the Moon reaches and exits the Earth's penumbra and umbra).
Eclipses are listed in sets by lunar years, repeating every 12 months for each node. Ascending node eclipses are given a red background highlight, and descending node eclipses are given a blue background highlight.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_lunar_eclipses_in_the_21st_century</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 05:01:55 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>