<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Astronomy fact of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/astronomy_fact</link><description>RSS feed of the astronomy fact of the day.</description><item><title>Neutrino astronomy</title><description>Neutrino astronomy is a branch of astronomy that gathers information about astronomical objects by observing and studying neutrinos emitted by them with the help of neutrino detectors in special Earth observatories. It is an emerging field in astroparticle physics providing insights into the high-energy and non-thermal processes in the universe. 
Neutrinos are nearly massless and electrically neutral or chargeless elementary particles. They are created as a result of certain types of radioactive decay, nuclear reactions such as those that take place in the Sun or high energy astrophysical phenomena, in nuclear reactors, or when cosmic rays hit atoms in the atmosphere. Neutrinos rarely interact with matter (only via the weak nuclear force), travel at nearly the speed of light in straight lines, pass through large amounts of matter without any notable absorption or without being deflected by magnetic fields. Unlike photons, neutrinos rarely scatter along their trajectory. But like photons, neutrinos are some of the most common particles in the universe. Because of this, neutrinos offer a unique opportunity to observe processes that are inaccessible to optical telescopes, such as reactions in the Sun's core. Neutrinos that are created in the Sun's core are barely absorbed, so a large quantity of them escape from the Sun and reach the Earth. Neutrinos can also offer a very strong pointing direction compared to charged particle cosmic rays.
Neutrinos are very hard to detect due to their non-interactive nature. In order to detect neutrinos, scientists have to shield the detectors from cosmic rays, which can penetrate hundreds of meters of rock. Neutrinos, on the other hand, can go through the entire planet without being absorbed, like "ghost particles". Thus neutrino detectors are placed many hundreds of meter underground, usually at the bottom of mines. There a neutrino detection liquid such as a Chlorine-rich solution is placed; the neutrinos react with a Chlorine isotope and can create radioactive Argon. Gallium to Germanium conversion has also been used. The IceCube Neutrino Observatory built in 2010 in the south pole is the biggest neutrino detector, consisting of thousands of optical sensors buried 500 meters underneath a cubic kilometer of deep, ultra-transparent ice, detects light emitted by charged particles that are produced when a single neutrino collides with a proton or neutron inside an atom. The resulting nuclear reaction produces secondary particles traveling at high speeds that give off a blue light called Cherenkov radiation. Super-Kamiokande in Japan and ANTARES and KM3NeT in the Mediterranean are some other important neutrino detectors.
Since neutrinos interact weakly, neutrino detectors must have large target masses (often thousands of tons). The detectors also must use shielding and effective software to remove background signal. Since neutrinos are very difficult to detect, the only bodies that have been studied in this way are the sun and the supernova SN1987A, which exploded in 1987. Scientist predicted that supernova explosions would produce bursts of neutrinos, and a similar burst was actually detected from Supernova 1987A.
In the future neutrino astronomy promises to discover other aspects of the universe, including coincidental gravitational waves, gamma ray bursts, the cosmic neutrino background, origins of ultra-high-energy neutrinos, neutrino properties (such as neutrino mass hierarchy), dark matter properties, etc. It will become an integral part of multi-messenger astronomy, complementing gravitational astronomy and traditional telescopic astronomy.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neutrino_astronomy</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 05:10:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>