<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Constellation of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/constellation</link><description>RSS feed of the constellation of the day.</description><item><title>Scorpio (astrology)</title><description>Scorpio (♏︎) (Ancient Greek: Σκορπιός, romanized: Skorpiós, Latin for "scorpion") is the eighth astrological sign in the zodiac, originating from the constellation of Scorpius. It spans 210–240° ecliptic longitude. Under the tropical zodiac (most commonly used in Western astrology), the Sun transits this sign on average from October 23 to November 21. Depending on which zodiac system one uses, someone born under the influence of Scorpio may be called a Scorpio or a Scorpionic.

Scorpio is one of the water signs, the others being Cancer and Pisces. It is a fixed, negative sign. According to The Astrology Bible, Scorpio's colors are deep red, maroon, black, and brown.

According to Greek mythology, its representation as a scorpion is related to the Greek legend of  Orion and how a scorpion stung him to death (said to be why Orion sets as Scorpius rises in the sky). Another Greek myth recounts how a scorpion caused the horses of the Sun to bolt when they were being driven by the inexperienced youth Phaethon.

		
			
			
		
		
			
			
		
		
			
			
		
		
			
			
		

Allen, Richard Hinckley (1899). Star-names and Their Meanings. G.E. Stechert.
Astronomical Applications Department (2011). Multiyear Computer Interactive Almanac. 2.2.2. Washington DC: US Naval Observatory. Longitude of Sun, apparent geocentric ecliptic of date, interpolated to find time of crossing 0°, 30°....
Hall, Judy (2005). The Astrology Bible: The Definitive Guide to the Zodiac. New York: Sterling. ISBN 1402727593.
Lewis, James R. (2003). The Astrology Book: The Encyclopedia of Heavenly Influences (2nd ed.). Detroit: Visible Ink Press. ISBN 1578591449.
"Scorpio". dictionary.com. n.d. Retrieved October 14, 2022.
"Scorpius, constellation and astrological sign". Britannica.com. 2023. Retrieved July 24, 2023.

 Media related to Scorpio at Wikimedia Commons</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scorpio_(astrology)</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 05:01:44 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>