<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Galaxy of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/galaxy</link><description>RSS feed of the galaxy of the day.</description><item><title>Super Mario Galaxy 2</title><description>Super Mario Galaxy 2 is a 2010 platform game developed and published by Nintendo for the Wii. It was first announced at E3 2009 and is the sequel to 2007's Super Mario Galaxy. Much like the first game, the story follows Mario as he pursues the Koopa King, Bowser, into outer space, where he has imprisoned Princess Peach and taken control of the universe using Power Stars and Grand Stars. Mario must travel across various galaxies to recover the Power Stars in order to travel to the center of the universe and rescue Princess Peach.
The game was originally planned as an updated version of Super Mario Galaxy, known as Super Mario Galaxy More. However, it was later decided that the game would be expanded into a fully fleshed-out sequel when the development staff continued to build upon the game with dozens of new ideas. As such, development time expanded to two and a half years. Among the new additions are dynamic environments, new power-ups, and the addition of Yoshi.
Super Mario Galaxy 2 was met with critical acclaim, and was considered to match or surpass its lauded predecessor, with its creativity, level design, gameplay, music, and technological improvements over the original receiving high praise, although critics were divided on its lack of story and high difficulty compared to the original. It is frequently regarded by critics to be one of the greatest video games ever made and is one of the best-selling games on the Wii, with over seven million copies sold worldwide.
An enhanced collection, alongside Super Mario Galaxy, was released for Nintendo Switch on October 2, 2025. Both games were also released separately on the Nintendo eShop. The enhanced release features 1080p resolution, improved UI, and additional content. A free update for Nintendo Switch 2 allows the games to be played in 4K resolution. A feature film featuring elements from both games, titled The Super Mario Galaxy Movie, is set to be released in April 2026. It is the sequel to The Super Mario Bros. Movie (2023), with its release being a part of the franchise's 40th anniversary celebrations.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Super_Mario_Galaxy_2</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:02:16 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>