<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Galaxy of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/galaxy</link><description>RSS feed of the galaxy of the day.</description><item><title>Samsung Galaxy Note</title><description>The Samsung Galaxy Note is a discontinued line of high-end flagship Android smartphones developed and marketed by Samsung Electronics. The line was primarily oriented towards pen computing; all Galaxy Note models shipped with a stylus pen, called the S Pen, and incorporate a pressure-sensitive Wacom digitizer. All Galaxy Note models also include software features that are oriented towards the stylus and the devices' large screens, such as note-taking, digital scrapbooking apps, tooltips, and split-screen multitasking. The line served as Samsung's flagship smartphone model, positioned above the Galaxy S series, and was part of the wider Samsung Galaxy series of Android computing devices.
The Galaxy Note smartphone series is noteworthy for being considered the first commercially successful examples of "phablets"—a class of smartphones with large screens that are intended to straddle the functionality of a traditional tablet with that of a phone, and having helped accelerate the trend of bigger screened smartphones becoming the norm around the mid 2010s. Samsung sold over 50 million Galaxy Note devices between September 2011 and October 2013.
In August 2021, TM Roh, Samsung's president and head of mobile communications, announced that no new Galaxy Note device would be unveiled at their 2021 launch event, which would instead focus on new foldable phones. "Instead of unveiling a new Galaxy Note this time around, we will further broaden beloved Note features to more Samsung Galaxy devices," he added.Phablet-sized Galaxy products are still being produced as "Ultra" editions of certain models in the Galaxy S series (since the Galaxy S22).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samsung_Galaxy_Note</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:02:08 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>