<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Galaxy of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/galaxy</link><description>RSS feed of the galaxy of the day.</description><item><title>Samsung Galaxy Note series</title><description>The Samsung Galaxy Note series was a line of high-end flagship Android phablets and smartphones developed and marketed by Samsung Electronics (Although still produced as the Ultra edition of the Galaxy S series since the Samsung Galaxy S22). The line is primarily oriented towards pen computing; all Galaxy Note models shipped with a stylus pen, called the S Pen, and incorporate a pressure-sensitive Wacom digitizer. All Galaxy Note models also include software features that are oriented towards the stylus and the devices' large screens, such as note-taking, digital scrapbooking apps, tooltips, and split-screen multitasking. The line served as Samsung's flagship smartphone model, positioned above the Galaxy S series.
The Galaxy Note smartphone series is noteworthy for being considered the first commercially successful examples of "phablets"—a class of smartphones with large screens that are intended to straddle the functionality of a traditional tablet with that of a phone, and having helped accelerate the trend of bigger screened smartphones becoming the norm around the mid 2010s. Samsung sold over 50 million Galaxy Note devices between September 2011 and October 2013. 10 million units of the Galaxy Note 3 have been sold within its first 2 months, 30 million were of the Note II, while the original Galaxy Note sold around 10 million units worldwide.
In August 2021, TM Roh, Samsung's president and Head of Mobile Communications, announced that no new Galaxy Note device would be unveiled at their 2021 launch event, which would instead focus on new foldable phones. "Instead of unveiling a new Galaxy Note this time around, we will further broaden beloved Note features to more Samsung Galaxy devices," he added.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samsung_Galaxy_Note_series</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 05:02:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>