<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Planet of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/planet</link><description>RSS feed of the planet of the day.</description><item><title>Exoplanet</title><description>An exoplanet (formerly extrasolar planet) is a planet outside the Solar System. The study of exoplanets begun in 1992 with the first confirmation of Poltergeist and Phobetor exoplanets orbiting Lich pulsar. By 2024, there are thousands of exoplanets discovered, with the exact number depending on the definition of an exoplanet.
Most methods of detecting and finding basic data about exoplanets such as their orbits, atmosphere and composition is indirect. The direct approach is to image the planet, which is extremely difficult and provide little data about the planet itself. The two most popular indirect methods are transit photometry and radial velocity. Transit photometry relies on the exoplanet lining in front of the parent star, causing dimming in the line of sight. Radial velocity relies on the fact that the exoplanet can shift the planetary system's barycenter, leading to star movement and detectable Doppler shifts. Due to bias in these detection methods, most planets discovered have masses many times of Earth and orbit very closely to the star. The composition and atmosphere can be analysed via spectroscopy.
The definition of the word exoplanet itself is fuzzy as many objects in exoplanet catalogues are arguably brown dwarfs. It is estimated that there are billions of exoplanets in the Milky Way compared to thousands discovered, therefore information about exoplanets can be outdated very quickly and it is too early to make any general trends about them. A prime example of such myths is the belief that an exoplanet in the habitable zone (such as those in the TRAPPIST-1 system) is automatically habitable by humans like Earth. This is not true and many exoplanets discovered are hot Jupiters or terrestrial planets tidally locked to the star, unsuitable for habitation.
Exoplanet discoveries are challenging current theories on the formation and evolution of the Solar System and the definition of the word planet itself. Exoplanets are the prime candidates to find extraterrestrial life via biosignatures and provide concrete foundations for cosmic pluralism. As such, their discoveries are popular with the general public and is seeking reconciliation with cultures and religions around the world. There are theoretical space missions that can provide great insight to these exoplanets, such as using solar gravitational lens to image exoplanets' surface and interstellar probes.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exoplanet</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 05:01:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>