<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Planet of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/planet</link><description>RSS feed of the planet of the day.</description><item><title>Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite</title><description>Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) is a space telescope for NASA's Explorer program, designed to search for exoplanets using the transit method in an area 400 times larger than that covered by the Kepler mission. It was launched on 18 April 2018, atop a Falcon 9 launch vehicle and was placed into a highly elliptical 13.70-day orbit around the Earth. The first light image from TESS was taken on 7 August 2018, and released publicly on 17 September 2018.
In the two-year primary mission, TESS was expected to detect about 1,250 transiting exoplanets orbiting the targeted stars, and an additional 13,000 orbiting stars not targeted but observed.  After the end of the primary mission around 4 July 2020, scientists continued to search its data for more planets, while the extended missions acquires additional data.  As of 6 July 2024, TESS had identified 7,203 candidate exoplanets, of which 482 had been confirmed. 
The primary mission objective for TESS was to survey the brightest stars near the Earth for transiting exoplanets over a two-year period.  The TESS satellite uses an array of wide-field cameras to perform a survey of 85% of the sky. With TESS, it is possible to study the mass, size, density and orbit of a large cohort of small planets, including a sample of rocky planets in the habitable zones of their host stars. TESS provides prime targets for further characterization by the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), as well as other large ground-based and space-based telescopes of the future. While previous sky surveys with ground-based telescopes have mainly detected giant exoplanets and the Kepler space telescope has mostly found planets around distant stars that are too faint for characterization, TESS finds many small planets around the nearest stars in the sky. TESS records the nearest and brightest main sequence stars hosting transiting exoplanets, which are the most favorable targets for detailed investigations.  Detailed information about such planetary systems with hot Jupiters makes it possible to better understand the architecture of such systems.
Led by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) with seed funding from Google, on 5 April 2013, it was announced that TESS, along with the Neutron Star Interior Composition Explorer (NICER), had been selected by NASA for launch.  On 18 July 2019, after the first year of operation, the southern portion of the survey was completed, and the northern survey was started. The primary mission ended with the completion of the northern survey on 4 July 2020, which was followed by the first extended mission. The first extended mission concluded in September 2022 and the spacecraft entered its second extended mission  which should last for another three years.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transiting_Exoplanet_Survey_Satellite</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 05:02:02 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>