<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Star of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/star</link><description>RSS feed of the star of the day.</description><item><title>Champagne Supernova</title><description>"Champagne Supernova" is a song by English rock band Oasis, written by Noel Gallagher. It is the closing track on the band's second studio album, (What's the Story) Morning Glory? (1995), and was released as the sixth and final single from the album in Australia and New Zealand on 13 May 1996 by Helter Skelter. Paul Weller appears as a guest guitarist and backing vocalist on the track. A music video for the song, directed by Nigel Dick, was released in 1996. The single was not released in the United Kingdom.
Described by Gallagher himself as “probably as psychedelic as I'll ever get", it features a dreamy, anthemic sound characterized by its expansive instrumentation and atmospheric production. The song begins with a gentle, arpeggiated guitar riff that sets a reflective mood, gradually building in intensity. As it progresses, layered guitars and lush strings create a rich soundscape, complemented by a steady drum beat that drives the song forward, accompanied with the vocals of Liam Gallagher, conveying a sense of longing and nostalgia, with lyrics that are both evocative and somewhat abstract.
Although much debate surrounds the meaning of the song, Noel Gallagher originally described how "Champagne Supernova" resonates with him depending on his mood. However, in later interviews, he has stated that he does not really know what the song means and how "it means something different" to everyone.
"Champagne Supernova" is considered by fans and music journalists alike as one of the most defining songs of Oasis and of Britpop. Alexis Petridis, the chief critic of The Guardian, called it the band's greatest song, claiming it was the "perfect epitaph for swaggering mid-90s hedonism." Upon its release, the song became a radio single in the United States, becoming the band's second No. 1 single on the Modern Rock Tracks chart. It also peaked at No. 20 on the Billboard Hot 100 Airplay, becoming the band's third top 40 single on that chart. The song is included on the band's greatest hits album Stop the Clocks and on the US release of Time Flies... 1994–2009. "Champagne Supernova" has also topped several ranked lists of the band's best songs, including from Consequence of Sound, Medium, Uproxx, and Variety. Supernova SN 2003fg was nicknamed "Champagne Supernova" after the song.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Champagne_Supernova</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 05:01:58 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>