<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Star of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/star</link><description>RSS feed of the star of the day.</description><item><title>Rogue One</title><description>Rogue One: A Star Wars Story is a 2016 American epic space opera film directed by Gareth Edwards and written by Chris Weitz and Tony Gilroy. Produced by Lucasfilm and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the first Star Wars anthology film and a prequel to Star Wars (1977). It stars Felicity Jones, Diego Luna, Ben Mendelsohn, Donnie Yen, Mads Mikkelsen, Alan Tudyk, Riz Ahmed, Jiang Wen, and Forest Whitaker. Set a week before the events of Star Wars, Rogue One follows rebels who steal the schematics for the Galactic Empire's ultimate weapon, the Death Star. It details the Rebel Alliance's first effective victory against the Empire, as referenced in the Star Wars opening crawl.
John Knoll, who served as the visual effects supervisor of the Star Wars prequel trilogy, pitched Rogue One's story as an episode of the unproduced television series Star Wars: Underworld in 2003. He pitched it again as a film following Disney's acquisition of Lucasfilm in 2012; Edwards was hired to direct in 2014. Edwards sought to differentiate Rogue One from previous Star Wars films and approach it as a war film, omitting the opening crawl and transitional screen wipes used in the main "Skywalker Saga" installments. Principal photography began at Pinewood Studios, Buckinghamshire, in early August 2015 and wrapped in February 2016. The film went through extensive reshoots in mid-2016. The score was composed by Michael Giacchino, rather than the Skywalker Saga composer John Williams. With an estimated production budget of $200–280.2 million, Rogue One is one of the most expensive films ever made.
Rogue One: A Star Wars Story premiered in Los Angeles on December 10, 2016, and was theatrically released in the United States on December 16. It received positive reviews, with praise for its acting, story, visuals, musical score, cinematography, and darker tone than previous Star Wars films, but criticism for its pacing, characters, and digital recreations of the deceased actors Peter Cushing and Carrie Fisher. Rogue One grossed over $1 billion worldwide, becoming the second-highest-grossing film of 2016, and received two Academy Award nominations for Best Sound Mixing and Best Visual Effects. Andor, a prequel television series focused on Luna's character Cassian Andor, aired on the streaming service Disney+ for two seasons from 2022 to 2025.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rogue_One</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 05:02:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>