<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Star of the Day</title><link>http://example.com/star</link><description>RSS feed of the star of the day.</description><item><title>List of Star Wars films</title><description>The Star Wars franchise involves multiple live-action and animated films. The film series started with a trilogy set in medias res that was later expanded to a trilogy of trilogies, known as the "Skywalker Saga".
The 1977 self-titled film was followed by the sequels The Empire Strikes Back (1980) and Return of the Jedi (1983), these films form the original trilogy. 22 years later, the Star Wars prequel trilogy was first released, consisting of Star Wars: Episode I – The Phantom Menace (1999), Star Wars: Episode II – Attack of the Clones (2002), and Star Wars: Episode III – Revenge of the Sith (2005). After creator George Lucas sold Lucasfilm to Disney in 2012, a Star Wars sequel trilogy consisting of Episodes VII through IX was released, consisting of Star Wars: The Force Awakens (2015), Star Wars: The Last Jedi (2017), and Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker (2019).
The first three spin-off films produced were the made-for-television Star Wars Holiday Special (1978), The Ewok Adventure (1984) and Ewoks: The Battle for Endor (1985). Following Disney's 2012 acquisition of the franchise, these earlier films were dropped from the official canon, but the theatrical animated film Star Wars: The Clone Wars (2008) and its television series continuation retain their canonical status. Two standalone films were produced and released between the sequel trilogy films: Rogue One (2016) and Solo: A Star Wars Story (2018), both set between the original and prequel trilogies. A yearslong hiatus began in late 2019, during which numerous films were announced and often shelved. Five officially announced projects were reputedly being developed as of early 2024, with a Mandalorian spin-off movie helmed by Jon Favreau reportedly slotted for release in May 2026.
The combined box office revenue of the films amounts to over US$10 billion, and it is currently the third-highest-grossing film franchise. The major live-action releases (including all the films within the Skywalker Saga) were nominated for Academy Awards. The original film was nominated for most of the major categories, including Best Picture, Best Director, Best Original Screenplay, and Best Supporting Actor for Alec Guinness (who played Obi-Wan Kenobi), while all theatrical live-action films have been nominated for particular categories. Several official Star Wars television series have also been released, all now on Disney+.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Star_Wars_films</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 05:01:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>