<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Significant Battles or Wars Before 1000</title><link>http://example.com/ancient_battles</link><description>RSS feed of significant battles or wars before the year 1000.</description><item><title>Battle of Stiklestad</title><description>The Battle of Stiklestad (Norwegian: Slaget på Stiklestad; Old Norse: Stiklarstaðir) in 1030 is one of the most famous battles in the history of Norway. In this battle, King Olaf II of Norway (Óláfr Haraldsson) was killed. During the pontificate of Pope Alexander III, the Roman Catholic Church declared Olaf a saint in 1164.
His younger half-brother, Harald Hardrada (Haraldr Haraldsson harðráði), was also present at the battle. Harald was only fifteen when the battle of Stiklestad took place. He became King of Norway in 1047, until his death in a failed invasion of England at the Battle of Stamford Bridge in 1066.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Stiklestad</link></item><item><title>Battle of Adrianople</title><description>The Battle of Adrianople also known as Battle of Hadrianopolis was fought between the Eastern Roman army led by the Roman emperor Valens and Gothic rebels (largely Thervings as well as Greutungs, non-Gothic Alans, and various local rebels) led by Fritigern. The battle took place on 9 August 378 in the vicinity of Adrianople, in the Roman province of Thracia (modern Edirne in European Turkey). It ended with an overwhelming victory for the Goths and the death of Emperor Valens.
As part of the Gothic War of 376–382, the battle is often considered the start of the events which led to the fall of the Western Roman Empire in the 5th century.
A detailed contemporary account of the lead-up to the battle from the Roman perspective was written by Ammianus Marcellinus and forms the culminating point at the end of his history.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Adrianople</link></item><item><title>Battles of Khalkhin Gol</title><description>The Battles of Khalkhin Gol (Russian: Бои на Халхин-Голе; Mongolian: Халхын голын байлдаан) were the decisive engagements of the undeclared Soviet–Japanese border conflicts involving the Soviet Union, Mongolia, Japan and Manchukuo in 1939. The conflict was named after the river Khalkhin Gol, which passes through the battlefield. In Japan, the decisive battle of the conflict is known as the Nomonhan Incident (Japanese: ノモンハン事件, Hepburn: Nomonhan jiken) after Nomonhan Burd Obo, an obo, a cairn set as a border marker in the Yongzheng period of the Qing dynasty. The battles resulted in the defeat of the Japanese Sixth Army.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battles_of_Khalkhin_Gol</link></item></channel></rss>