<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Significant Battles or Wars Before 1000</title><link>http://example.com/ancient_battles</link><description>RSS feed of significant battles or wars before the year 1000.</description><item><title>Battle of Badgam</title><description>The Battle of Badgam was a defensive encounter that took place at Badgam in the Kashmir Valley close to the Srinagar Airport during the initial stages of the First Kashmir War. The skirmishes took place on 3 November 1947 between a company of the Indian Army, aided by Indian Air Force, and a tribal lashkar of Pakistani raiders numbering around 1000, who had apparently occupied Badgam. The battle drew its significance from the success of the solitary company of 4th Battalion, Kumaon Regiment, led by Major Somnath Sharma, in halting the momentum of advancing tribal "Lashkars", though being heavily outnumbered. Sharma was awarded the Param Vir Chakra posthumously for his actions. The Indian Air Force served as an accompaniment to the army's efforts in the battle, contributing to the majority of the casualties inflicted on the Pakistani lashkars.However the tribal forces would successfully raid badgam and defeat the indian company at badgam and later infiltrate towards shalateng north of srinagar, with another decesive called Battle of Shalateng.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Badgam</link></item><item><title>List of wars involving the Ottoman Empire</title><description>This is a List of wars involving the Ottoman Empire ordered chronologically, including civil wars within the empire.
The earliest form of the Ottoman military was a nomadic steppe cavalry force. This was centralized by Osman I from Turkoman tribesmen inhabiting western Anatolia in the late 13th century. Orhan I organized a standing army paid by salary rather than looting or fiefs. The Ottomans began using guns in the late 14th century.
The Ottoman Empire was the first of the three Islamic Gunpowder Empires, followed by Safavid Persia and Mughal India. By the 14th century, the Ottomans had adopted gunpowder artillery. By the time of Sultan Mehmed II, they had been drilled with firearms and became "perhaps the first standing infantry force equipped with firearms in the world." The Janissaries are thus considered the first modern standing army.
The Ottoman Classical Army was the military structure established by Mehmed II. The classical Ottoman army was the most disciplined and feared military force of its time, mainly due to its high level of organization, logistical capabilities and its elite troops. Following a century long reform efforts, this army was forced to disbandment by Sultan Mahmud II on 15 June 1826 by what is known as Auspicious Incident. By the reign of Mahmud the Second, the elite Janissaries had become corrupt and an obstacle in the way of modernization efforts, meaning they were more of a liability than an asset.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_wars_involving_the_Ottoman_Empire</link></item><item><title>T2-3D: Battle Across Time</title><description>T2-3D: Battle Across Time (also known as Terminator 2: 3D) was an attraction at Universal Studios Florida, Universal Studios Hollywood and Universal Studios Japan. The version of the show in Hollywood had its final performance on December 31, 2012; the show then closed January 1, 2013. The version in Florida had its final performance on October 8, 2017; the show then closed October 9. The version in Osaka closed on September 14, 2020, in response to the COVID-19 pandemic, making the show on September 13, 2020, the final performance.
The attraction is a mini-sequel to Terminator 2: Judgment Day and reunites director James Cameron and the main cast from the movie, including Arnold Schwarzenegger as The Terminator, Linda Hamilton as Sarah Connor, Edward Furlong as John Connor, and Robert Patrick as the T-1000. The show was presented in two parts; a pre-show where a Cyberdyne Systems company hostess shows guests a brief video presentation about the company's innovations, and the main show, where live performers interact with a 3D film.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T2-3D:_Battle_Across_Time</link></item></channel></rss>