<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Significant Battles or Wars Before 1000</title><link>http://example.com/ancient_battles</link><description>RSS feed of significant battles or wars before the year 1000.</description><item><title>Battle of Laukkai</title><description>The Battle of Laukkai was a military offensive conducted by the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army (MNDAA) encircling and capturing Laukkai, the capital of the Kokang Self-Administered Zone (Kokang SAZ) in northeastern Myanmar. The battle was part of the larger Operation 1027, a joint military operation conducted by the Three Brotherhood Alliance coalition of three ethnic armed organisations and part of the overall renewed civil war in Myanmar.
Chinshwehaw, a key border town and main entrypoint into Kokang on the Lashio-chinshwehaw Road was seized on the first day of Operation 1027. In the second half of November, the MNDAA encircled the town of Laukkai taking several key outposts. They began attacking in southeastern Laukkai city on 1 December. On 3 December, they captured the Four Buddhist Statues Hill capturing all territory south of Laukkai. There was a brief respite in fighting in mid-December as peace talks were attempted. They were unsuccessful and on 18 December, fighting resumed north of Laukkai. The MNDAA captured key border towns and gates on 19 December and began pushing into the city.
On 26 December, the Tatmadaw's military and the Border Guard Forces led by Bai Suocheng in Laukkai surrendered to the MNDAA. By 28 December, the MNDAA had taken control of most of the city. Remaining junta personnel surrendered on 4 January and up to 1000 personnel evacuated to Lashio.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Laukkai</link></item><item><title>Battle of Badgam</title><description>The Battle of Badgam was a defensive encounter that took place at Badgam in the Kashmir Valley close to the Srinagar Airport during the initial stages of the First Kashmir War. The skirmishes took place on 3 November 1947 between a company of the Indian Army, aided by Indian Air Force, and a tribal lashkar of Pakistani raiders numbering around 1000, who had apparently occupied Badgam. The battle drew its significance from the success of the solitary company of 4th Battalion, Kumaon Regiment, led by Major Somnath Sharma, in halting the momentum of advancing tribal "Lashkars", though being heavily outnumbered. Sharma was awarded the Param Vir Chakra posthumously for his actions. The Indian Air Force served as an accompaniment to the army's efforts in the battle, contributing to the majority of the casualties inflicted on the Pakistani lashkars.However the tribal forces would successfully raid badgam and defeat the indian company at badgam and later infiltrate towards shalateng north of srinagar, with another decesive called Battle of Shalateng.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Badgam</link></item><item><title>T2-3D: Battle Across Time</title><description>T2-3D: Battle Across Time (also known as Terminator 2: 3D) was an attraction at Universal Studios Florida, Universal Studios Hollywood and Universal Studios Japan. The version of the show in Hollywood had its final performance on December 31, 2012; the show then closed January 1, 2013. The version in Florida had its final performance on October 8, 2017; the show then closed October 9. The version in Osaka closed on September 14, 2020, in response to the COVID-19 pandemic, making the show on September 13, 2020, the final performance.
The attraction is a mini-sequel to Terminator 2: Judgment Day and reunites director James Cameron and the main cast from the movie, including Arnold Schwarzenegger as The Terminator, Linda Hamilton as Sarah Connor, Edward Furlong as John Connor, and Robert Patrick as the T-1000. The show was presented in two parts; a pre-show where a Cyberdyne Systems company hostess shows guests a brief video presentation about the company's innovations, and the main show, where live performers interact with a 3D film.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T2-3D:_Battle_Across_Time</link></item></channel></rss>