<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Significant Battles or Wars Before 1000</title><link>http://example.com/ancient_battles</link><description>RSS feed of significant battles or wars before the year 1000.</description><item><title>Battle of Laukkai</title><description>The Battle of Laukkai was a military offensive conducted by the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army (MNDAA) encircling and capturing Laukkai, the capital of the Kokang Self-Administered Zone (Kokang SAZ) in northeastern Myanmar. The battle was part of the larger Operation 1027, a joint military operation conducted by the Three Brotherhood Alliance coalition of three ethnic armed organisations and part of the overall renewed civil war in Myanmar.
Chinshwehaw, a key border town and main entrypoint into Kokang on the Lashio-chinshwehaw Road was seized on the first day of Operation 1027. In the second half of November, the MNDAA encircled the town of Laukkai taking several key outposts. They began attacking in southeastern Laukkai city on 1 December. On 3 December, they captured the Four Buddhist Statues Hill capturing all territory south of Laukkai. There was a brief respite in fighting in mid-December as peace talks were attempted. They were unsuccessful and on 18 December, fighting resumed north of Laukkai. The MNDAA captured key border towns and gates on 19 December and began pushing into the city.
On 26 December, the Tatmadaw's military and the Border Guard Forces led by Bai Suocheng in Laukkai surrendered to the MNDAA. By 28 December, the MNDAA had taken control of most of the city. Remaining junta personnel surrendered on 4 January and up to 1000 personnel evacuated to Lashio.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Laukkai</link></item><item><title>Battle of Edington</title><description>At the Battle of Edington, an army of the kingdom of Wessex under Alfred the Great defeated the Great Heathen Army led by the Dane Guthrum sometime between 6 and 12 May 878, resulting in the Treaty of Wedmore later the same year. Primary sources locate the battle at "Eðandun". Until a scholarly consensus linked the battle site with the present-day village of Edington in Wiltshire, it was known as the Battle of Ethandun. This name continues to be used.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Edington</link></item><item><title>Battle of Carrhae</title><description>The Battle of Carrhae (Latin pronunciation: [ˈkarrae̯]) was fought in 53 BC between the Roman Republic and the Parthian Empire near the ancient town of Carrhae (present-day Harran, Turkey). An invading force of seven legions of Roman heavy infantry under Marcus Licinius Crassus was lured into the desert and decisively defeated by a mixed cavalry army of heavy cataphracts and light horse archers led by the Parthian general Surena. On such flat terrain, the Legion proved to have no viable tactics against the highly-mobile Parthian horsemen, and the slow and vulnerable Roman formations were surrounded, exhausted by constant attacks, and eventually crushed. Crassus was killed along with the majority of his army. It is commonly seen as one of the earliest and most important battles between the Roman and Parthian Empires and one of the most crushing defeats in Roman history. According to the poet Ovid in Book 6 of his poem Fasti, the battle occurred on 9 June.
Crassus, a member of the First Triumvirate and the wealthiest man in Rome, had been enticed by the prospect of military glory and riches and decided to invade Parthia without the official consent of the Senate. Rejecting an offer from the Armenian King Artavasdes II to allow Crassus to invade Parthia via Armenia, Crassus marched his army directly through the deserts of Mesopotamia. His forces clashed with Surena's troops near Carrhae. Surena's cavalry killed or captured most of the Roman soldiers. Crassus himself was killed when truce negotiations turned violent.
His death ended the First Triumvirate. The following four-year period of peace between the remaining two members of the Triumvirate, Julius Caesar and Pompey, argues against the view that Crassus had been a peacekeeper within the group and supports the views of most Roman historians that friction between Crassus and Pompey had always been a greater cause of tension than that between Caesar and Pompey.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Carrhae</link></item></channel></rss>