<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Significant Battles or Wars Before 1000</title><link>http://example.com/ancient_battles</link><description>RSS feed of significant battles or wars before the year 1000.</description><item><title>List of wars: before 1000</title><description>This is a list of wars that began before 1000 AD. Other wars can be found in the historical lists of wars and the list of wars extended by diplomatic irregularity.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_wars:_before_1000</link></item><item><title>Battle of Cervera</title><description>The Battle of Cervera took place near Espinosa de Cervera on 29 July 1000 between the Christian troops of counts Sancho García of Castile and García Gómez of Saldaña and the Muslim Caliphate of Córdoba under the hajib Almanzor. The battle, "tremendous and difficult to describe", was a victory for Almanzor. The battle is listed as the fifty-second of Almanzor's career in the Dikr bilad al-Andalus.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Cervera</link></item><item><title>First Battle of Panipat</title><description>The First Battle of Panipat, on 21 April 1526 was fought between the invading forces of Babur against Ibrahim Khan Lodi, the Sultan of Delhi, in North India. Babur's forces, employing gunpowder firearms and cannons, defeated Ibrahim. This was one of the earliest battles involving gunpowder arms on the Indian subcontinent. The victory marked the beginning of Mughal rule in India.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_Battle_of_Panipat</link></item><item><title>Battle of Kleidion</title><description>The Battle of Kleidion (Ancient Greek: Κλειδίον; or Clidium, after the medieval name of the village of Klyuch, lit. 'key'; also known as the Battle of Belasitsa) took place on 29 July 1014, between the Byzantine Empire and the Bulgarian Empire. It was the culmination of the nearly half-century struggle between the Byzantine Emperor Basil II and the Bulgarian emperor Samuel in the late 10th and early 11th centuries. The result was a decisive Byzantine victory.
The battle took place in the valley between the mountains of Belasitsa and Ograzhden, near the modern Bulgarian village of Klyuch. The decisive encounter occurred on 29 July with an attack in the rear by a force under the Byzantine general Nikephoros Xiphias, who had infiltrated the Bulgarian positions. The ensuing battle was a major defeat for the Bulgarians. Thousands of Bulgarian soldiers were captured and blinded by order of Basil II, who would subsequently be known as the "Bulgar-Slayer". Samuel survived the battle, but died two months later from a heart attack, reportedly brought on by the sight of his blind soldiers.
Although the engagement did not end the First Bulgarian Empire, the Battle of Kleidion reduced its ability to resist Byzantine advances, and it has been considered the pivotal encounter of the war with Byzantium.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Kleidion</link></item></channel></rss>