<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Significant Battles or Wars Before 1000</title><link>http://example.com/ancient_battles</link><description>RSS feed of significant battles or wars before the year 1000.</description><item><title>Christmas Battles</title><description>The Christmas Battle (Italian: La battaglia di natale) was fought between forces of the Soviet Red Army and the Italian Expeditionary Corps in Russia from 25 December to 28 December, 1941, during Operation Barbarossa, when the Soviets launched a multi-division attack in the gap between the Italian expeditionary force and the German XLIX Mountain Corps. The goal of the attack was to open the path to Stalino and threaten vital Axis railway junctures.
The attack was conducted on Christmas day by the Soviet 35th and 68th Cavalry divisions plus the 136th Rifle Division, and was primarily aimed at the Italian 3rd Cavalry Division "Principe Amedeo Duca d'Aosta", later reinforced by parts of the Italian 9th Infantry Division "Pasubio" and 52nd Infantry Division "Torino". Bearing the brunt of the attack against numerically-superior forces, the 3rd Cavalry Division held their sector. The limited Soviet gains were rolled back by Dec 27, when formations from the "Pasubio" and "Torino" divisions, plus the German 318th Infantry Regiment (with supporting armor), counterattacked and regained the lost ground. In the end, for the cost of 168 dead and 207 missing, the Italians had defeated the Soviets, who lost over 2,000 dead; the Italians also took 1,200 Soviet troops prisoner and captured 24 76mm guns, 9 anti-tank guns, and large stockpiles of machine guns and vehicles. The Italian victory was partly due to close collaboration between their infantry and artillery.
The 3rd Bersaglieri Regiment played a decisive part in the fighting, defending against ten-fold superior forces before falling back, and participating in the counterattack.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christmas_Battle_(1941)</link></item><item><title>First Battle of Panipat</title><description>The First Battle of Panipat, on 21 April 1526 was fought between the invading forces of Babur against Ibrahim Khan Lodi, the Sultan of Delhi, in North India. Babur's forces, employing gunpowder firearms and cannons, defeated Ibrahim. This was one of the earliest battles involving gunpowder arms on the Indian subcontinent. The victory marked the beginning of Mughal rule in India.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_Battle_of_Panipat</link></item><item><title>T2-3D: Battle Across Time</title><description>T2-3D: Battle Across Time (also known as Terminator 2: 3D) was an attraction at Universal Studios Florida, Universal Studios Hollywood and Universal Studios Japan. The version of the show in Hollywood had its final performance on December 31, 2012; the show then closed January 1, 2013. The version in Florida had its final performance on October 8, 2017; the show then closed October 9, 2017. The version in Osaka closed on September 14, 2020, in response to the COVID-19 pandemic, making the show on September 13, 2020, the final performance.
The attraction is a mini-sequel to Terminator 2: Judgment Day and reunites director James Cameron and the main cast from the movie, including Arnold Schwarzenegger as The Terminator, Linda Hamilton as Sarah Connor, Edward Furlong as John Connor, and Robert Patrick as the T-1000. The show was presented in two parts; a pre-show where a Cyberdyne Systems company hostess shows guests a brief video presentation about the company's innovations, and the main show, where live performers interact with a 3D film. The attraction marked James Cameron's final involvement with the Terminator franchise until Terminator: Dark Fate in 2019.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T2-3D:_Battle_Across_Time</link></item><item><title>List of battles 301–1300</title><description>This is a list of battles from 301 A.D. to 1300 A.D.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_battles_301%E2%80%931300</link></item><item><title>Battle of Chappar Chiri</title><description>The Battle of Chappar Chiri, also called Battle of Sirhind, was fought between Mughal Empire and the Sikhs on 12 May 1710 at Chappar Chiri, located 20 kilometers from Sirhind.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Chappar_Chiri</link></item></channel></rss>