<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Significant Battles or Wars Before 1000</title><link>http://example.com/ancient_battles</link><description>RSS feed of significant battles or wars before the year 1000.</description><item><title>Battle of Rocroi</title><description>The Battle of Rocroi, fought on 19 May 1643, was a major engagement of the Thirty Years' War between a French army, led by the 21-year-old Duke of Enghien (later known as the Great Condé) and Spanish forces under General Francisco de Melo only five days after the accession of Louis XIV to the throne of France after his father's death. Rocroi shattered the myth of invincibility of the Spanish Tercios, the terrifying infantry units that had dominated European battlefields for the previous 120 years. The battle is therefore often considered to mark the end of Spanish military greatness and the beginning of French hegemony in Europe during the 17th century. After Rocroi, the Spanish progressively transformed the tercio system incorporating more of the line infantry doctrine used by the French over time.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Rocroi</link></item><item><title>First Battle of Panipat</title><description>The First Battle of Panipat, on 21 April 1526 was fought between the invading forces of Babur against Ibrahim Khan Lodi, the Sultan of Delhi, in North India. Babur's forces, employing gunpowder firearms and cannons, defeated Ibrahim. This was one of the earliest battles involving gunpowder arms on the Indian subcontinent. The victory marked the beginning of Mughal rule in India.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_Battle_of_Panipat</link></item><item><title>List of naval battles</title><description>This list of naval battles is a chronological list delineating important naval battles that have occurred throughout history, from the beginning of naval warfare with the Hittites in the 12th century BC to piracy off the coast of Somalia in the 21st century. If a battle has no commonly used name it is referred to as "Action of (date)" within the list below.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_naval_battles</link></item><item><title>Hoadley's Battle of the Sounds</title><description>Hoadley's Battle of the Sounds was an annual national rock/pop band competition held in Australia from 1966 to 1972. The winners of the national finals were the Twilights (1966), the Groop (1967), the Groove (1968), Doug Parkinson in Focus (main, 1969) and the Affair (vocal group, 1969), the Flying Circus (1970), Fraternity (1971) and Sherbet (1972).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hoadley%27s_Battle_of_the_Sounds</link></item></channel></rss>