<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Peter James (writer)</title><description>Peter J. James (born 22 August 1948) is a British writer of crime. He was born in Brighton, the son of Cornelia James, the former glovemaker to Queen Elizabeth II.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_James_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, England, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Nicholas Rowe (actor)</title><description>Nicholas James Sebastian Rowe (born 22 November 1966) is a British actor. At the start of his career he appeared as the lead in the 1985 film Young Sherlock Holmes.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nicholas_Rowe_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Wilson (actor)</title><description>Andrew Cunningham Wilson (born August 22, 1964) is an American actor and director. He is the older brother of actors Owen Wilson and Luke Wilson.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Wilson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Michael Kelly (actor)</title><description>Michael Kelly (born May 22, 1969) is an American actor, widely known for his role as Doug Stamper in the Netflix drama series House of Cards. He played a regular role as CIA Agent Mike November in the Prime Video thriller series Jack Ryan. He also appeared on The Sopranos as FBI Agent Ron Goddard.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Kelly_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Carl Lee (actor)</title><description>Carl Lee (born Carl Vincent Canegata; November 22, 1926 – April 17, 1986) was an American actor. His father was actor/professional boxer Canada Lee.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Lee_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Srikanth (actor, born 1979)</title><description>Srikanth is an Indian actor known for his works predominantly in Tamil and Telugu films. He is credited as Sriram in Telugu films. He debuted in K. Balachander's tele serial Jannal – Marabu Kavithaigal (1999). His film debut was in the romantic film Roja Kootam (2002) and went on to star in more such films including April Maadhathil (2002), Parthiban Kanavu (2003) and Okariki Okaru (2003). He subsequently went on to portray action roles in  Drohi (2010). In 2012, he starred in Nanban.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Srikanth_(actor,_born_1979)</link></item></channel></rss>