<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1949) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Chris McKenna (writer)</title><description>Chris McKenna is an American television writer, film producer, screenwriter, and television producer. He has written for American Dad!, Community, and The Mindy Project, and part of the first Marvel Cinematic Universe Spider-Man trilogy (2017–2021).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_McKenna_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Confederation Poets</title><description>Confederation Poets is the name given to a group of Canadian poets born in the decade of Canada's Confederation (the 1860s) who rose to prominence in Canada in the late 1880s and 1890s. The term was coined by Canadian professor and literary critic Malcolm Ross, who applied it to four poets – Charles G.D. Roberts (1860–1943), Bliss Carman (1861–1929), Archibald Lampman (1861–1899), and Duncan Campbell Scott (1862–1947) – in the Introduction to his 1960 anthology, Poets of the Confederation. He wrote, "It is fair enough, I think, to call Roberts, Carman, Lampman, and Scott our 'Confederation poets.'"
The term has also been used since to include William Wilfred Campbell (?1860-1918) and Frederick George Scott (1861–1944), sometimes Francis Joseph Sherman (1871–1926), sometimes Pauline Johnson (1861–1913) and George Frederick Cameron (1854–1885),  and Isabella Valancy Crawford (1850–1887) as well.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confederation_Poets</link></item><item><title>Paul Kane (poet)</title><description>Paul Kane (born March 23, 1950) is an American poet, critic and scholar. Awards for his work include Fellowships from the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Guggenheim Foundation, the Bogliasco Foundation, a Fulbright Award, an honorary doctorate from La Trobe University in Australia, and The Order of Australia. He is also considered an Australian poet. Kane is Professor Emeritus at Vassar College with homes in Clinton Corners and Warwick, New York.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Kane_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Chetan Anand (director)</title><description>Chetan Anand (3 January 1921 – 6 July 1997) was a Bollywood film producer, screenwriter and director from India, whose first film, Neecha Nagar, was awarded the Grand Prix Prize (now Golden Palm) at the first ever Cannes Film Festival in 1946. Later, he co-founded Navketan Films with his younger brother Dev Anand in 1949.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chetan_Anand_(director)</link></item><item><title>List of Jewish film directors</title><description>This is a list of Jewish film directors. The countries listed are those where films were directed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Jewish_film_directors</link></item><item><title>Roger Clark (actor, born 1978)</title><description>Roger Clark (born July 14, 1978) is an Irish-American actor and voice actor. He is best known for portraying Arthur Morgan through performance capture in the 2018 video game Red Dead Redemption 2, a role which garnered him critical acclaim and numerous accolades.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Clark_(actor,_born_1978)</link></item><item><title>Kevin Miles (American actor)</title><description>Kevin Miles (born Kevin Miles Julian Mimms, July 1990) is an American actor best known for his role as Jake, the spokesman for State Farm insurance company.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kevin_Miles_(American_actor)</link></item><item><title>Ian Chen (actor)</title><description>Ian Chen (Chinese: 陳琦燁; was born on 7 September 2006) is an American actor. He is known for his roles as Evan Huang in the ABC sitcom Fresh Off the Boat (2015–2020) and Eugene Choi in the DC Extended Universe films Shazam! (2019) and Shazam! Fury of the Gods (2023).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Chen_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor. He is known for his role as Benedict in the Netflix period drama Bridgerton (2020–present) and has also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016). He was nominated for a Laurence Olivier Award for his performance in the play A Little Life in 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Peter Hermann (actor)</title><description>Peter Hermann (born August 15, 1967) is an American actor. He may be best known for his roles as Charles Brooks in Younger, Trevor Langan in Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit, and Jack Boyle in Blue Bloods. Hermann is the husband of fellow Law &amp; Order franchise actor Mariska Hargitay, series lead of Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Hermann_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jake Hoffman (actor)</title><description>Jacob Edward Hoffman (born March 20, 1981) is an American actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jake_Hoffman_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>