<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>David Shapiro (poet)</title><description>David Shapiro (January 2, 1947 – May 4, 2024) was an American poet, literary critic, and art historian. He wrote some twenty volumes of poetry, literary, and art criticism. He was first published at the age of thirteen, and his first book was published when he was eighteen.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Shapiro_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Dasaradh (director)</title><description>Kondapalli Dasaradh Kumar (born 5 June 1971) is an Indian film director and screenwriter who works in Telugu cinema. He is best known for directing the films Santosham (2002), Mr. Perfect (2011), and Greeku Veerudu (2013).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dasaradh_(director)</link></item><item><title>List of Jewish film directors</title><description>This is a list of Jewish film directors. The countries listed are those where films were directed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Jewish_film_directors</link></item><item><title>Ian Chen (actor)</title><description>Ian Chen (Chinese: 陳琦燁; was born on 7 September 2006) is an American actor. He is known for his roles as Evan Huang in the ABC sitcom Fresh Off the Boat (2015–2020) and Eugene Choi in the DC Extended Universe films Shazam! (2019) and Shazam! Fury of the Gods (2023).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Chen_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ben Foster (actor)</title><description>Benjamin A. Foster (born October 29, 1980) is an American actor. His films include The Punisher (2004), X-Men: The Last Stand and Alpha Dog (both 2006), 30 Days of Night (2007), The Messenger and Pandorum (both 2009), The Mechanic (2011), Contraband (2012), Kill Your Darlings and Lone Survivor (both 2013), The Program (2015), Warcraft (2016), and Leave No Trace (2018). He has won an Independent Spirit Award for portraying Tanner Howard in Hell or High Water (2016). He also had a recurring role as Russell Corwin in Six Feet Under (2003–05).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Foster_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kim Ji-hoon (actor, born 1981)</title><description>Kim Ji-hoon (Korean: 김지훈; born May 9, 1981) is a South Korean actor. He is best known for his romantic comedies on television such as The Golden Age of Daughters-in-Law (2007), Love Marriage (also known as Matchmaker's Lover, 2008), Stars Falling from the Sky (also known as Wish Upon a Star, 2010), and My Cute Guys (2012). In 2010, he also appeared in the film Natalie, and cable mystery series Unsolved. In 2023 he appeared in Lee Chung-hyun's Netflix film Ballerina.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Ji-hoon_(actor,_born_1981)</link></item><item><title>John Marquez (actor)</title><description>John Charles Marquez (born 5 June 1970) is a British actor and writer. He is best known for his role as PC Joseph Penhale in ITV drama series Doc Martin (2007–2022) and Ray Wilson in BBC One's drama In the Club (2014–2016).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Marquez_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Graham Phillips (actor)</title><description>Graham David Phillips (born April 14, 1993) is an American actor,  singer, writer and director. Beginning his acting career at the age of nine, Phillips is known for a variety of television, film, and stage roles; as Zach Florrick on the CBS series The Good Wife, Ben Tennyson in the film Ben 10: Race Against Time, and Evan Goldman in the Broadway musical 13, as well as a leading role in the independent film Staten Island Summer. He has also appeared in films such as Blockers and XOXO and in the recurring television roles of Nick St. Clair in Riverdale and Nate in Atypical. He made his feature film directorial debut in 2019 with The Bygone.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graham_Phillips_(actor)</link></item><item><title>John Abbott (actor)</title><description>John Albert Chamberlain Kefford (5 June 1905 – 24 May 1996) was an English actor professionally known as John Abbott. His memorable roles include the invalid Frederick Fairlie in the 1948 film The Woman in White and the pacifist Ayelborne in the Star Trek episode "Errand of Mercy". He also played Sesmar in an episode of Lost in Space, "The Dream Monster", in 1966. Abbott was known as a Shakespearean actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Abbott_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Rajesh (Tamil actor)</title><description>Rajesh (20 December 1949 – 29 May 2025) was an Indian actor who performed in predominately Tamil films and serials. He completed more than 50 years in films and appeared as lead roles and supporting roles in over 150 films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rajesh_(Tamil_actor)</link></item><item><title>Kim Joon (actor, born 2014)</title><description>Kim Joon (born Kim Byung-gong on May 12, 2014) is a South Korean actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Joon_(actor,_born_2014)</link></item></channel></rss>