<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Peter James (writer)</title><description>Peter J. James (born 22 August 1948) is a British writer of crime. He was born in Brighton, the son of Cornelia James, the former glovemaker to Queen Elizabeth II.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_James_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Brian Keenan (writer)</title><description>Brian Keenan  (born 28 September 1950) is an Irish writer whose work includes the book An Evil Cradling, an account of the four and a half years he spent as a hostage in Beirut, Lebanon from 11 April 1986 to 24 August 1990.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Keenan_(writer)</link></item><item><title>William Stafford (poet)</title><description>William Edgar Stafford (January 17, 1914 – August 28, 1993) was an American poet and pacifist. He was the father of poet and essayist Kim Stafford. He was appointed the twentieth Consultant in Poetry to the Library of Congress in 1970.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Stafford_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Deputy Director of the Central Intelligence Agency</title><description>The deputy director of the Central Intelligence Agency (DD/CIA) is a statutory office (50 U.S.C. § 3037) and the second-highest official of the Central Intelligence Agency. The DD/CIA assists the director of the Central Intelligence Agency (D/CIA) and is authorized to exercise the powers of the D/CIA when the director's position is vacant or in the director's absence or disability.
Under current law, the deputy director is appointed by the president of the United States and is not required to be confirmed by the United States Senate.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deputy_Director_of_the_Central_Intelligence_Agency</link></item><item><title>Ali Raza (actor)</title><description>Muhammad Ali Raza (born 28 August 1998) is a Pakistani actor and model who works in Urdu television. Raza is known for portraying Daniyal in Muhabbat Gumshuda Meri (2023) and Shahnawaz Shah in Iqtidar (2024-2025).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ali_Raza_(actor)</link></item><item><title>John Goddard (actor)</title><description>John Goddard (born August 28, 1927) is an American film and television actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Goddard_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Vijay (actor)</title><description>Joseph Vijay Chandrasekhar (born 22 June 1974), known professionally as Vijay, is an Indian actor and politician who works in Tamil cinema. In a career spanning over three decades, Vijay has acted in 68 films and is one of the most commercially successful actors in Tamil cinema with multiple films amongst the highest-grossing Tamil films of all time and is amongst the highest paid actors in India. He has won several awards as an actor. Referred to as "Thalapathy" (transl. Commander), Vijay has a significant fan following.
Born in Madras to director S. A. Chandrasekhar, Vijay made his debut as a child actor in the Tamil film Vetri (1984). After a few roles as a child actor in his father’s films, he played his first lead role in the film Naalaiya Theerpu (1992) at the age of 18. Vijay continued doing lead roles for the next few years with notable films amongst them included Poove Unakkaga (1996), Love Today (1997), Kadhalukku Mariyadhai (1997), Thullatha Manamum Thullum (1999) and Kushi (2000). In 1998, he was awarded Kalaimaamani by the Government of Tamil Nadu for his role in Kadhalukku Mariyadhai.
In 2004, he starred in the blockbuster action-masala film Ghilli and with subsequent success of Thirupaachi (2005) and Pokkiri (2007) later, he established himself as one of the leading and commercially successful actors in Tamil cinema. Following a period of moderate success, Vijay acted in several critically and commercially successful films starting from early 2010s including Thuppakki (2012), Kaththi (2014), Mersal (2017), Sarkar (2018), Master (2021), Beast (2022), Leo (2023) and his penultimate film The Greatest of All Time (2024).
In February 2024, Vijay announced his retirement from films and his forthcoming entry into politics with the launch of his political party, known as Tamilaga Vettri Kazhagam.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vijay_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Martin McCann (actor)</title><description>Martin McCann (born 20 July 1983) is an actor from Northern Ireland. In 2020, he was listed as number 48 on The Irish Times list of Ireland's greatest film actors.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martin_McCann_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>