<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Tom Kristensen (poet)</title><description>Tom Kristensen ((1893-08-04)4 August 1893 – (1974-06-02)2 June 1974), was a Danish poet, novelist, literary critic and journalist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Kristensen_(poet)</link></item><item><title>David Shapiro (poet)</title><description>David Shapiro (January 2, 1947 – May 4, 2024) was an American poet, literary critic, and art historian. He wrote some twenty volumes of poetry, literary, and art criticism. He was first published at the age of thirteen, and his first book was published when he was eighteen.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Shapiro_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Zelda (poet)</title><description>Zelda Schneurson Mishkovsky (Hebrew: זלדה שניאורסון-מישקובסקי; June 20, 1914 – April 30, 1984), widely known as Zelda, was an Israeli poet. She received three awards for her published works.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zelda_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Liverpool poets</title><description>The Liverpool poets are a number of influential 1960s poets from Liverpool, England, influenced by 1950s Beat poetry. 
Their work is characterised by its directness of expression, simplicity of language, suitability for live performance and concern for contemporary subjects and references. There is often humour, but the full range of human experience and emotion is addressed.

The kids didn't see this poetry with a capital p, they understood it as modern entertainment, as part of the pop-movement. (Roger McGough)</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liverpool_poets</link></item><item><title>William Campbell (actor)</title><description>William Campbell (October 30, 1923 – April 28, 2011) was an American actor who appeared in supporting roles in major film productions, and also starred in several low-budget B-movies and horror films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Campbell_(actor)</link></item><item><title>David Davies (Welsh actor)</title><description>David Lewis Davies (3 April 1906 – June 1974), was a Welsh stage and film actor. At 6 feet 4 inches tall, he was often cast as a heavy, police officer or in a military or authoritarian role, such as Mr. Arrow, the first mate and enforcer outwitted by Long John Silver in Disney's 1950 Treasure Island. Davies appeared mainly in British film and television programmes, and was in demand for films set in Wales, such as The Three Weird Sisters (1948), The Last Days of Dolwyn (1949), Tiger Bay (1959) and Only Two Can Play (1962).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Davies_(Welsh_actor)</link></item></channel></rss>