<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Chen Chen (poet)</title><description>Chen Chen (Chinese: 陳琛; pinyin: Chén Chēn, born March 9, 1989) is an American poet. His book, When I Grow Up I Want to Be a List of Further Possibilities, was longlisted for the 2017 National Book Award for Poetry. Chen serves on the poetry faculty for the low-residency MFA programs at New England College and Stonecoast. He served as Jacob Ziskind Poet-in-Residence at Brandeis University from 2018 to 2022.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chen_Chen_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Johnny Brown (actor)</title><description>Johnny Brown (June 11, 1937 – March 2, 2022) was an American actor, comedian and singer. He was most famous for his role as building superintendent Nathan Bookman on the 1970s CBS sitcom, Good Times. Brown portrayed Bookman until the series was cancelled in 1979.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_Brown_(actor)</link></item><item><title>James Martin (Scottish actor)</title><description>James Rooney Martin BEM (13 March 1931 – 18 February 2025) was a Scottish film and television actor. He is best known for playing Eric in the sitcom Still Game, in which he was one of the few actors who was actually an old age pensioner.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Martin_(Scottish_actor)</link></item><item><title>Jake Hoffman (actor)</title><description>Jacob Edward Hoffman (born March 20, 1981) is an American actor.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jake_Hoffman_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Michael Chaplin (actor)</title><description>Michael John Chaplin (born March 7, 1946) is an American actor born in Santa Monica, California.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Chaplin_(actor)</link></item><item><title>David Paul (actor)</title><description>David Paul (March 8, 1957 – March 6, 2020) was an American actor and bodybuilder. He and his twin brother Peter were born in Hartford, Connecticut and grew up in Rhode Island. The death of David was confirmed by his twin brother Peter. David died just two days before the twins' 63rd birthday.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Paul_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor. He is known for his role as Benedict in the Netflix period drama Bridgerton (2020–) and has also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016). He was nominated for a Laurence Olivier Award for his performance in the play A Little Life in 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>