<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Niall Williams (writer)</title><description>Niall Williams is an Irish writer. 
He has written novels, plays and non-fiction. His work has been translated into twenty different languages.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niall_Williams_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Kenneth Anderson (writer)</title><description>Kenneth Douglas Stewart Anderson (8 March 1910 – 30 August 1974) was an Indian writer and hunter who wrote books about his adventures in the jungles of South India.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenneth_Anderson_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Goldberg (writer)</title><description>Andrew Goldberg is an American writer and producer.
Goldberg co-created the Netflix adult animated series Big Mouth with his childhood best friend Nick Kroll, and Mark Levin and Jennifer Flackett, and serves as a writer and executive producer. Prior to that, he wrote for Family Guy. He is also the author of Family Guy: Brian's Guide to Booze, Broads, and the Lost Art of Being a Man, a book published by HarperCollins focusing on Brian Griffin's beliefs.
Goldberg was born and raised in White Plains, New York and is of Jewish descent. He earned his BA at Columbia University in 2000 and his MFA at the UCLA School of Film &amp; Television in 2002.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Goldberg_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Tom Kristensen (poet)</title><description>Tom Kristensen ((1893-08-04)4 August 1893 – (1974-06-02)2 June 1974), was a Danish poet, novelist, literary critic and journalist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Kristensen_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Wilson (actor)</title><description>Andrew Cunningham Wilson (born August 22, 1964) is an American actor and director. He is the older brother of actors Owen Wilson and Luke Wilson.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Wilson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Benjamin Walker (actor)</title><description>Benjamin Walker Scodelario-Davis (né Davis; born June 21, 1982) is an American actor and stand-up comedian. He starred as Andrew Jackson in the musical Bloody Bloody Andrew Jackson, which premiered on Broadway in 2010. He has appeared in a number of Broadway productions, notably as Patrick Bateman in the 2016 musical adaptation of the novel American Psycho and as Chris Keller in the 2019 revival of All My Sons, for which he was nominated for a Tony Award for Best Featured Actor. On screen, he is known for his title role in the 2012 film Abraham Lincoln: Vampire Hunter, as well as his appearances in the films Kinsey, Flags of Our Fathers, and In the Heart of the Sea. In 2019, he starred as Erik Gelden in the third and final season of the Netflix series Jessica Jones. He plays the High King of the Ñoldorin Elves Ereinion Gil-galad in the Amazon Prime Video series The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benjamin_Walker_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Chris McNally (actor)</title><description>Christopher McNally (born November 8, 1988) is a Canadian-born actor most noted for his role as Lucas Bouchard in the Hallmark Channel series When Calls the Heart (2019–present).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_McNally_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Hutton (actor)</title><description>Robert Hutton (born Robert Bruce Winne; June 11, 1920 – August 7, 1994) was an American actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Hutton_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>