<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Ahmed Ali (writer)</title><description>Ahmed Ali   (Urdu: احمد علی; 1 July 1910 – 14 January 1994) was a Pakistani novelist, poet, critic, translator, diplomat and scholar. A pioneer of the modern Urdu short story, his works include the short story collections: Angarey (Embers), 1932; Hamari Gali (Our Lane), 1940; Qaid Khana (The Prison), 1942; and Maut Se Pehle (Before Death), 1945. His other writings include Twilight in Delhi (1940), his first novel in the English language.
Muneeza Shamshie has called him "the forefather to all Pakistani English fiction."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ahmed_Ali_(writer)</link></item><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Ed Cox (poet)</title><description>Ed Cox (July 6, 1946 in Washington, D.C. – September 1, 1992) was an American poet.
He served in the U.S. Navy.
He studied at the University of Maryland with Rudd Fleming and Roderick Jellema.
He worked for the U.S. Association for the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees.
He read at Mass Transit, at the Community Book Shop on P Street.
He lived at 1345 Saratoga Ave. NE from 1959 to 1964, and 1920 S Street NW,4110 Emery St NW, and 1301 15th St. NW #720 in the 1980s. 
His papers are held by American University.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ed_Cox_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Alun Lewis (poet)</title><description>Alun Lewis (1 July 1915 – 5 March 1944) was a Welsh poet. He is one of the best-known English-language war poets of the Second World War. His poetry centres around a "recurring obsession with the themes of isolation and death."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alun_Lewis_(poet)</link></item><item><title>David Shapiro (poet)</title><description>David Shapiro (January 2, 1947 – May 4, 2024) was an American poet, literary critic, and art historian. He wrote some twenty volumes of poetry, literary, and art criticism. He was first published at the age of thirteen, and his first book was published when he was eighteen.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Shapiro_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Chetan Anand (director)</title><description>Chetan Anand (3 January 1921 – 6 July 1997) was a Bollywood film producer, screenwriter and director from India, whose first film, Neecha Nagar, was awarded the Grand Prix Prize (now Golden Palm) at the first ever Cannes Film Festival in 1946. Later, he co-founded Navketan Films with his younger brother Dev Anand in 1949.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chetan_Anand_(director)</link></item><item><title>Václav Vydra (actor, born 1956)</title><description>Václav Vydra (29 April 1876 – 7 April 1953), was a Czech film and stage actor. He starred in 31 films between 1914 and 1953.
Vydra was also a noted stage actor, acting in the Vinohrady Theater and National Theater playing major roles of the characters in plays by William Shakespeare, Karel Čapek, and others. From 1945 to 1949, he was director of the National Theater; as both a member of the Communist Party and the head of the National Theater, Vydra was one of the most powerful figures in Czech theater in the post-war era. In 1946 he became the first actor awarded the National Artist title.
His grandson, Václav Vydra, born 1956, is also a notable actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V%C3%A1clav_Vydra_(actor,_born_1876)</link></item><item><title>Kevin Miles (American actor)</title><description>Kevin Miles (born Kevin Miles Julian Mimms, July 1990) is an American actor best known for his role as Jake, the mascot of the State Farm insurance company.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kevin_Miles_(American_actor)</link></item><item><title>David Thornton (actor)</title><description>David Farrington Thornton (born May 4, 1953) is an American actor. He has appeared in John Q, Home Alone 3 as Earl Unger, Law &amp; Order, The Notebook, and The Other Woman, among other roles. He is the husband of singer, songwriter and actress Cyndi Lauper.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Thornton_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor. He is known for his role as Benedict in the Netflix period drama Bridgerton (2020–present) and has also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016). He was nominated for a Laurence Olivier Award for his performance in the play A Little Life in 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>