<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Bill Aitken (writer)</title><description>William McKay Aitken (31 May 1934 – 16 April 2025) was a British-born Indian travel writer and mountain lover from Scotland. He was the author of a number of books about India, its mountains, rivers and its steam trains.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Aitken_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Hashim (poet)</title><description>Hashim Shah (Punjabi ہاشم شاہ (Shahmukhi), ਹਾਸ਼ਿਮ ਸ਼ਾਹ (Gurmukhi); b. 1735 d. 1843) was a Punjabi writer and Sufi poet, best known for his story Sassi Punnun (or Sassi Panhu). His family migrated from Holy city Madina to Punjab, India, where they began living at Jagdev Kalan, the biggest village in Ajnala tehsil, Amritsar district. Hashim Shah was born in Jagdev Kalan in 1735 or 1752 and lived in that village his entire life. He wrote three stories "Kissa Kaw" named Sassi Punnu, Sohni Mahiwal, and Shirin Farhad.
Hashim, besides following the family tradition of hikmat (physician), copunselling and Piri-Muridi, also worked as a carpenter for sustenance. He left the profession of carpentry when Maharaja Ranjit Singh and his courtiers extended their patronage to Hashim. Thereafter, he devoted his entire life to spiritual attainments and composing Sufistic (mystic) poetry.
Hashim Shah's poetry is unique in its own right. Credited as one of the best poets of his era many books have been written about him by his followers. His poetry has a certain style reverberating with description and sometimes sadness. The way he has narrated Sassi Punnu speaks for the depth in his words and the immense aptitude he had.
Sufism ran in Hashim's family. He, his father and grandfather practised piri-muridi. He took Sufism as an established belief. His Punjabi poetry reverberates with mysticism of high order and can be allegorically interpreted for Love Divine.
Hashim died in Ajnala, 1843 or 1823 and was buried in Tharpal village in Narowal District where every year Urs was held on or about 21st of Jeth (end May – early June).
In his poetic compositions his prosody is Punjabi though his vocabulary abounds in Hindi, Persian and Arabic words He has written the following books:

Qissa Shirin Farhad
Qissa Sohni Mahiwal
Qissa Sassi Punnun
Gyan Prakash
Dohre

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hashim_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Young (poet, born 1885)</title><description>Andrew John Young (29 April 1885 – 25 November 1971) was a Scottish poet and clergyman, although recognition of his poetry was slow to develop.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Young_(poet,_born_1885)</link></item><item><title>Michael Mayer (director)</title><description>Michael Mayer (born June 27, 1960) is an American theatre director, filmmaker, and playwright. He won the Tony Award for Best Direction of a Musical in 2007 for directing Spring Awakening.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Mayer_(director)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Bob May (actor)</title><description>Bob May (September 4, 1939 – January 18, 2009) was an American actor best remembered for playing The Robot on the television series Lost in Space, which debuted in 1965 and ran until 1968.  May appeared in all 83 episodes inside a prop costume built by Bob Stewart; the robot's voice was dubbed by Dick Tufeld, who was also the narrator of the series.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bob_May_(actor)</link></item><item><title>William Campbell (actor)</title><description>William Campbell (October 30, 1923 – April 28, 2011) was an American actor who appeared in supporting roles in major film productions, and also starred in several low-budget B-movies and horror films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Campbell_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jack Douglas (actor)</title><description>John Douglas Roberton (26 April 1927 – 18 December 2008), known professionally as  Jack Douglas or Jack D. Douglas, was an English actor best known for his portrayals in the Carry On films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Douglas_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor. He is known for his role as Benedict in the Netflix period drama Bridgerton (2020–) and has also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016). He was nominated for a Laurence Olivier Award for his performance in the play A Little Life in 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Billy Harris (actor)</title><description>Billy Harris (born 12 April 1994) is an English actor. He appears as Colin Hughes in all seasons of the Apple TV+ television show Ted Lasso.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Billy_Harris_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>