<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Stephen Glover (screenwriter)</title><description>Stephen Antuan Glover (born June 18, 1988) is an American screenwriter, rapper, actor, and producer. He is known for his work as the head story editor and one of the writers for the FX comedy-drama Atlanta. He frequently collaborates with his older brother Donald Glover, who plays the lead character in Atlanta and co-stars in Guava Island, also written by Stephen.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen_Glover_(screenwriter)</link></item><item><title>Niall Williams (writer)</title><description>Niall Williams is an Irish writer. 
He has written novels, plays and non-fiction. His work has been translated into twenty different languages.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niall_Williams_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Tom Kristensen (poet)</title><description>Tom Kristensen ((1893-08-04)4 August 1893 – (1974-06-02)2 June 1974), was a Danish poet, novelist, literary critic and journalist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Kristensen_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Dennis Wilson (poet)</title><description>Dennis B. Wilson (25 June 1921 – 28 June 2022) was a British poet known mainly for his writings as a soldier in World War II.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dennis_Wilson_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Edward Field (poet)</title><description>Edward Field (born June 7, 1924) is an American poet, and an author of fiction and non-fiction, anthologies, and periodicals.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Field_(poet)</link></item><item><title>James Thomson (poet, born 1834)</title><description>James Thomson (23 November 1834 – 3 June 1882) — pen name Bysshe Vanolis — was a Scottish journalist, poet, and translator. He is remembered for The City of Dreadful Night (1874; 1880), a poetic allegory of urban suffering and despair. His pen name derives from the names of the poets Shelley and Novalis; both strong influences on him as a writer. Thomson's essays were written mainly for National Reformer, Secular Review, and Cope's Tobacco Plant. His longer poems include "The Doom of a City" (1854) in four parts, "Vane's Story" (1865), and the Orientalist ballad "Weddah and Om-El-Bonain". He admired and translated the works of the Italian poet Giacomo Leopardi and Heinrich Heine. In the title of his biography of Thomson, Bertram Dobell dubbed him "the Laureate of Pessimism".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Thomson_(poet,_born_1834)</link></item><item><title>Charles Wright (poet)</title><description>Charles Wright (born August 25, 1935) is an American poet. He shared the National Book Award in 1983 for Country Music: Selected Early Poems and won the Pulitzer Prize in 1998 for Black Zodiac. From 2014 to 2015, he served as the 20th Poet Laureate of the United States.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Wright_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Junaid Khan (Indian actor)</title><description>Junaid Khan (born 2 June 1993) is an Indian actor who works on stage as well as in Hindi films. A son of actor Aamir Khan, he began his career in various theatre productions and made his screen debut playing Karsandas Mulji in the period drama film Maharaj (2024).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Junaid_Khan_(Indian_actor)</link></item><item><title>Vijay (actor)</title><description>Joseph Vijay Chandrasekhar (born 22 June 1974), known professionally as Vijay, is an Indian actor and playback singer who works in Tamil cinema. In a career spanning over three decades, Vijay has acted in 68 films and is one of the most commercially successful actors in Tamil cinema with multiple films amongst the highest-grossing Tamil films of all time and is amongst the highest paid actors in India. He has won several awards as an actor. Referred to as "Thalapathy" (transl. Commander), Vijay has a significant fan following.
Born in Madras to director S. A. Chandrasekhar, Vijay made his debut as a child actor in the Tamil film Vetri (1984). After a few roles as a child actor in his father’s films, he played his first lead role in the film Naalaiya Theerpu (1992) at the age of 18. Vijay continued doing lead roles for the next few years with notable films amongst them included Poove Unakkaga (1996), Love Today (1997), Kadhalukku Mariyadhai (1997), Thullatha Manamum Thullum (1999) and Kushi (2000). In 1998, he was awarded Kalaimaamani by the Government of Tamil Nadu for his role in Kadhalukku Mariyadhai.
In 2004, he starred in the blockbuster action-masala film Ghilli and with subsequent success of Thirupaachi (2005) and Pokkiri (2007) later, he established himself as one of the leading and commercially successful actors in Tamil cinema. Following a period of moderate success, Vijay acted in several critically and commercially successful films starting from early 2010s including Thuppakki (2012), Kaththi (2014), Mersal (2017), Sarkar (2018), Master (2021), Beast (2022), Leo (2023) and his penultimate film The Greatest of All Time (2024).
In February 2024, Vijay announced his retirement from films and his forthcoming entry into politics with the launch of his political party, known as Tamilaga Vettri Kazhagam.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vijay_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kunal Kapoor (actor, born 1959)</title><description>Kunal Kapoor (born 26 June 1959) is an Indian actor, film producer, director and advertisement maker. Elder son of actors Shashi Kapoor and Jennifer Kendal, he made his debut with the 1972 English-language film Siddhartha, later acted in Shyam Benegal's Junoon and in his first mainstream Bollywood film, Ahista Ahista, opposite Padmini Kolhapure as well as  Vijeta. He also acted in the art films Utsav (1984) and Trikal (1985).
In 1987, he stopped acting after Trikal to set up his own company, Adfilm-Valas, to produce and direct television commercials. Adfilm Valas has also line-produced for many international feature films and ad films shot in India. Notably, the credit sequence of the film City of Joy, and the French films Le Cactus  (2005) and Fire in Paradise.
In 2015, he returned to films after 30 years, appearing in Singh is Bling as Amy Jackson's character's father.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kunal_Kapoor_(actor,_born_1959)</link></item></channel></rss>