<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1957) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>The Last Poets</title><description>The Last Poets is a poetry collective and musical group that arose in the late 1960s as part of the African-American civil rights movement and black nationalism. The name was inspired by revolutionary South African poet Keorapetse Kgositsile who believed he was in the last era of poetry before guns took over.
The group originally comprised Jalaluddin Mansur Nuriddin, Umar Bin Hassan and Abiodun Oyewole. Lineup changes and departures led to offshoots, including The Original Last Poets composed of Oyewole, Gylan Kain and David Nelson. Critic Jason Ankeny wrote: "With their politically charged raps, taut rhythms, and dedication to raising African-American consciousness, the Last Poets almost single-handedly laid the groundwork for the emergence of hip-hop." The British music magazine NME stated, "Serious spokesmen like Gil Scott-Heron, The Last Poets, and later Gary Byrd, paved the way for the many socially committed Black [emcees] a decade later." 

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Poets</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Frank McDonald (director)</title><description>Frank Burgess McDonald (November 9, 1899 – March 8, 1980) was an American film and television director, active from 1935 to 1966. He directed more than 100 films, including many Westerns starring Gene Autry and Roy Rogers, and numerous TV show episodes. He is interred at Conejo Mountain Memorial Park in Camarillo, California.
McDonald was born in Baltimore, Maryland, the son of Samuel and Florence McDonald. His father was an employee of Baltimore and Ohio Railroad. Participation in amateur theatrical productions sparked an interest in performing, causing him to leave Baltimore City College to pursue a career in entertainment.
McDonald's professional performing debut came in a vaudeville act in which he played a burglar. He also acted on Broadway, in Puppets (1925), The K Guy (1928), Just to Remind You (1931), and Bulls, Bears and Asses (1932).
McDonald married actress and musician Goodee Montgomery in 1934. She died in 1978. He died in Oxnard, California.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_McDonald_(director)</link></item><item><title>Hari (director)</title><description>Harikrishnan is an Indian film director and screenwriter who works in Tamil cinema. He is known for directing action and masala films. Hari made his directorial debut with Thamizh (2002) and went on to direct films such as Saamy (2003), Kovil (2004), Ayya (2005), Thaamirabharani (2007), Vel (2007), and the Singam film series (2010-2017). He mostly directs Coimbatore, Dindigul, Tenkasi and Thoothukudi-Tirunelveli district based movies.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hari_(director)</link></item><item><title>James Anderson (English actor)</title><description>James Anderson (born 3 November 1980) is a British actor.
Born in the Surrey village of Thursley, Anderson graduated with first class honours from Warwick University and went on to train at the Actors Studio (MFA) in New York City. He has since had roles across TV, stage and film.
He is known for playing Oliver Valentine on the BBC medical drama Holby City between 2009 and 2021.
For his debut film he was recipient of the Gold Hugo Award (2006), gaining eligibility for an Academy Award (2008).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Anderson_(English_actor)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor. He is known for his role as Benedict in the Netflix period drama Bridgerton (2020–present) and has also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016). He was nominated for a Laurence Olivier Award for his performance in the play A Little Life in 2024.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Roger Clark (actor, born 1978)</title><description>Roger Clark (born July 14, 1978) is an Irish-American actor and voice actor. He is best known for portraying Arthur Morgan through performance capture in the 2018 video game Red Dead Redemption 2, a role which garnered him critical acclaim and numerous accolades.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Clark_(actor,_born_1978)</link></item><item><title>Ibrahim Ali Khan (actor)</title><description>Ibrahim Ali Khan Pataudi (born 5 March 2001) is an Indian actor who works in Hindi films. Born to actors Saif Ali Khan and Amrita Singh, he had his first acting role as a child as the younger version of his father's character in Tashan (2008). As an adult, he had his first leading role in the poorly-received Netflix romantic comedy film Nadaaniyan (2025).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ibrahim_Ali_Khan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Trevor Morgan (actor)</title><description>Trevor John Morgan (born November 26, 1986) is an American actor. He has appeared in the films Genius, The Sixth Sense, The Patriot, A Rumor of Angels, Jurassic Park III, The Glass House, Chasing 3000, Mean Creek, Barney's Great Adventure (based on the popular children's television series), Local Color, Family Plan, and Uncle Nino.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trevor_Morgan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ben Foster (actor)</title><description>Benjamin A. Foster (born October 29, 1980) is an American actor. His films include The Punisher (2004), X-Men: The Last Stand and Alpha Dog (both 2006), 30 Days of Night (2007), The Messenger and Pandorum (both 2009), The Mechanic (2011), Contraband (2012), Kill Your Darlings and Lone Survivor (both 2013), The Program (2015), Warcraft (2016), and Leave No Trace (2018). He has won an Independent Spirit Award for portraying Tanner Howard in Hell or High Water (2016). He also had a recurring role as Russell Corwin in Six Feet Under (2003–05).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Foster_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>