<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Claude Roy (poet)</title><description>Claude Roy (28 August 1915 – 13 December 1997) was a French poet and essayist. He was born and died in Paris.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claude_Roy_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Hikari (director)</title><description>Mitsuyo Miyazaki (宮崎 光代, Miyazaki Mitsuyo; born 1976 or 1977), better known mononymously as Hikari, is a Japanese filmmaker and former actress. She is best known for writing, directing, and producing the drama film 37 Seconds (2019), and directing three episodes of the Netflix series Beef (2023). She co-wrote and directed the comedy-drama film Rental Family (2025).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hikari_(director)</link></item><item><title>Shawn Harrison (actor)</title><description>Shawn Harrison (born December 28, 1973) is an American actor known for his role as Waldo Faldo, the dim-witted but lovable chef-in-training on the ABC sitcom Family Matters from 1990 to 1996.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shawn_Harrison_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Miles Brown (actor)</title><description>Miles Brown (born December 28, 2004), also known by his stage name Baby Boogaloo, is an American actor, dancer, and rapper. He is best known for his role as Jack Johnson in the ABC comedy series Black-ish.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miles_Brown_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>John Callahan (actor)</title><description>John Kevin Callahan (December 23, 1953 – March 28, 2020) was an American actor, known for his work as Edmund Grey on the daytime soap opera All My Children and Eric Stavros on Falcon Crest.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Callahan_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>