<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>76th Writers Guild of America Awards</title><description>The 76th Writers Guild of America Awards was held on April 14, 2024, to honor the best writing in film, television and radio of 2023. The nominees were announced on February 21, 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/76th_Writers_Guild_of_America_Awards</link></item><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Mark Bailey (writer)</title><description>Mark Daniel Bailey (born November 21, 1968) is an American writer, best known for his documentary films, including Last Days in Vietnam (2014), Downfall: The Case Against Boeing (2022), and The Volcano: Rescue from Whakaari (2022). Bailey, together with his wife, filmmaker Rory Kennedy, own Moxie Films, a documentary film production company. The company produces documentaries "for broadcast and cable networks, including Netflix, HBO, PBS, A&amp;E, National Geographic, Showtime, Discovery Channel, MTV, TLC, Lifetime Television, the Oxygen Network, and the Sundance Channel as well as for educational foundations and philanthropic organizations."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Bailey_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Peter Hermann (actor)</title><description>Peter Hermann (born August 15, 1967) is an American actor. He may be best known for his roles as Charles Brooks in Younger, Trevor Langan in Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit, and Jack Boyle in Blue Bloods. Hermann is the husband of fellow Law &amp; Order franchise actor Mariska Hargitay, series lead of Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Hermann_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Duncan (poet)</title><description>Robert Edward Duncan (January 7, 1919 – February 3, 1988) was an American poet and a devotee of Hilda "H.D." Doolittle and the Western esoteric tradition who spent most of his career in and around San Francisco. Though associated with any number of literary traditions and schools, Duncan is often identified with the poets of the New American Poetry and Black Mountain College. Duncan saw his work as emerging especially from the tradition of Pound, Williams and Lawrence. Duncan was a key figure in the San Francisco Renaissance.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Duncan_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Philip Levine (poet)</title><description>Philip Levine (January 10, 1928 – February 14, 2015) was an American poet best known for his poems about working-class Detroit. He taught for more than thirty years in the English department of California State University, Fresno and held teaching positions at other universities as well. He served on the Board of Chancellors of the Academy of American Poets from 2000 to 2006, and was appointed Poet Laureate of the United States for 2011–2012.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philip_Levine_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Alan Taylor (director)</title><description>Alan Taylor (born January 13, 1959) is an American television director, film director, screenwriter, and television producer. He is best known for his work on television series such as The Sopranos, Sex and the City, Mad Men, and Game of Thrones. He also directed films such as Palookaville, Thor: The Dark World, Terminator Genisys, and The Many Saints of Newark.
In 2007, Taylor won a Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Directing for a Drama Series for The Sopranos episode "Kennedy and Heidi". In 2008 and 2018, he was also nominated in the same category for the Mad Men episode "Smoke Gets in Your Eyes" and the Game of Thrones episode "Beyond the Wall", respectively.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Taylor_(director)</link></item><item><title>Matt Johnson (director)</title><description>Matt Johnson (born October 5, 1985) is a Canadian actor and filmmaker. He first attracted accolades for his low-budget independent feature films, including The Dirties (2013), which won Best Narrative Feature at the Slamdance Film Festival, and Operation Avalanche (2016), which premiered at the Sundance Film Festival.
Johnson achieved acclaim and commercial success with his third feature film, BlackBerry (2023), which documented the rise and fall of the BlackBerry phone. The film premiered in competition at the 73rd Berlin International Film Festival, and went on to win several accolades including the $50,000 Rogers Best Canadian Film Award from the Toronto Film Critics Association.
In addition to his feature films, Johnson is known for co-creating, co-starring in, and directing the mockumentary-sitcom Nirvanna the Band the Show.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matt_Johnson_(director)</link></item><item><title>Charlie Hall (actor, born 1997)</title><description>Charlie Hall (born May 30, 1997) is an American television and film actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hall_(actor,_born_1997)</link></item><item><title>Salvatore Esposito (actor)</title><description>Salvatore Esposito (Italian: [salvaˈtoːre eˈspɔːzito]; born 2 February 1986, Naples) is an Italian actor. He is best known for his leading role as Gennaro "Genny" Savastano on the Sky Italia television series Gomorrah (2014–2021). In 2020, Esposito made his English-language debut, appearing in the 4th season of the American TV series Fargo. His role in the series, as intimidating Italian mobster Gaetano Fadda, was highly praised.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salvatore_Esposito_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Benjamin Walker (actor)</title><description>Benjamin Walker Scodelario-Davis (né Davis; born June 21, 1982) is an American actor and stand-up comedian. He starred as Andrew Jackson in the musical Bloody Bloody Andrew Jackson, which premiered on Broadway in 2010. He has appeared in a number of Broadway productions, notably as Patrick Bateman in the 2016 musical adaptation of the novel American Psycho and as Chris Keller in the 2019 revival of All My Sons, for which he was nominated for a Tony Award for Best Featured Actor. On screen, he is known for his title role in the 2012 film Abraham Lincoln: Vampire Hunter, as well as his appearances in the films Kinsey, Flags of Our Fathers, and In the Heart of the Sea. In 2019, he starred as Erik Gelden in the third and final season of the Netflix series Jessica Jones. He plays the High King of the Ñoldorin Elves Ereinion Gil-galad in the Amazon Prime Video series The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benjamin_Walker_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor. He is known for his role as Benedict in the Netflix period drama Bridgerton (2020–) and has also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016). He was nominated for a Laurence Olivier Award for his performance in the play A Little Life in 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Christopher Jones (actor, born 1941)</title><description>William Frank Jones (August 18, 1941 – January 31, 2014), known professionally as Christopher Jones, was an American actor. He was best known for his starring roles in the films Wild in the Streets (1968) and Ryan's Daughter (1970), and for playing the title role in the 1960s television series The Legend of Jesse James.
According to The New York Times, Jones' "talent and star power drew comparisons with James Dean," and he "seemed poised for stardom before abruptly abandoning his movie career in the late 1960s."

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Jones_(actor,_born_1941)</link></item><item><title>Robert Lee (British actor)</title><description>Robert Ya Fu Lee (30 November 1913 – 1 December 1986) was a Chinese actor based in the United Kingdom.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Lee_(British_actor)</link></item></channel></rss>