<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Joan London (American writer)</title><description>Joan London (January 15, 1901 – January 18, 1971) was an American writer and the older of two daughters born to Jack London and his first wife, Elizabeth "Bess" Maddern London.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joan_London_(American_writer)</link></item><item><title>The Poets</title><description>The Tortured Poets Department is the eleventh studio album by the American singer-songwriter Taylor Swift. It was released on April 19, 2024, through Republic Records, with a double album edition subtitled The Anthology being released two hours after the standard edition. Swift wrote and produced the album with Jack Antonoff and Aaron Dessner while she was embarking on the American leg of the Eras Tour in 2023.
Using autobiographical songwriting, The Tortured Poets Department reflects Swift's cathartic episode while she was experiencing personal upheavals amidst breakups and heightened fame. Its songs depict grief and emotional tumult caused by ill-fated romance in a hyperbolic and confrontational manner, exploring themes of mourning, depression, anger, delusion, erotic desires, and self-aware humor. Musically, The Tortured Poets Department features two production styles. The standard edition is largely minimalist, mid-tempo synth-pop, characterized by synthesizers, sustained bass, and programmed drums. The Anthology primarily consists of mellow, acoustic chamber pop and folk-pop ballads driven by piano and guitar. The album incorporates elements of electronica, country, rock, folk, and western.
Swift promoted the album via social media and music streaming platforms, and she included an extended set list for the Eras Tour in 2024. The Tortured Poets Department topped charts across Europe, Asia–Pacific, and the Americas; broke streaming and sales records; and became the global best-selling album of 2024. In the United States, The Tortured Poets Department became Swift's seventh album to open with over a million units and first to open with two million units, spent 17 weeks atop the Billboard 200, and was certified eight-times platinum by the Recording Industry Association of America. Its songs made Swift the first artist to monopolize the Billboard Hot 100's top 14 spots, with the lead single "Fortnight" featuring Post Malone topping the chart.
Critical reception of The Tortured Poets Department upon its release was mixed; positive reviews praised the cathartic narrative songwriting as emotionally resonant and deemed the album one of Swift's finest works, but negative reviews described the production as redundant and the lyrics verbose rather than poetic. Within weeks after the initial reviews, several journalists reassessed the album and appreciated the musical and lyrical nuances, opining that the criticism was overshadowed by Swift's media overexposure. The album received an ARIA Music Award, a Premios Odeón, a Japan Gold Disc Award, and five nominations at the 67th Annual Grammy Awards, including Album of the Year.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tortured_Poets_Department</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Anurag Singh (director)</title><description>Anurag Singh Thind (born 17 November 1975), is an Indian film director, screenwriter and producer who mainly works in Punjabi and Hindi cinema. Known for his comedy and period war genre films, he is widely recognized as one of the most influential film directors of Punjabi cinema.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anurag_Singh_(director)</link></item><item><title>Peter Robbins (actor)</title><description>Peter Robbins (born Louis G. Nanasi; August 10, 1956 – January 18, 2022) was an American actor and real estate broker. Robbins gained national fame in the 1960s for being the first actor to voice Charlie Brown in the Peanuts animated specials.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Robbins_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kunal Kapoor (actor, born 1959)</title><description>Kunal Kapoor (born 26 June 1959) is an Indian actor, film producer, director and advertisement maker. Elder son of actors Shashi Kapoor and Jennifer Kendal, he made his debut with the 1972 English-language film Siddhartha, later acted in Shyam Benegal's Junoon and in his first mainstream Bollywood film, Ahista Ahista, opposite Padmini Kolhapure as well as  Vijeta. He also acted in the art films Utsav (1984) and Trikal (1985).
In 1987, he stopped acting after Trikal to set up his own company, Adfilm-Valas, to produce and direct television commercials. Adfilm Valas has also line-produced for many international feature films and ad films shot in India. Notably, the credit sequence of the film City of Joy, and the French films Le Cactus  (2005) and Fire in Paradise.
In 2015, he returned to films after 30 years, appearing in Singh is Bling as Amy Jackson's character's father.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kunal_Kapoor_(actor,_born_1959)</link></item><item><title>Kevin McGarry (actor)</title><description>Kevin W. McGarry (born March 18, 1985) is a Canadian actor, director, and writer best known for his roles as Nathan Grant on the Hallmark Channel series When Calls the Heart, Mitch Cutty on CBC Television's long running series Heartland, and Peter Hastings in The Wedding Veil film series. He has appeared in numerous romantic comedies and television movies, primarily for Hallmark Channel and is well known Hallmark actor.
Born in Kincardine, Ontario, Canada on March 18, 1985. McGarry developed an interest in acting by chance during high school when he wandered into a 12th grade theatre class as a freshman.  
McGarry attended George Brown College; studied theatre at Fanshawe College and further honed his skills at Pro Actors Lab in Toronto.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kevin_McGarry_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Derek Richardson (actor)</title><description>Derek Richardson Jr. (born January 18, 1976) is an American actor. He is best known for his TV roles on Men in Trees and Anger Management, and for starring as young Harry Dunne in the film Dumb and Dumberer: When Harry Met Lloyd.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Derek_Richardson_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>