<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Ian Patterson (poet)</title><description>Ian Kenneth Patterson (born 31 August 1948) is a British poet, translator and academic. He is a Life Fellow of Queens' College, Cambridge, having retired in 2018 from his post as Senior Lecturer in English Literature, Director of Studies in English and Fellow Librarian.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Patterson_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.
In 2009, the founders of the Royal Ballet were commemorated in a memorial floor stone and on 25 September 2010, the writer Elizabeth Gaskell was celebrated with the dedication of a panel in the memorial window. On 6 December 2011, former Poet Laureate Ted Hughes was commemorated with a floor stone. On 22 November 2013, the fiftieth anniversary of his death, writer C. S. Lewis was commemorated with a memorial floor stone. The poet Philip Larkin was commemorated with a floor stone dedicated on 2 December 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became the independent production company A24's highest-grossing release, and won the duo many awards, including  Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Director General of the Indian Coast Guard</title><description>The Director General of the Indian Coast Guard (DG ICG) is the head of the Indian Coast Guard. The DG ICG has their office in the Coast Guard Headquarters (CGHQ) in New Delhi. Appointed by the Government of India, the DG ICG reports to the Minister of Defence. The Director General is assisted by four Deputy Directors General, each holding the rank of inspector-general, and other senior officers heading various staff divisions. The Additional Director General of the ICG serves as the second-in-command to the Director General.
The post of Director General of the Indian Coast Guard is held by a three-star rank holder as a position and is not a rank in itself. It is equivalent to Vice Admiral of the Indian Navy, Lieutenant General of the Indian Army and the Air Marshal of the Indian Air Force. The rank of Additional Director General of the Indian Coast Guard is equivalent to that of a Lieutenant General of the Indian Army.
Rakesh Pal was the current Director General of the Indian Coast Guard who assumed the office after Virender Singh Pathania retired. The Flag officer was the fourth direct entry Coast Guard officer who took over the helm of the ICG on 19 July 2023 as the 25th Director General but died on 18th August 2024 following a cardiac arrest.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Director_General_of_the_Indian_Coast_Guard</link></item><item><title>Abhishek Banerjee (actor)</title><description>Abhishek Banerjee (born 5 May 1985) is an Indian actor and casting director. He is best known for his roles in the Maddock Supernatural Universe films Stree, Bhediya and Stree 2 and as Hathoda Tyagi in Amazon Prime Video series Paatal Lok. Banerjee's other notable films include Dream Girl, Dream Girl 2, Rashmi Rocket and Vedaa.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abhishek_Banerjee_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Don Harvey (actor, born 1960)</title><description>Donald Patrick Harvey II (born May 31, 1960) is an American actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don_Harvey_(actor,_born_1960)</link></item><item><title>Stuart Graham (actor)</title><description>Stuart Graham (born 31 August 1967) is a film, television, and stage actor, born and brought up in Northern Ireland.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuart_Graham_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Joseph Quinn (actor)</title><description>Joseph Quinn (born 26 January 1994) is an English actor. He is best known for his role as Eddie Munson in the fourth season of the Netflix series Stranger Things (2022). His previous appearances were in the BBC One series Dickensian (2016), Howards End (2017), and Les Misérables (2018), and the Sky Atlantic series Catherine the Great (2019). He has since starred in the horror film A Quiet Place: Day One (2024).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joseph_Quinn_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>