<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Hernan Diaz (writer)</title><description>Hernan Diaz (born 1973) is an Argentine-American writer. His 2017 novel In the Distance was a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction, as well as the PEN/Faulkner Award for Fiction. He also received a Whiting Award. For his second novel Trust, he was awarded the 2023 Pulitzer Prize for Fiction.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hernan_Diaz_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Mark Bailey (writer)</title><description>Mark Daniel Bailey (born November 21, 1968) is an American writer, best known for his documentary films, including Last Days in Vietnam (2014), Downfall: The Case Against Boeing (2022), and The Volcano: Rescue from Whakaari (2022). Bailey, together with his wife, filmmaker Rory Kennedy, own Moxie Films, a documentary film production company. The company produces documentaries "for broadcast and cable networks, including Netflix, HBO, PBS, A&amp;E, National Geographic, Showtime, Discovery Channel, MTV, TLC, Lifetime Television, the Oxygen Network, and the Sundance Channel as well as for educational foundations and philanthropic organizations."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Bailey_(writer)</link></item><item><title>List of African writers by country</title><description>This is a list of prominent and notable writers from Africa. It includes poets, novelists, children's writers, essayists, and scholars, listed by country.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_African_writers_by_country</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.
Over a dozen national governments continue the poet laureate tradition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>David Lowery (director)</title><description>David Lowery (born December 26, 1980) is an American filmmaker.
His original work Ain't Them Bodies Saints (2013), starring Rooney Mara and Casey Affleck, was nominated for the Grand Jury Prize at the 2013 Sundance Film Festival. In 2016, he directed the Disney film Pete's Dragon (2016), a live-action film which he had co-written. It was a new work loosely based on the same original story as the Disney 1977 musical of the same name. In 2017, he directed the drama film A Ghost Story and in 2018, he directed The Old Man &amp; the Gun. In 2021, he directed the fantasy epic The Green Knight.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Lowery_(director)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor. He is best known for his role as Benedict, the second Bridgerton child, in the Netflix show Bridgerton. For his theatre work, he received number of accolades, including a WhatsOnStage Award and a nomination for a Laurence Olivier Award. He also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Anthony Edwards (actor)</title><description>Anthony Charles Edwards (born July 19, 1962) is an American actor, director, and producer. He played Dr. Mark Greene on the first eight seasons of ER, for which he received a Golden Globe Award and six Screen Actors Guild Awards, and was nominated for four consecutive Primetime Emmy Awards. He has appeared in various films and television series, including Fast Times at Ridgemont High, Top Gun, Zodiac, Gotcha!, Miracle Mile, Revenge of the Nerds, Planes, Northern Exposure, and Designated Survivor.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Edwards_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Meteor Man (1993), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. Townsend is also known for his role as Donald "Duck" Matthews in his 1991 film The Five Heartbeats. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ian Chen (actor)</title><description>Ian Chen (born September 7, 2006) is an American actor. He is known for his roles as Evan Huang in the ABC sitcom Fresh Off the Boat (2015–2020) and Eugene Choi in the DC Extended Universe films Shazam! (2019) and Shazam! Fury of the Gods (2023).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Chen_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ben Foster (actor)</title><description>Benjamin A. Foster (born October 29, 1980) is an American actor. His films include The Punisher (2004), X-Men: The Last Stand and Alpha Dog (both 2006), 30 Days of Night (2007), The Messenger and Pandorum (both 2009), The Mechanic (2011), Contraband (2012), Kill Your Darlings and Lone Survivor (both 2013), The Program (2015), and Leave No Trace (2018). He has won an Independent Spirit Award for portraying Tanner Howard in Hell or High Water (2016). He also had a recurring role as Russell Corwin in the television series Six Feet Under (2003–2005).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Foster_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jeremy Jordan (actor, born 1984)</title><description>Jeremy Michael Jordan (born November 20, 1984) is an American actor and singer. He has performed on Broadway, in television and film, in concert, as well as in other theatrical productions.
He made his Broadway debut in 2009 as part of Rock of Ages. Subsequently, he went to star in the original Broadway musicals Bonnie &amp; Clyde (2011) as Clyde Barrow and Newsies (2012) as Jack Kelly, for which he was nominated for a Tony Award and a Grammy Award. He has also appeared in the Broadway productions of the musicals West Side Story as Tony and Waitress as Dr. Jim Pomatter, as well as the play American Son on Broadway. In 2021 and 2023, he starred as Seymour Krelborn in the Off-Broadway revival of Little Shop of Horrors and in 2024 returned to Broadway originating the role of Jay Gatsby in The Great Gatsby. 
On screen, he starred opposite Anna Kendrick in the 2014 musical film The Last Five Years and as Jimmy Collins in the NBC series Smash (2013). From 2015 to 2021, he played Winslow "Winn" Schott Jr. on the CBS/CW DC Comics-based superhero drama series Supergirl. In 2017–2020, he voiced Varian in the Disney Channel original Tangled:  The Series. Since 2024, he has voiced Lucifer Morningstar in the adult animated musical series Hazbin Hotel.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeremy_Jordan_(actor,_born_1984)</link></item><item><title>Jonathan Adams (American actor)</title><description>Jonathan Adams (born July 16, 1967) is an American actor. He is best known for playing Henry Walker on American Dreams, Daniel Goodman on Bones and Chuck Larabee on Last Man Standing. He is also known as a voice actor with roles such as Galactus, Dormammu and Kang the Conqueror from Marvel Comics and Darkseid and Atrocitus from DC Comics.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jonathan_Adams_(American_actor)</link></item></channel></rss>