<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1949) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Mark Bailey (writer)</title><description>Mark Daniel Bailey (born November 21, 1968) is an American writer, best known for his documentary films, including Last Days in Vietnam (2014), Downfall: The Case Against Boeing (2022), and The Volcano: Rescue from Whakaari (2022). Bailey, together with his wife, filmmaker Rory Kennedy, own Moxie Films, a documentary film production company. The company produces documentaries "for broadcast and cable networks, including Netflix, HBO, PBS, A&amp;E, National Geographic, Showtime, Discovery Channel, MTV, TLC, Lifetime Television, the Oxygen Network, and the Sundance Channel as well as for educational foundations and philanthropic organizations."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Bailey_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Andrew Young (poet, born 1885)</title><description>Andrew John Young (29 April 1885 – 25 November 1971) was a Scottish poet and clergyman, although recognition of his poetry was slow to develop.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Young_(poet,_born_1885)</link></item><item><title>Max Winkler (director)</title><description>Max Daniel Winkler (born August 18, 1983) is an American director and screenwriter. His credits include directing the film Ceremony (2010), starring Michael Angarano and Uma Thurman. The film was Winkler's feature film directorial debut.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Winkler_(director)</link></item><item><title>Michael Gordon (film director)</title><description>Michael Gordon (born Irving Kunin Gordon; September 6, 1909 – April 29, 1993) was an American stage actor and stage and film director.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Gordon_(film_director)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>William Campbell (actor)</title><description>William Campbell (October 30, 1923 – April 28, 2011) was an American actor who appeared in supporting roles in major film productions, and also starred in several low-budget B-movies and horror films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Campbell_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Feroz Khan (actor)</title><description>Feroz Khan (born Zulfiqar Ali Shah Khan; 25 September 1939 — 27 April 2009) was an Indian actor, film editor, producer and director best known for his work in Indian cinema. He appeared in over 60 films throughout his career and became one of Bollywood's popular style icons. Feroz Khan rose to prominence with Phani Majumdar's drama film Oonche Log (1965), and starred in successful Hindi films, such as Arzoo (1965), Aag (1967), Safar (1970), Mela (1971), Apradh (1972), Geeta Mera Naam (1974), Khotte Sikkay (1974), Kaala Sona (1975), Dharmatma (1975), Nagin (1976), Shankar Shambhu (1976) and Qurbani (1980). The 2007 superhit Welcome (2007), was his final film.
He won the Filmfare Best Supporting Actor Award for Aadmi Aur Insaan (1969) in 1970, and was honored with the Filmfare Lifetime Achievement Award in 2000. He has been called "Clint Eastwood of India".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feroz_Khan_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>