<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Peter James (writer)</title><description>Peter J. James (born 22 August 1948) is a British writer of crime. He was born in Brighton, the son of Cornelia James, the former glovemaker to Queen Elizabeth II.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_James_(writer)</link></item><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Kenneth Anderson (writer)</title><description>Kenneth Douglas Stewart Anderson (8 March 1910 – 30 August 1974) was an Indian writer and hunter who wrote books about his adventures in the jungles of South India.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenneth_Anderson_(writer)</link></item><item><title>List of directorial debuts</title><description>This is a list of film directorial debuts in chronological order. The films and dates referred to are a director's first commercial cinematic release. Many filmmakers have directed works which were not commercially released, for example early works by Orson Welles such as his filming of his stage production of Twelfth Night in 1933 or his experimental short film The Hearts of Age in 1934. Often, these early works were not intended for commercial release by intent, such as film school projects or inability to find distribution.
Subsequently, many directors learned their trade in the medium of television as it became popular in the 1940s and 1950s. Notable directors who did their first directorial work in this medium include Robert Altman, Sidney Lumet, and Alfonso Cuarón. As commercial television advertising became more cinematic in the 1960s and 1970s, many directors early work was in this medium, including directors such as Alan Parker and Ridley Scott. With the success of MTV and the popularity of music videos from the early 1980s, this gave another avenue for directors to hone their skills. Notable directors whose early work was in music videos include David Fincher, Jonathan Glazer, Michel Gondry, and Spike Jonze.
The following symbols indicate where a director has worked in another medium prior to directing commercially.
♦ Indicates where a director has created other earlier works for television
# Indicates when a director's earlier work is uncredited
† Indicates when a director's earlier work has not been released in cinemas, for example film school productions, short films or music videos.
Refer to individual entries for further detail.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_directorial_debuts</link></item><item><title>Andrew Wilson (actor)</title><description>Andrew Cunningham Wilson (born August 22, 1964) is an American actor and director. He is the older brother of actors Owen Wilson and Luke Wilson.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Wilson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Charles Gray (actor)</title><description>Charles Gray (born Donald Marshall Gray; 29 August 1928 – 7 March 2000) was an English actor and voice artist. Appearing in around 140 films and TV series, he was best known as the arch-villain Ernst Stavro Blofeld in the James Bond film Diamonds Are Forever; Dikko Henderson in a previous Bond film, You Only Live Twice; Sherlock Holmes's brother Mycroft Holmes in The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes; and The Criminologist in The Rocky Horror Picture Show.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Gray_(actor)</link></item><item><title>James Coombes (actor)</title><description>James Coombes (born 8 October 1956 in Newport, Monmouthshire) is a British film, television and theatre actor.
He trained as an actor at the Birmingham School of Speech and Drama from 1975 to 1978.
He is best known for his roles as Pierre Challon during the final series of the BBC drama Howards' Way, Iain Strathmorris in the long running STV series Take The High Road, and Grendel in HTV's Robin of Sherwood. He also donned the famous black polo top as the iconic Milk Tray Man in the eighties' TV adverts. He appeared as Paroli in the 1984 Doctor Who serial Warriors of the Deep and provided the voice of the Krargs in the lost episode Shada, written by Douglas Adams. He has appeared in many films including Murder with Mirrors co-starring with Bette Davis and Helen Hayes, and played Richard Gere's son, Amnon, in the Bible epic, King David. He also played Sir Lancelot in the Disney film, A Knight in Camelot with Whoopi Goldberg. He appeared in Monarch.
Coombes has worked extensively in the theatre including seasons at Chichester Festival, Pitlochry Festival, Bristol Old Vic, London Young Vic, The Arts Theatre, London, Ludlow Festival, Coventry, Southampton Nuffield and Birmingham Rep.
Other credits include: Minder on the Orient Express, The Country Diary of an Edwardian Lady, Capital City, US mini series Napoleon and Josephine, Boon, The Kenny Everett Television Show, Drop the Dead Donkey, Saracen, Heartbeat, Bugs, Holby City, Starhunter, The Bill, My Family and Dinosapien.  He appeared as Paul Deroulard in "The Chocolate Box" episode of Agatha Christie's Poirot, and was Gennaro Lucca in the Jeremy Brett Memoirs of Sherlock Holmes adventure, "The Red Circle" . He recently appeared in a UK and Ireland tour of Dirty Dancing, playing Dr. Jake Houseman following runs at the Piccadilly Theatre, and the Phoenix Theatre, London. He appears as Governor De Rouvray in Knightfall which started broadcasting in December 2017 on History Channel. In January 2018, he directed Hayfever by Noel Coward at ArtsEd London.
As well as acting, Coombes regularly tutors at the Academy of Creative Training in Brighton and guest directs at ArtsEd School of Musical Theatre, and Drama Studio London. He is a trustee for charity Acting for Others which provides support to all theatre workers in times of need. https://actingforothers.co.uk. He is also a founding trustee of theatre company Persever Productions Ltd https://persever-productions.co.uk During the Covid pandemic, Coombes retired from acting and is now a photographer and documentary film maker https://jamescoombesphotography.com

In 1989, he married Cathy Finlay, daughter of actor Frank Finlay CBE. They have three children, Josh (drummer in rock band TIGRESS), Charlotte and Benedict.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Coombes_(actor)</link></item><item><title>David Paul (actor)</title><description>David Paul (March 8, 1957 – March 6, 2020) was an American actor and bodybuilder. He and his twin brother Peter were born in Hartford, Connecticut and grew up in Rhode Island. The death of David was confirmed by his twin brother Peter. David died just two days before the twins' 63rd birthday.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Paul_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>