<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1958) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Ian Brennan (writer)</title><description>Ian Brennan (born April 23, 1978) is an American screenwriter, director and actor. He is known for creating the American television shows Glee, Scream Queens, The Politician, and Monster.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Brennan_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.
Over a dozen national governments continue the poet laureate tradition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>National poet</title><description>A national poet or national bard is a poet held by tradition and popular acclaim to represent the identity, beliefs and principles of a particular national culture. The national poet as culture hero is a long-standing symbol, to be distinguished from successive holders of a bureaucratically-appointed poet-laureate office. The idea and honoring of national poets emerged primarily during Romanticism, as a figure that helped consolidation of the nation states, as it provided validation of their ethno-linguistic groups.
Most national poets are historic figures, though a few contemporary writers working in relatively new or revived national literatures are also considered "national poets". Though not formally elected, national poets play a role in shaping a country's understanding of itself. Some nations may have more than one national poet; the idea of a single one is always a simplification. It has been argued that a national poet "must write poetry that closely identifies with the nation's cause – or is thought to do so", with an additional assumption being that "a national poet must write in a national language".
The following is a list of nations, with their associated national poets. It is not a list of sovereign states or countries, though many of the nations listed may also be such. The terms "nation" (as cultural concept), "country" (as geographical concept) and "state" (as political concept) are not synonyms.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_poet</link></item><item><title>Edward Thomas (poet)</title><description>Philip Edward Thomas (3 March 1878 – 9 April 1917) was a British writer of poetry and prose. He is sometimes considered a war poet, although few of his poems deal directly with his war experiences.  He only started writing poetry at the age of 36, but by that time he had already been a prolific critic, biographer, nature writer and travel writer for two decades. In 1915, he enlisted in the British Army to fight in the First World War and was killed in action during the Battle of Arras in 1917, soon after he arrived in France.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Thomas_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Max Winkler (director)</title><description>Max Daniel Winkler (born August 18, 1983) is an American director and screenwriter. His credits include directing the film Ceremony (2010), starring Michael Angarano and Uma Thurman. The film was Winkler's feature film directorial debut.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Winkler_(director)</link></item><item><title>Sean Foley (director)</title><description>Sean Foley (born John Foley; 21 November 1964) is a British director, writer, comedian and actor. Following early success as part of the comedy double act The Right Size and their long-running stage show The Play What I Wrote, Foley has more recently become a director, including of several West End comedy productions. From 2019 to 2024, he was appointed as Artistic Director of the Birmingham Repertory Theatre.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sean_Foley_(director)</link></item><item><title>Gordon Hunt (director)</title><description>Gordon Edwynn Hunt (April 26, 1929 – December 17, 2016) was an American writer, director and actor who worked in television, film, theatre and voice work. 
He directed such animated productions as The Jetsons, Scooby-Doo, Super Friends, The Richie Rich Show, The Smurfs, Pound Puppies, Tom &amp; Jerry Kids, The Pirates of Dark Water, Droopy, Master Detective and The New Adventures of Captain Planet.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gordon_Hunt_(director)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Meteor Man (1993), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. Townsend is also known for his role as Donald "Duck" Matthews in his 1991 film The Five Heartbeats. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>James Olson (actor)</title><description>James Olson (October 8, 1930 – April 17, 2022) was an American actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Olson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Anthony Edwards (actor)</title><description>Anthony Charles Edwards (born July 19, 1962) is an American actor, director, and producer. He played Dr. Mark Greene on the first eight seasons of ER, for which he received a Golden Globe Award and six Screen Actors Guild Awards, and was nominated for four consecutive Primetime Emmy Awards. He has appeared in various films and television series, including Fast Times at Ridgemont High, Top Gun, Zodiac, Gotcha!, Miracle Mile, Revenge of the Nerds, Planes, Northern Exposure, and Designated Survivor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Edwards_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ben Foster (actor)</title><description>Benjamin A. Foster (born October 29, 1980) is an American actor. His films include The Punisher (2004), X-Men: The Last Stand and Alpha Dog (both 2006), 30 Days of Night (2007), The Messenger and Pandorum (both 2009), The Mechanic (2011), Contraband (2012), Kill Your Darlings and Lone Survivor (both 2013), The Program (2015), Warcraft (2016), and Leave No Trace (2018). He has won an Independent Spirit Award for portraying Tanner Howard in Hell or High Water (2016). He also had a recurring role as Russell Corwin in the television series Six Feet Under (2003–2005).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Foster_(actor)</link></item><item><title>William Moseley (actor)</title><description>William Peter Moseley (born 27 April 1987) is an English actor. He is known for his portrayal of the fictional character Peter Pevensie in The Chronicles of Narnia (2005–2010) trilogy, which won him a Kids' Choice Award, in addition to nominations for a Saturn Award and a Young Artist Award. He also played Prince Liam in the E! series The Royals (2015–2018).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Moseley_(actor)</link></item><item><title>John Robinson (American actor)</title><description>John Robinson (born October 25, 1985) is an American actor. He portrayed John McFarland in Gus Van Sant's Elephant and Stacy Peralta in the skateboarding film Lords of Dogtown.
Robinson enjoys snowboarding and played lacrosse in high school. He has also done some modeling. He is a 2005 graduate of the Oregon Episcopal School. Robinson gave an in-depth interview in issue 10 of Hero, published in October 2013.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Robinson_(American_actor)</link></item><item><title>William Campbell (actor)</title><description>William Campbell (October 30, 1923 – April 28, 2011) was an American actor who appeared in supporting roles in major film productions, and also starred in several low-budget B-movies and horror films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Campbell_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>