<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, England, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Kevin J. O'Connor (actor)</title><description>Kevin James O'Connor (born November 15, 1963) is an American actor, known for portraying character roles in major studio films such as F/X2, Lord of Illusions, The Mummy, Van Helsing, There Will Be Blood and G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra. He is a favorite of writer/directors Stephen Sommers and Paul Thomas Anderson, who often cast him in their films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kevin_J._O%27Connor_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Sean Murray (actor)</title><description>Sean Harland Murray (born November 15, 1977) is an American actor known for his role as Special Agent Timothy McGee on the American TV drama NCIS, Thackery Binx in Disney's Halloween film Hocus Pocus and Danny Walden in the military drama series JAG.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sean_Murray_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ranjith (actor)</title><description>Ranjith (born 15 November 1972) is an Indian actor and director who appears in Tamil and Malayalam language films. In 2024, he participated in the reality show Bigg Boss 8 as a contestant.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranjith_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kim Ji-hoon (actor, born 1981)</title><description>Kim Ji-hoon (Korean: 김지훈; born May 9, 1981) is a South Korean actor. He is best known for his romantic comedies on television such as The Golden Age of Daughters-in-Law (2007), Love Marriage (also known as Matchmaker's Lover, 2008), Stars Falling from the Sky (also known as Wish Upon a Star, 2010), and My Cute Guys (2012). In 2010, he also appeared in the film Natalie, and cable mystery series Joseon X-Files. In 2023 he appeared in Lee Chung-hyun's Netflix film Ballerina.  He was cast as a hired assassin in Amazon Prime Video 2025 TV series Butterfly.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Ji-hoon_(actor,_born_1981)</link></item></channel></rss>