<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Joshua Prager (writer)</title><description>Joshua Harris Prager (born 1971) is an American journalist and author.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joshua_Prager_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Priest (writer)</title><description>Priest (born 13 June 1988) is a pseudonymous Chinese author whose works are published online. She has been actively writing since 2007 and has received several awards for her writing. She is signed by the web-based publisher Jinjiang Literature City. She is considered to be among the top five Chinese writers catering to women's interests. She is known for writing various genres of danmei, as well as novels featuring female protagonists. Her works have been adapted into manhua, donghua, and Chinese dramas. Many of her novels have been translated into Korean, Thai, Vietnamese, Traditional Chinese, and Japanese versions. The dramas Guardian, Legend of Fei, Word of Honor, and Justice in the Dark are  based on Priest's novels.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priest_(writer)</link></item><item><title>James Thomson (poet, born 1834)</title><description>James Thomson (23 November 1834 – 3 June 1882) — pen name Bysshe Vanolis — was a Scottish journalist, poet, and translator. He is remembered for The City of Dreadful Night (1874; 1880), a poetic allegory of urban suffering and despair. His pen name derives from the names of the poets Shelley and Novalis; both strong influences on him as a writer. Thomson's essays were written mainly for National Reformer, Secular Review, and Cope's Tobacco Plant. His longer poems include "The Doom of a City" (1854) in four parts, "Vane's Story" (1865), and the Orientalist ballad "Weddah and Om-El-Bonain". He admired and translated the works of the Italian poet Giacomo Leopardi and Heinrich Heine. In the title of his biography of Thomson, Bertram Dobell dubbed him "the Laureate of Pessimism".

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Thomson_(poet,_born_1834)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Edward Thomas (poet)</title><description>Philip Edward Thomas (3 March 1878 – 9 April 1917) was a British writer of poetry and prose. He is sometimes considered a war poet, although few of his poems deal directly with his war experiences.  He only started writing poetry at the age of 36, but by that time he had already been a prolific critic, biographer, nature writer and travel writer for two decades. In 1915, he enlisted in the British Army to fight in the First World War and was killed in action during the Battle of Arras in 1917, soon after he arrived in France.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Thomas_(poet)</link></item><item><title>David Lowery (director)</title><description>David Lowery (born December 26, 1980) is an American filmmaker.
His original work Ain't Them Bodies Saints (2013), starring Rooney Mara and Casey Affleck, was nominated for the Grand Jury Prize at the 2013 Sundance Film Festival. In 2016, he directed the Disney film Pete's Dragon (2016), a live-action film which he had co-written. It was a new work loosely based on the same original story as the Disney 1977 musical of the same name. In 2017, he directed the drama film A Ghost Story and in 2018, he directed The Old Man &amp; the Gun. In 2021, he directed the fantasy epic The Green Knight.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Lowery_(director)</link></item><item><title>Jake Scott (director)</title><description>Jason "Jake" Scott (born August 1965) is a British film director who works primarily in the field of music videos and commercials. His father is film director Sir Ridley Scott.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jake_Scott_(director)</link></item><item><title>Brad Armstrong (director)</title><description>Brad Armstrong (born Rod Hopkins; September 23, 1965) is a Canadian pornographic actor, director, producer and screenwriter. He is currently under contract with Wicked Pictures. He has been known as one of the most popular leading men in the sex industry, as well as "The King of Porn" and "The Spielberg of Skin Directors".
Among the films he has directed is Octomom Home Alone (2012).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brad_Armstrong_(director)</link></item><item><title>Hari (director)</title><description>Harikrishnan is an Indian film director and screenwriter best known for his action and masala films in Tamil cinema. He made his directorial debut with Thamizh (2002). He later directed films such as Saamy (2003), Kovil (2004), Ayya (2005), Thaamirabharani (2007), Vel (2007) and the Singam film series (2010-2017). He mostly directed Coimbatore, Dindigul, Tenkasi and Thoothukudi-Tirunelveli district based movies.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hari_(director)</link></item><item><title>Roger Clark (actor, born 1978)</title><description>Roger Clark (born July 14, 1978) is an Irish-American actor and voice actor. He is best known for portraying Arthur Morgan through performance capture in the 2018 video game Red Dead Redemption 2, a role which garnered him critical acclaim and numerous accolades.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Clark_(actor,_born_1978)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor known for his role as Benedict in the Netflix period drama Bridgerton (2020–) and has also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016). He was nominated for a Laurence Olivier Award in 2024 for his supporting role in the play A Little Life.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Adam Scott (actor)</title><description>Adam Paul Scott (born April 3, 1973) is an American actor and comedian. He is best known for his role as Ben Wyatt in the NBC sitcom Parks and Recreation, for which he was twice nominated for the Critics' Choice Television Award for Best Actor in a Comedy Series. He has also appeared as Derek Huff in the film Step Brothers, Johnny Meyer in The Aviator, Henry Pollard in the Starz sitcom Party Down, Ed Mackenzie in the HBO series Big Little Lies, and Trevor in the NBC series The Good Place. In 2022, he began starring in the Apple TV+ psychological drama series Severance, for which he received numerous award nominations, including for the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Lead Actor in a Drama Series, as well as best actor nominations from the Screen Actors Guild, Golden Globes, Critics' Choice, and more.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adam_Scott_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Meteor Man (1993), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. Townsend is also known for his role as Donald "Duck" Matthews in his 1991 film The Five Heartbeats. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Srikanth (actor, born 1968)</title><description>Meka Srikanth (born 23 March 1968) is an Indian actor who is known for works predominantly in Telugu cinema. He has appeared in more than 120 films. The actor has received one state Nandi Award, and one Filmfare Award South. He has starred in films like Swarabhishekam, which won the National Film Award for Best Feature Film in Telugu for 2004. Srikanth's another film Virodhi premiered at the Indian panorama section, at the 2011 International Film Festival of India. Sri Rama Rajyam also had a special screening at International Film Festival of India on 28 November 2011. He has also appeared in some other language films including  Kannada, Malayalam and Tamil films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Srikanth_(actor,_born_1968)</link></item><item><title>Graham Phillips (actor)</title><description>Graham David Phillips (born April 14, 1993) is an American actor,  singer, writer and director. Beginning his acting career at the age of nine, Phillips is known for a variety of television, film, and stage roles; as Zach Florrick on the CBS series The Good Wife, Ben Tennyson in the film Ben 10: Race Against Time, and Evan Goldman in the Broadway musical 13, as well as a leading role in the independent film Staten Island Summer. He has also appeared in films such as Blockers and XOXO and in the recurring television roles of Nick St. Clair in Riverdale and Nate in Atypical. He made his feature film directorial debut in 2019 with The Bygone.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graham_Phillips_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>