<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Chris Kelly (writer)</title><description>Christopher Kelly (born September 7, 1983) is an American screenwriter and director known for his work on Saturday Night Live (SNL), and writing and directing the autobiographical film Other People that premiered at the 2016 Sundance Film Festival. He has received five Emmy Award nominations for his work on SNL.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Kelly_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Danny White (athletic director)</title><description>Daniel J. White (born October 28, 1979) is an American university sports administrator. He is the athletic director for the Tennessee Volunteers. White held the same position at the University at Buffalo from 2012 to 2015 and the University of Central Florida from 2015 to 2021.  Prior to his tenure at Buffalo, he was the senior associate athletic director for Ole Miss.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danny_White_(athletic_director)</link></item><item><title>John Boles (actor)</title><description>John Boles (October 28, 1895 – February 27, 1969) was an American singer and actor best known for playing Victor Moritz in the 1931 film Frankenstein.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Boles_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jeff Stewart (actor)</title><description>Jeffrey Stewart (born 28 October 1955) is a British actor. He is best known for playing PC Reg Hollis on the ITV drama series The Bill from 1984 to 2008.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Stewart_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>