<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Jason Moss (writer)</title><description>Jason Michael Moss (February 3, 1975 – June 6, 2006) was an American attorney who specialized in criminal defense. He was best known as the author of The Last Victim: A True-Life Journey into the Mind of the Serial Killer (1999), a memoir about his exploration of the minds of incarcerated serial killers, which started as a research project in college. He corresponded and conducted personal interviews with several notorious killers.
Struggling with depression, Moss died by suicide in 2006. His book was adapted and produced as a film, Dear Mr. Gacy, released in 2010.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jason_Moss_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Nikolai Ivanov (writer)</title><description>Nikolai Fyodorovich Ivanov (Russian: Николай Фёдорович Иванов; born June 8, 1956, in Strachovo, Bryansk Oblast, USSR) is a Russian writer and publicist, and chairman of the Board of the Union of Writers of Russia from February 15, 2018, to February 27, 2025.
He is the author of over 30 books of prose and drama. As a war journalist and writer, he has travelled over the years to Chechnya, Tskhinvali, Crimea, Donbass, and Syria. He is formerly the editor-in-chief of the magazine "Soviet Warrior" and the newspaper "Tax Police". He is a retired colonel in the Russian tax police, a military journalist, and a paratrooper officer. He is a member of the public organization "Bryansk Community" in Moscow. He is subject to sanctions by all EU countries for spreading Russian propaganda and disinformation about the Russian invasion of Ukraine.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikolai_Ivanov_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times, the title of poet laureate may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Vijay (actor)</title><description>Joseph Vijay Chandrasekhar (born 22 June 1974), known professionally as Vijay, is an Indian actor and politician who works in Tamil cinema. In a career spanning over three decades, he acted in 69 films and is amongst the highest paid actors in India. He is one of the most commercially successful actors in the industry with multiple films amongst the highest-grossing Tamil films of all time. He has won several awards as an actor. Referred to as "Thalapathy" (transl. Commander), he has a significant fan following.
Born in Madras in 1974 to film director S. A. Chandrasekhar, Vijay made his debut as a child actor in the Tamil film Vetri (1984). After playing as a child actor in few of the films directed by his father, he played his first lead role in the film Naalaiya Theerpu (1992) at the age of 18. He continued doing lead roles for the next few years and notable films amongst them included Poove Unakkaga (1996), Love Today (1997), Kadhalukku Mariyadhai (1997), Thullatha Manamum Thullum (1999), and Kushi (2000). In 1998, he was awarded Kalaimaamani by the Government of Tamil Nadu for his role in Kadhalukku Mariyadhai.
In 2004, he starred in the blockbuster action-masala film Ghilli and with subsequent success of Thirupaachi (2005) and Pokkiri (2007), he established himself as one of the leading and commercially successful actors in Tamil cinema. Following a period of moderate success, Vijay acted in several critically and commercially successful films starting from the early 2010s including Thuppakki (2012), Kaththi (2014), Mersal (2017), Sarkar (2018), Master (2021), Beast (2022), Leo (2023), and The Greatest of All Time (2024).
In February 2024, Vijay announced his retirement from films and his entry into politics with the launch of his political outfit, known as Tamilaga Vettri Kazhagam.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vijay_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>