<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Varun Grover (writer)</title><description>Varun Grover (born 26 January 1980) is an Indian lyricist, writer, stand-up comedian and filmmaker. He won the award for Best Lyricist at the 63rd National Film Awards in 2015. He co-created the political satire group Aisi Taisi Democracy, and his debut film, All India Rank, closed the 52nd Rotterdam International Film Festival, in 2023. Grover also performs stand-up comedy, writes poetry and acts.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Varun_Grover_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Charles Wright (poet)</title><description>Charles Wright (born August 25, 1935) is an American poet. He shared the National Book Award in 1983 for Country Music: Selected Early Poems and won the Pulitzer Prize in 1998 for Black Zodiac. From 2014 to 2015, he served as the 20th Poet Laureate of the United States.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Wright_(poet)</link></item><item><title>James Beattie (poet)</title><description>James Beattie (; 25 October 1735 – 18 August 1803) was a Scottish poet, moralist, and philosopher.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Beattie_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Siddique (director)</title><description>Siddique Ismail (25 March 1955  – 8 August 2023) was an Indian film director, producer, screenwriter and actor who predominantly worked in Malayalam cinema. He made his directorial debut with the Malayalam film Ramji Rao Speaking (1989). His screenwriting debut came with the Malayalam film Pappan Priyappetta Pappan (1986). His final film was Big Brother (2020).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Siddique_(director)</link></item><item><title>Academy Award for Best Director</title><description>The Academy Award for Best Director (officially known as the Academy Award of Merit for Directing) is an award presented annually by the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences (AMPAS). It is given in honor of a film director who has exhibited outstanding directing while working in the film industry.
The 1st Academy Awards ceremony was held in 1929 with the award being split into "Dramatic" and "Comedy" categories; Frank Borzage and Lewis Milestone won for 7th Heaven and Two Arabian Knights, respectively. However, these categories were merged for all subsequent ceremonies. Nominees are determined by single transferable vote within the directors branch of AMPAS; winners are selected by a plurality vote from the entire eligible voting members of the academy.
For the first eleven years of the Academy Awards, directors were allowed to be nominated for multiple films in the same year. However, after the nomination of Michael Curtiz for two films, Angels with Dirty Faces and Four Daughters, at the 11th Academy Awards, the rules were revised so that an individual could only be nominated for one film at each ceremony. That rule has since been amended, although the only director who has received multiple nominations in the same year was Steven Soderbergh for Erin Brockovich and Traffic in 2000, winning the award for the latter.
The Academy Awards for Best Director and Best Picture have been very closely linked throughout their history. Of the 91 films that won Best Picture and were also nominated for Best Director, 70 won the award. The award has been criticised in recent years for failing to recognise female directors. Of the 257 individual directors nominated in the history of the award, only 9 have been women; and only 3 of the 76 winners have been women.
Since its inception, the award has been given to 74 different directors or directing teams. As of the 97th Academy Awards ceremony, American filmmaker Sean Baker is the most recent winner in this category for his work on Anora.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Academy_Award_for_Best_Director</link></item><item><title>Robert Walker (actor, born 1940)</title><description>Robert Hudson Walker Jr. (April 15, 1940 – December 5, 2019) was an American actor who appeared in films including Easy Rider (1969) and was a familiar presence on television in the 1960s and early 1970s.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Walker_(actor,_born_1940)</link></item><item><title>Damon Evans (actor)</title><description>Damon Evans (born November 24, 1949) is an American actor best known as the second of two actors who portrayed Lionel Jefferson on the CBS sitcom The Jeffersons. He also portrayed the young Alex Haley (ages 17–25) in the ABC television miniseries Roots: The Next Generations.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Damon_Evans_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Charlie Hall (actor, born 1997)</title><description>Charlie Hall (born May 30, 1997) is an American television and film actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hall_(actor,_born_1997)</link></item></channel></rss>