<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, England, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>Jeeva (director)</title><description>Jeeva (21 September 1963 – 26 June 2007) was an Indian filmmaker, cinematographer and film director in Tamil, Hindi and Malayalam-language cinema. He was an established cinematographer in the late 90s and early 2000s.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeeva_(director)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Michael Potts (actor)</title><description>Michael Potts (born September 21, 1962) is an American actor. He has appeared on stage, on television and in motion pictures.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Potts_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jack Ryder (actor)</title><description>Jack Siegfried Ryder (born 21 September 1981) is an English actor, best known for playing Jamie Mitchell in the BBC One soap opera EastEnders from 1998 to 2002.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Ryder_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Hoffman (actor)</title><description>Robert James Hoffman III (born September 21, 1985) is an American actor, producer, dancer, and choreographer.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Hoffman_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Scott Evans (actor)</title><description>Scott Andrew Evans (born September 21, 1983) is an American actor. He is known for playing the role of police officer Oliver Fish on the ABC daytime soap opera One Life to Live, the recurring role of Oliver on the series Grace and Frankie, and one of the Kens in Barbie. He is the younger brother of actor Chris Evans.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Evans_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Sam Richardson (actor)</title><description>Sam Richardson (born January 12, 1984) is an American actor and comedian. He is best known for playing Richard Splett in the HBO political comedy series Veep (2012–19), co-creating and co-starring in the Comedy Central comedy series Detroiters (2017–18) alongside Tim Robinson, and for playing various characters in the Netflix sketch show I Think You Should Leave with Tim Robinson (2019–2023), Aniq Adjaye in the Apple TV+ series The Afterparty (2022–23), and Norville Rogers in the Max series Velma (2023–24). In 2022 and 2023, he was nominated for the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Guest Actor in a Comedy Series for his performance as Edwin Akufo in Ted Lasso, winning the 2023 award in this category.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sam_Richardson_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>