<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Peter James (writer)</title><description>Peter J. James (born 22 August 1948) is a British writer of crime. He was born in Brighton, the son of Cornelia James, the former glovemaker to Queen Elizabeth II.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_James_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Tom Kristensen (poet)</title><description>Tom Kristensen ((1893-08-04)4 August 1893 – (1974-06-02)2 June 1974), was a Danish poet, novelist, literary critic and journalist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Kristensen_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Max Winkler (director)</title><description>Max Daniel Winkler (born August 18, 1983) is an American director and screenwriter. His credits include directing the film Ceremony (2010), starring Michael Angarano and Uma Thurman. The film was Winkler's feature film directorial debut.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Winkler_(director)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Wilson (actor)</title><description>Andrew Cunningham Wilson (born August 22, 1964) is an American actor and director. He is the older brother of actors Owen Wilson and Luke Wilson.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Wilson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kishore (actor, born 1974)</title><description>Kishore Kumar G (born 14 August 1974), known mononymously as Kishore, is an Indian actor who appears in Kannada, Tamil and Telugu films alongside few Malayalam, and Hindi Films

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kishore_(actor,_born_1974)</link></item><item><title>Tim Williams (actor)</title><description>Timothy Leigh Williams (born August 16, 1966) is an American actor who is best known for his appearances in advertisements for the hotel website Trivago and his roles on German television and in German film, including the German series Gute Zeiten, schlechte Zeiten in the 2010s.  He also played in the movies Valkyrie (2008), Ninja Assassin (2009) and Labyrinth of Lies (2014) and performed a music album, Magnolia City, around 2018.
Williams went to Robert E. Lee High School in Houston, Texas, and graduated in 1985. He went on to study at the Lee Strasberg Theatre and Film Institute</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tim_Williams_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jordan Wall (actor, born 1981)</title><description>Jordan Wall (born August 1, 1981) is a former American actor. He is best known for his role as Joe Talbot in the children's public television show Wishbone (1995-1998). He is not the real-life son of actress Mary Chris Wall, who played Joe's mother, Ellen Talbot, on Wishbone, but the son of Graydon and Diane Wall.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jordan_Wall_(actor,_born_1981)</link></item><item><title>Brandon Adams (actor)</title><description>Brandon Quintin Adams (born August 22, 1979) is an American actor, known for having played Jesse Hall in the first two Mighty Ducks movies and Kenny DeNunez in The Sandlot. He also played Jimmy Bean in the 1989 film Polly.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brandon_Adams_(actor)</link></item><item><title>John Sharp (actor)</title><description>John Herbert Sharp ((1920-08-05)5 August 1920 – (1992-11-26)26 November 1992) was a British actor who made numerous appearances on television during a career spanning 42 years.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Sharp_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Christopher Jones (actor, born 1941)</title><description>William Frank Jones (August 18, 1941 – January 31, 2014), known professionally as Christopher Jones, was an American actor. He was best known for his starring roles in the films Wild in the Streets (1968) and Ryan's Daughter (1970), and for playing the title role in the 1960s television series The Legend of Jesse James.
According to The New York Times, Jones' "talent and star power drew comparisons with James Dean," and he "seemed poised for stardom before abruptly abandoning his movie career in the late 1960s."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Jones_(actor,_born_1941)</link></item></channel></rss>