<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Richard Olney (food writer)</title><description>Richard Olney (April 12, 1927 – August 3, 1999) was an American painter, cook, food writer, editor, and memoirist, best known for his books of French country cooking.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Olney_(food_writer)</link></item><item><title>Alfred Meyer (writer)</title><description>Alfred Meyer (4 August 1882 – 9 January 1956) was a German writer. His work was part of the literature event in the art competition at the 1932 Summer Olympics.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alfred_Meyer_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Tom Kristensen (poet)</title><description>Tom Kristensen ((1893-08-04)4 August 1893 – (1974-06-02)2 June 1974), was a Danish poet, novelist, literary critic and journalist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Kristensen_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Lorenzo Thomas (poet)</title><description>Lorenzo Thomas (August 31, 1944 – July 4, 2005) was an American poet and critic. He was born in the Republic of Panama and grew up in New York City, where his family immigrated in 1948. In 1973, Thomas moved to Houston, Texas. Thomas had a two decade career as a professor at the University of Houston–Downtown.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lorenzo_Thomas_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Edwin Morgan (poet)</title><description>Edwin George Morgan  (27 April 1920 – 19 August 2010) was a Scottish poet and translator associated with the Scottish Renaissance. He is widely recognised as one of the foremost Scottish poets of the 20th century. In 1999, Morgan was made the first Glasgow Poet Laureate. In 2004, he was named as the first Makar or National Poet for Scotland.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edwin_Morgan_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Max Winkler (director)</title><description>Max Daniel Winkler (born August 18, 1983) is an American director and screenwriter. His credits include directing the film Ceremony (2010), starring Michael Angarano and Uma Thurman. The film was Winkler's feature film directorial debut.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Winkler_(director)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Walter Massey (actor)</title><description>Walter Edward Hart Massey (August 19, 1928 – August 4, 2014) was a Canadian actor, best known for voicing Principal Herbert Haney on the animated series Arthur and The Doctor in the English version of The Mysterious Cities of Gold. He was based in Montreal, Quebec.
He played Dr. Donald Stewart on the 1990s version of Lassie, and had numerous roles on stage, and in films and television, for more than six decades. Massey was the cousin of actor Raymond Massey and was a founding member of Canadian Actors' Equity.
Walter Massey's father, Denton, was an engineer and Ontario politician.
Massey died in Montreal, Quebec on August 4, 2014, fifteen days before his 86th birthday.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Massey_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>