<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>The Poets</title><description>The Tortured Poets Department is the eleventh studio album by the American singer-songwriter Taylor Swift. It was released on April 19, 2024, by Republic Records. Swift developed the album amidst the Eras Tour in 2023, with the resultant, heightened media scrutiny on her life inspiring the record. Two hours after the album's release, it was expanded into a double album subtitled The Anthology, containing a second volume of songs. 
Swift wrote and produced the album with Jack Antonoff and Aaron Dessner. Self-described as her "lifeline" album, its introspective songs depict emotional tumult, with self-awareness, mourning, anger, humor, and delusion as dominant themes. Musically, the album is a minimalist synth-pop, chamber pop, and folk-pop effort with country and rock stylings. The composition is largely mid-tempo, driven by a mix of synthesizers and drum machines with piano and guitar. The visual aesthetics were influenced by dark academia.
The album broke numerous commercial records, including the highest single-day and single-week streams for an album on Spotify. It topped the charts across Europe, Asia-Pacific, and the Americas. In the United States, The Tortured Poets Department became Swift's record-extending seventh album to open with over a million units, spent a career-best 17 weeks atop the Billboard 200, and was certified six-times platinum by the Recording Industry Association of America. Its songs made Swift the only artist to monopolize the Billboard Hot 100's top 14 spots, led by "Fortnight" featuring Post Malone. It became the world's best-selling album of 2024.
Critical reception to The Tortured Poets Department was polarized upon release; critics praised Swift's cathartic songwriting for emotional resonance and wit, but some found the album lengthy and lacking profundity. Subsequent assessments appreciated the album's musical and lyrical nuances more, while disputing initial critiques for allegedly focusing on Swift's public image rather than artistic merit. Its accolades include an ARIA Music Award, a Premios Odeón, a Japan Gold Disc Award, and five nominations at the 67th Annual Grammy Awards, including Album of the Year. Swift included songs from the album in a revamped Eras Tour set from May to December 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tortured_Poets_Department</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Kunal Kapoor (actor, born 1959)</title><description>Kunal Kapoor (born 26 June 1959) is an Indian actor, film producer, director and advertisement maker. Elder son of actors Shashi Kapoor and Jennifer Kendal, he made his debut with the 1972 English-language film Siddhartha, later acted in Shyam Benegal's Junoon and in his first mainstream Bollywood film, Ahista Ahista, opposite Padmini Kolhapure as well as  Vijeta. He also acted in the art films Utsav (1984) and Trikal (1985).
In 1987, he stopped acting after Trikal to set up his own company, Adfilm-Valas, to produce and direct television commercials. Adfilm Valas has also line-produced for many international feature films and ad films shot in India. Notably, the credit sequence of the film City of Joy, and the French films Le Cactus  (2005) and Fire in Paradise.
In 2015, he returned to films after 30 years, appearing in Singh is Bling as Amy Jackson's character's father.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kunal_Kapoor_(actor,_born_1959)</link></item><item><title>Vijay (actor)</title><description>Joseph Vijay Chandrasekhar (born 22 June 1974), known professionally as Vijay, is an Indian actor and playback singer who works in Tamil cinema. In a career spanning over three decades, Vijay has acted in 68 films and is one of the most commercially successful actors in Tamil cinema with multiple films amongst the highest-grossing Tamil films of all time and is amongst the highest paid actors in India. He has won several awards as an actor. Referred to as "Thalapathy" (transl. Commander), Vijay has a significant fan following.
Born in Madras to director S. A. Chandrasekhar, Vijay made his debut as a child actor in the Tamil film Vetri (1984). After a few roles as a child actor in his father’s films, he played his first lead role in the film Naalaiya Theerpu (1992) at the age of 18. Vijay continued doing lead roles for the next few years with notable films amongst them included Poove Unakkaga (1996), Love Today (1997), Kadhalukku Mariyadhai (1997), Thullatha Manamum Thullum (1999) and Kushi (2000). In 1998, he was awarded Kalaimaamani by the Government of Tamil Nadu for his role in Kadhalukku Mariyadhai.
In 2004, he starred in the blockbuster action-masala film Ghilli and with subsequent success of Thirupaachi (2005) and Pokkiri (2007) later, he established himself as one of the leading and commercially successful actors in Tamil cinema. Following a period of moderate success, Vijay acted in several critically and commercially successful films starting from early 2010s including Thuppakki (2012), Kaththi (2014), Mersal (2017), Sarkar (2018), Master (2021), Beast (2022), Leo (2023) and his penultimate film The Greatest of All Time (2024).
In February 2024, Vijay announced his retirement from films and his forthcoming entry into politics with the launch of his political party, known as Tamilaga Vettri Kazhagam.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vijay_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>