<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>The Last Poets</title><description>The Last Poets is a poetry collective and musical group that arose in the late 1960s as part of the African-American civil rights movement and black nationalism. The name was inspired by revolutionary South African poet Keorapetse Kgositsile who believed he was in the last era of poetry before guns took over.
The group originally comprised Jalaluddin Mansur Nuriddin, Umar Bin Hassan and Abiodun Oyewole. Lineup changes and departures led to offshoots, including The Original Last Poets composed of Oyewole, Gylan Kain and David Nelson. Critic Jason Ankeny wrote: "With their politically charged raps, taut rhythms, and dedication to raising African-American consciousness, the Last Poets almost single-handedly laid the groundwork for the emergence of hip-hop." The British music magazine NME stated, "Serious spokesmen like Gil Scott-Heron, The Last Poets, and later Gary Byrd, paved the way for the many socially committed Black [emcees] a decade later."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Poets</link></item><item><title>List of directorial debuts</title><description>This is a list of notable directors and their first commercial cinematic films, listed chronologically by release date. 
Many of the listed filmmakers, including Orson Welles, directed earlier works that were not commercially released, such as film-school projects, movies that failed to find distribution, or others that were never intended for release. Beginning in the 1940s and 1950s, some directors learned their trade in the medium of television, including Robert Altman, Sidney Lumet, and Alfonso Cuarón. Later directors such as Alan Parker and Ridley Scott did their first professional work in commercial television advertising, which became more cinematic in the 1960s and 1970s. The success of MTV and the popularity of music videos from the early 1980s drew first work from David Fincher, Jonathan Glazer, Michel Gondry, and Spike Jonze.
♦ Indicates a director who created other earlier works for television.
# Indicates a director whose earlier work is uncredited.

† Indicates a director whose earlier work has not been released in cinemas—for example, film school productions, short films, or music videos.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_directorial_debuts</link></item><item><title>Charlie Hall (actor, born 1997)</title><description>Charlie Hall (born May 30, 1997) is an American television and film actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hall_(actor,_born_1997)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Vishal Singh (actor, born 1985)</title><description>Vishal Singh (born 7 September 1985) is an Indian model and actor who works in Hindi television. He is best known for his roles of Ayaan Nanda in Kuchh Is Tara and Jigar Chirag Modi in Saath Nibhaana Saathiya.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vishal_Singh_(actor,_born_1985)</link></item><item><title>Jeremy Jordan (actor, born 1984)</title><description>Jeremy Michael Jordan (born November 20, 1984) is an American actor. He has performed on Broadway, in television and film, in concert, as well as in other theatrical productions.
Jeremy Jordan, affectionately nicknamed "Jerjor" by his fans, made his Broadway debut in 2009 as part of Rock of Ages. Subsequently, he went to star in the original Broadway musicals Bonnie &amp; Clyde (2011) as Clyde Barrow and Newsies (2012) as Jack Kelly, for which he was nominated for a Tony Award and a Grammy Award. He has also appeared in a Broadway revival of the musical West Side Story as Tony, the musical adaptation of Waitress on Broadway as Dr. Jim Pomatter, and the play American Son on Broadway. In 2021 and 2023, he starred as Seymour Krelborn in the Off-Broadway revival of Little Shop of Horrors. He made his return to Broadway in the title role of the original cast of The Great Gatsby in 2024 and played the titular character in the Broadway premiere of Floyd Collins in 2025, which earned him his second Tony Award nomination.
On screen, he starred opposite Anna Kendrick in the 2014 musical film The Last Five Years and as Jimmy Collins in the NBC series Smash (2013). From 2015 to 2021, he played Winslow "Winn" Schott Jr. on the CBS/CW DC Comics-based superhero drama series Supergirl. From 2017 to 2020, he voiced Varian in the Disney Channel animated series Rapunzel's Tangled Adventure. Since 2024, he has voiced Lucifer Morningstar in the adult animated musical series Hazbin Hotel, for which he received an Annie Award nomination for Best Voice Acting - TV/Media.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeremy_Jordan_(actor,_born_1984)</link></item><item><title>Anthony Carrigan (actor)</title><description>Anthony Carrigan (born January 2, 1983) is an American actor. He is best known for playing Chechen mobster NoHo Hank in the HBO series Barry (2018–2023), for which he was nominated three times for the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Supporting Actor in a Comedy Series in 2019, 2022, and 2023. 
He is also known for playing Tyler Davies in the television series The Forgotten (2009–2010), Victor Zsasz in the Fox series Gotham (2014–2019), the robot Dennis Caleb McCoy in Bill &amp; Ted Face the Music (2020), and Metamorpho in Superman (2025). In 2025, he also starred in the second season of the Peacock series Twisted Metal.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Carrigan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kim Ji-hoon (actor, born 1981)</title><description>Kim Ji-hoon (Korean: 김지훈; born May 9, 1981) is a South Korean actor. He is best known for his romantic comedies on television such as The Golden Age of Daughters-in-Law (2007), Love Marriage (also known as Matchmaker's Lover, 2008), Stars Falling from the Sky (also known as Wish Upon a Star, 2010), and My Cute Guys (2013). In 2010, he also appeared in the film Natalie, and cable mystery series Joseon X-Files. In 2023 he appeared in Lee Chung-hyun's Netflix film Ballerina.  He was cast as a hired assassin in Amazon Prime Video 2025 TV series Butterfly.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Ji-hoon_(actor,_born_1981)</link></item></channel></rss>