<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Kate Atkinson (writer)</title><description>Kate Atkinson  (born 20 December 1951) is an English writer of novels, plays and short stories.  She has written historical novels, detective novels and family novels, incorporating postmodern and magical realist elements into the plots. Her debut, Behind the Scenes at the Museum, won the Whitbread Book Award, the precursor to the Costa Book Award, in 1995. The novels Life After Life and A God in Ruins won the Costa Book Award for novel in 2013 and 2015. She is also known for the Jackson Brodie series of detective novels, which has been adapted into the BBC One series, Case Histories.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kate_Atkinson_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Young (poet, born 1885)</title><description>Andrew John Young (29 April 1885 – 25 November 1971) was a Scottish poet and clergyman, although recognition of his poetry was slow to develop.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Young_(poet,_born_1885)</link></item><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.
In 2009, the founders of the Royal Ballet were commemorated in a memorial floor stone and on 25 September 2010, the writer Elizabeth Gaskell was celebrated with the dedication of a panel in the memorial window. On 6 December 2011, former Poet Laureate Ted Hughes was commemorated with a floor stone. On 22 November 2013, the fiftieth anniversary of his death, writer C. S. Lewis was commemorated with a memorial floor stone. The poet Philip Larkin was commemorated with a floor stone dedicated on 2 December 2016.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing and most popular film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>David Lowery (director)</title><description>David Lowery (born December 26, 1980) is an American filmmaker.
His original work Ain't Them Bodies Saints (2013), starring Rooney Mara and Casey Affleck, was nominated for the Grand Jury Prize at the 2013 Sundance Film Festival. In 2016, he directed the Disney film Pete's Dragon (2016), a live-action film which he had co-written. It was a new work loosely based on the same original story as the Disney 1977 musical of the same name. In 2017, he directed the drama film A Ghost Story and in 2018, he directed The Old Man &amp; the Gun. In 2021, he directed the fantasy epic The Green Knight.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Lowery_(director)</link></item><item><title>Rob Morgan (actor)</title><description>Rob Morgan (born 
February 24, 1973) is an American actor. He is known for his role as Turk Barrett in all six of Marvel's Netflix television series (2015–2018), Hap Jackson in Mudbound (2017), Officer Powell in Stranger Things (2016–present), and Teddy Oglethorpe in Don't Look Up (2021).
In 2020, Morgan was ranked #20 on the New York Times list "The 25 Greatest Actors of the 21st Century".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rob_Morgan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Matt Clark (actor)</title><description>Matt Clark (born November 25, 1936) is an American actor. He is best known for his roles in Western films.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matt_Clark_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Matthew Beard (English actor)</title><description>Matthew Beard (born 25 March 1989) is an English actor and model.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matthew_Beard_(English_actor)</link></item><item><title>Will Kemp (actor, born 1977)</title><description>William Kemp (born 29 June 1977) is an English actor and dancer. His stage names are Will and James Dean of Ballet.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Will_Kemp_(actor,_born_1977)</link></item></channel></rss>