<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Elizabeth Arnold (poet)</title><description>Elizabeth Arnold (1958 – February 24, 2024) was an American poet.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Arnold_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Rob Morgan (actor)</title><description>Rob Morgan (born February 24, 1973) is an American actor. He is known for his role as Turk Barrett in all six of Marvel's Netflix television series (2015–2019), Hap Jackson in Mudbound (2017), Officer Powell in Stranger Things (2016–2025), and Teddy Oglethorpe in Don't Look Up (2021).
In 2020, Morgan was ranked #20 on the New York Times list "The 25 Greatest Actors of the 21st Century".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rob_Morgan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Cooper (actor)</title><description>Andrew Cooper (born 24 February 1981) is an English actor and model.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Cooper_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Feroz Khan (actor)</title><description>Feroz Khan (born Zulfiqar Ali Shah Khan; 25 September 1935 — 27 April 2009) was an Indian actor, film editor, producer and director best known for his work in Indian cinema. He appeared in over 60 films throughout his career and became one of Bollywood's popular style icons. Feroz Khan rose to prominence with Phani Majumdar's drama film Oonche Log (1965), and starred in successful Hindi films, such as Arzoo (1965), Aag (1967), Safar (1970), Mela (1971), Apradh (1972), Geeta Mera Naam (1974), Khotte Sikkay (1974), Kaala Sona (1975), Dharmatma (1975), Nagin (1976), Shankar Shambhu (1976) and Qurbani (1980). The 2007 superhit Welcome (2007), was his final film.
He won the Filmfare Best Supporting Actor Award for Aadmi Aur Insaan (1969) in 1970, and was honored with the Filmfare Lifetime Achievement Award in 2000. He has been called "Clint Eastwood of India".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feroz_Khan_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>