<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Mustafa the Poet</title><description>Mustafa Ahmed (born 28 July 1996), known as Mustafa, formerly known as Mustafa the Poet, is a Sudanese-Canadian poet, singer, songwriter, and filmmaker from Toronto. He released his debut studio album, When Smoke Rises, in May 2021.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mustafa_the_Poet</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing and most popular film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Srikanth (actor, born 1968)</title><description>Meka Srikanth (born 23 March 1968) is an Indian actor who is known for works predominantly in Telugu cinema. He has appeared in more than 120 films. The actor has received one state Nandi Award, and one Filmfare Award South. He has starred in films like Swarabhishekam, which won the National Film Award for Best Feature Film in Telugu for 2004. Srikanth's another film Virodhi premiered at the Indian panorama section, at the 2011 International Film Festival of India. Sri Rama Rajyam also had a special screening at International Film Festival of India on 28 November 2011. He has also appeared in some other language films including  Kannada, Malayalam and Tamil films.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Srikanth_(actor,_born_1968)</link></item><item><title>Variety Studio: Actors on Actors</title><description>Variety Studio: Actors on Actors, also referred to as Actors on Actors, is an American entertainment talk show television series co-produced by PBS SoCal and Variety Media. It premiered on PBS SoCal on December 21, 2014.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variety_Studio:_Actors_on_Actors</link></item><item><title>Joseph Quinn (actor)</title><description>Joseph Quinn (born 26 January 1994) is an English actor. He is best known for his role as Eddie Munson in the fourth season of the Netflix series Stranger Things (2022). His previous appearances were in the BBC One series Dickensian (2016), Howards End (2017), and Les Misérables (2018), and the Sky Atlantic series Catherine the Great (2019). He has since starred in the horror film A Quiet Place: Day One and portrayed Geta in the historical action film Gladiator II (both 2024).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joseph_Quinn_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ben Foster (actor)</title><description>Benjamin A. Foster (born October 29, 1980) is an American actor. His films include The Punisher (2004), X-Men: The Last Stand and Alpha Dog (both 2006), 30 Days of Night (2007), The Messenger and Pandorum (both 2009), The Mechanic (2011), Contraband (2012), Kill Your Darlings and Lone Survivor (both 2013), The Program (2015), Warcraft (2016), and Leave No Trace (2018). He has won an Independent Spirit Award for portraying Tanner Howard in Hell or High Water (2016). He also had a recurring role as Russell Corwin in the television series Six Feet Under (2003–2005).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Foster_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>