<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1957) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>The Last Poets</title><description>The Last Poets is a poetry collective and musical group that arose in the late 1960s as part of the African-American civil rights movement and black nationalism. The name was inspired by revolutionary South African poet Keorapetse Kgositsile who believed he was in the last era of poetry before guns took over.
The group originally comprised Jalaluddin Mansur Nuriddin, Umar Bin Hassan and Abiodun Oyewole. Lineup changes and departures led to offshoots, including The Original Last Poets composed of Oyewole, Gylan Kain and David Nelson. Critic Jason Ankeny wrote: "With their politically charged raps, taut rhythms, and dedication to raising African-American consciousness, the Last Poets almost single-handedly laid the groundwork for the emergence of hip-hop." The British music magazine NME stated, "Serious spokesmen like Gil Scott-Heron, The Last Poets, and later Gary Byrd, paved the way for the many socially committed Black [emcees] a decade later."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Poets</link></item><item><title>Kevin Allen (director)</title><description>Kevin Edward Allen (born 15 September 1959) is an English actor, director, producer and writer. Allen came to prominence with the 1991 BBC film On the March with Bobby's Army, and for writing and directing his debut feature film, Twin Town, in 1997. He directed and co-wrote the film adaptation of Dylan Thomas' "Under Milk Wood", submitted for Best Foreign Language Film at the 2015 Oscars ceremony but not nominated, the Hollywood feature films, The Big Tease and Agent Cody Banks 2: Destination London, and the first series of ITV's Benidorm, along with numerous other films and documentaries.
Allen assisted Swansea City Council's 2017 bid to become the 2021 UK City of Culture. He is often cited as a figure in the Cool Cymru era.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kevin_Allen_(director)</link></item><item><title>Kim Ji-hoon (actor, born 1981)</title><description>Kim Ji-hoon (Korean: 김지훈; born May 9, 1981) is a South Korean actor. He is best known for his romantic comedies on television such as The Golden Age of Daughters-in-Law (2007), Love Marriage (also known as Matchmaker's Lover, 2008), Stars Falling from the Sky (also known as Wish Upon a Star, 2010), and My Cute Guys (2012). In 2010, he also appeared in the film Natalie, and cable mystery series Joseon X-Files. In 2023 he appeared in Lee Chung-hyun's Netflix film Ballerina.  He was cast as a hired assassin in Amazon Prime Video 2025 TV series Butterfly.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Ji-hoon_(actor,_born_1981)</link></item><item><title>Brian Hall (actor)</title><description>Brian Charles Hall (20 November 1937 – 16 September 1997) was a British actor. He is best remembered for his role as hotel chef Terry Hughes in the British sitcom Fawlty Towers.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Hall_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Anthony Carrigan (actor)</title><description>Anthony Carrigan (born January 2, 1983) is an American actor. He is best known for playing Chechen mobster NoHo Hank in the HBO series Barry (2018–2023), for which he was nominated three times for the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Supporting Actor in a Comedy Series in 2019, 2022, and 2023. 
He is also known for playing Tyler Davies in the television series The Forgotten (2009–2010), Victor Zsasz in the FOX series Gotham (2014–2019), the robot Dennis Caleb McCoy in Bill &amp; Ted Face the Music (2020), and Metamorpho in Superman (2025). In 2025, he also starred in the second season of the Peacock series Twisted Metal.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Carrigan_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>