<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Chen Chen (poet)</title><description>Chen Chen (Chinese: 陳琛; pinyin: Chén Chēn, born March 9, 1989) is an American poet. His book, When I Grow Up I Want to Be a List of Further Possibilities, was longlisted for the 2017 National Book Award for Poetry. Chen serves on the poetry faculty for the low-residency MFA programs at New England College and Stonecoast. He served as Jacob Ziskind Poet-in-Residence at Brandeis University from 2018 to 2022.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chen_Chen_(poet)</link></item><item><title>The Last Poets</title><description>The Last Poets is a poetry collective and musical group that arose in the late 1960s as part of the African-American civil rights movement and black nationalism. The name was inspired by revolutionary South African poet Keorapetse Kgositsile who believed he was in the last era of poetry before guns took over.
The group originally comprised Jalaluddin Mansur Nuriddin, Umar Bin Hassan and Abiodun Oyewole. Lineup changes and departures led to offshoots, including The Original Last Poets composed of Oyewole, Gylan Kain and David Nelson. Critic Jason Ankeny wrote: "With their politically charged raps, taut rhythms, and dedication to raising African-American consciousness, the Last Poets almost single-handedly laid the groundwork for the emergence of hip-hop." The British music magazine NME stated, "Serious spokesmen like Gil Scott-Heron, The Last Poets, and later Gary Byrd, paved the way for the many socially committed Black [emcees] a decade later." 

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Poets</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times, the title of poet laureate may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Director of United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement</title><description>The director of United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) is a civilian official in the United States Department of Homeland Security. During July 2010 the position's title was changed from Assistant Secretary for U.S. Immigrations and Customs Enforcement.
The director is in charge of the day-to-day operations of more than 7000 Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) agents that are the primary investigative component of ICE and 6000 enforcement and removal operations officers (ERO). ICE is an agency with the United States Department of Homeland Security and the director reports to the United States secretary of homeland security and the United States deputy secretary of homeland security.
This position requires Senate confirmation, though an acting director is permitted, and the agency has not had a confirmed director since January 20, 2017. The current acting director is Todd Lyons.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Director_of_United_States_Immigration_and_Customs_Enforcement</link></item><item><title>Roger Clark (actor, born 1978)</title><description>Roger Clark (born July 14, 1978) is an Irish-American actor and voice actor. He is best known for portraying Arthur Morgan through performance capture in the 2018 video game Red Dead Redemption 2, a role which garnered him critical acclaim and numerous accolades.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Clark_(actor,_born_1978)</link></item><item><title>Ibrahim Ali Khan (actor)</title><description>Ibrahim Ali Khan Pataudi (born 5 March 2001) is an Indian actor who works in Hindi films. Born to actors Saif Ali Khan and Amrita Singh, he had his first acting role as a child as the younger version of his father's character in Tashan (2008). As an adult, he had his first leading role in the poorly-received Netflix romantic comedy film Nadaaniyan (2025).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ibrahim_Ali_Khan_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>