<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.
In 2009, the founders of the Royal Ballet were commemorated in a memorial floor stone and on 25 September 2010, the writer Elizabeth Gaskell was celebrated with the dedication of a panel in the memorial window. On 6 December 2011, former Poet Laureate Ted Hughes was commemorated with a floor stone. On 22 November 2013, the fiftieth anniversary of his death, writer C. S. Lewis was commemorated with a memorial floor stone. The poet Philip Larkin was commemorated with a floor stone dedicated on 2 December 2016.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Atlee (director)</title><description>Arun Kumar (born 21 September 1986), known professionally as Atlee, is an Indian film director, screenwriter and film producer best known for his work in Tamil cinema and Hindi Cinema. He initially worked as an assistant director under S. Shankar in the films Enthiran (2010) and Nanban (2012). He made his directorial debut with the film Raja Rani (2013), produced by Fox Star Studios, for which he was awarded Best Debut Director by the Vijay Award and the Tamil Nadu State award for best dialogue writer.
He directed the films Theri (2016), Mersal (2017) and Bigil (2019), all featuring Vijay, all of which became commercially successful at the box office and won several accolades. He then directed the Hindi-language Jawan (2023) starring Shah Rukh Khan, which emerged as his highest-grossing release.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atlee_(director)</link></item><item><title>Suraj (director)</title><description>Suraj (born Suresh; December 31, 1977) is an Indian film director who works primarily in Tamil films. He is best known for directing action and masala films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suraj_(director)</link></item><item><title>Lee Jong-won (actor, born 1994)</title><description>Lee Jong-won (Korean: 이종원; born December 31, 1994) is a South Korean actor and model. He is known for his roles in dramas such as My Unfamiliar Family, XX, The Spies Who Loved Me, Brewing Love

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Jong-won_(actor,_born_1994)</link></item><item><title>Christopher Jones (actor, born 1941)</title><description>William Frank Jones (August 18, 1941 – January 31, 2014), known professionally as Christopher Jones, was an American actor. He was best known for his starring roles in the films Wild in the Streets (1968) and Ryan's Daughter (1970), and for playing the title role in the 1960s television series The Legend of Jesse James.
According to The New York Times, Jones' "talent and star power drew comparisons with James Dean," and he "seemed poised for stardom before abruptly abandoning his movie career in the late 1960s."

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Jones_(actor,_born_1941)</link></item><item><title>Vinod Raj (Tamil actor)</title><description>John Albert Victor (1937 – 31 December 2017), known professionally as Vinod Raj, was an Indian actor, who worked on Tamil films. He is the father of Indian actor Vikram.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vinod_Raj_(Tamil_actor)</link></item><item><title>Peter Williams (actor, born 1957)</title><description>Peter Williams (born 31 December 1957) is a Jamaican-born Canadian actor. He is known for playing Apophis, a primary antagonist on Stargate SG-1.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Williams_(actor,_born_1957)</link></item></channel></rss>