<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Writers Guild of America</title><description>The Writers Guild of America (WGA) is the generic term of two different American labor unions, representing writers in film, television, radio, and online media:  

The Writers Guild of America, East (WGAE), headquartered in New York City and affiliated with the AFL-CIO national trade union center
The Writers Guild of America West (WGAW), headquartered in Los Angeles but unaffiliated.
Although both organizations operate independently, they perform some common activities, including negotiating contracts and launching strike actions in unison.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writers_Guild_of_America</link></item><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Christopher Jones (actor, born 1941)</title><description>William Frank Jones (August 18, 1941 – January 31, 2014), known professionally as Christopher Jones, was an American actor. He was best known for his starring roles in the films Wild in the Streets (1968) and Ryan's Daughter (1970), and for playing the title role in the 1960s television series The Legend of Jesse James.
According to The New York Times, Jones' "talent and star power drew comparisons with James Dean," and he "seemed poised for stardom before abruptly abandoning his movie career in the late 1960s."

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Jones_(actor,_born_1941)</link></item><item><title>Benjamin Walker (actor)</title><description>Benjamin Walker Scodelario-Davis (né Davis; born June 21, 1982) is an American actor and stand-up comedian. He starred as Andrew Jackson in the musical Bloody Bloody Andrew Jackson, which premiered on Broadway in 2010. He has appeared in a number of Broadway productions, notably as Patrick Bateman in the 2016 musical adaptation of the novel American Psycho and as Chris Keller in the 2019 revival of All My Sons, for which he was nominated for a Tony Award for Best Featured Actor. On screen, he is known for his title role in the 2012 film Abraham Lincoln: Vampire Hunter, as well as his appearances in the films Kinsey, Flags of Our Fathers, and In the Heart of the Sea. In 2019, he starred as Erik Gelden in the third and final season of the Netflix series Jessica Jones. He plays the High King of the Ñoldorin Elves Ereinion Gil-galad in the Amazon Prime Video series The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benjamin_Walker_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>