<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Mark Bailey (writer)</title><description>Mark Daniel Bailey (born November 21, 1968) is an American writer, best known for his documentary films, including Last Days in Vietnam (2014), Downfall: The Case Against Boeing (2022), and The Volcano: Rescue from Whakaari (2022). Bailey, together with his wife, filmmaker Rory Kennedy, own Moxie Films, a documentary film production company. The company produces documentaries "for broadcast and cable networks, including Netflix, HBO, PBS, A&amp;E, National Geographic, Showtime, Discovery Channel, MTV, TLC, Lifetime Television, the Oxygen Network, and the Sundance Channel as well as for educational foundations and philanthropic organizations."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Bailey_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Writers Guild of America</title><description>The Writers Guild of America (WGA) is the generic term of two different American labor unions, representing writers in film, television, radio, and online media:  

The Writers Guild of America, East (WGAE), headquartered in New York City and affiliated with the AFL-CIO national trade union center
The Writers Guild of America West (WGAW), headquartered in Los Angeles but unaffiliated.
Although both organizations operate independently, they perform some common activities, including negotiating contracts and launching strike actions in unison.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Writers_Guild_of_America</link></item><item><title>Steve Adams (writer)</title><description>Steve Adams (born Steven Saint Lawrence Adams, February 8, 1947) is an American author and screenwriter who also uses the penname Waldo Mellon. He wrote Envy (2004), starring Ben Stiller and Jack Black. Adams conceived the idea with long-time friend Larry David. They met while both were comedy writers for Fridays, a Saturday Night Live inspired show in the early 1980s.   Adams also wrote Waiting for Forever (2010) starring Tom Sturridge, Rachel Bilson, and Blythe Danner as well as No Stranger Than Love (2015) starring Alison Brie and Colin Hanks.
In 2014, Adams wrote and self-published his first book What's What And What To Do About It under the pen name Waldo Mellon. The book was published in March 1, 2022 by Seven Stories Press.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Adams_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.
Over a dozen national governments continue the poet laureate tradition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Charles Wright (poet)</title><description>Charles Wright (born August 25, 1935) is an American poet. He shared the National Book Award in 1983 for Country Music: Selected Early Poems and won the Pulitzer Prize in 1998 for Black Zodiac. From 2014 to 2015, he served as the 20th Poet Laureate of the United States.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Wright_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became the independent production company A24's highest-grossing release, and won the duo many awards, including  Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Jake Scott (director)</title><description>Jason "Jake" Scott (born August 1965) is a British film director who works primarily in the field of music videos and commercials. His father is film director Sir Ridley Scott.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jake_Scott_(director)</link></item><item><title>Michael Cassidy (actor)</title><description>Michael Cassidy (born March 20, 1983) is an American film and television actor. He is best known for his role as Zach Stevens on The O.C. and as Tyler Mitchell on the TBS comedy Men at Work. He portrayed Jonathan Walsh on comedy People of Earth from the show's start in 2016 until its 2018 cancellation.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Cassidy_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Meteor Man (1993), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. Townsend is also known for his role as Donald "Duck" Matthews in his 1991 film The Five Heartbeats. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ben Foster (actor)</title><description>Benjamin A. Foster (born October 29, 1980) is an American actor. His films include The Punisher (2004), X-Men: The Last Stand and Alpha Dog (both 2006), 30 Days of Night (2007), The Messenger and Pandorum (both 2009), The Mechanic (2011), Contraband (2012), Kill Your Darlings and Lone Survivor (both 2013), The Program (2015), and Leave No Trace (2018). He has won an Independent Spirit Award for portraying Tanner Howard in Hell or High Water (2016). He also had a recurring role as Russell Corwin in the television series Six Feet Under (2003–2005).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Foster_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>