<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Chris McKenna (writer)</title><description>Chris McKenna is an American television writer, film producer, screenwriter, and television producer. He has written for American Dad!, Community, and The Mindy Project, and part of the first Marvel Cinematic Universe Spider-Man trilogy (2017–2021).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_McKenna_(writer)</link></item><item><title>The Last Poets</title><description>The Last Poets is a poetry collective and musical group that arose in the late 1960s as part of the African-American civil rights movement and black nationalism. The name was inspired by revolutionary South African poet Keorapetse Kgositsile who believed he was in the last era of poetry before guns took over.
The group originally comprised Jalaluddin Mansur Nuriddin, Umar Bin Hassan and Abiodun Oyewole. Lineup changes and departures led to offshoots, including The Original Last Poets composed of Oyewole, Gylan Kain and David Nelson. Critic Jason Ankeny wrote: "With their politically charged raps, taut rhythms, and dedication to raising African-American consciousness, the Last Poets almost single-handedly laid the groundwork for the emergence of hip-hop." The British music magazine NME stated, "Serious spokesmen like Gil Scott-Heron, The Last Poets, and later Gary Byrd, paved the way for the many socially committed Black [emcees] a decade later." 

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Poets</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>David Lowery (director)</title><description>David Lowery (born December 26, 1980) is an American filmmaker. His film Ain't Them Bodies Saints (2013), starring Rooney Mara and Casey Affleck, was nominated for the Grand Jury Prize at the 2013 Sundance Film Festival. In 2016, he directed the Disney film Pete's Dragon (2016), a live-action film which he had co-written. It was a new work loosely based on the same original story as the Disney 1977 musical of the same name. In 2017, he directed the drama film A Ghost Story and in 2018, he directed The Old Man &amp; the Gun. In 2021, he directed the fantasy epic The Green Knight.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Lowery_(director)</link></item><item><title>John Madden (director)</title><description>John Philip Madden (born 8 April 1949) is an English director of stage, film, television, and radio. He is known for directing the period romantic comedy film Shakespeare in Love (1998), which won the Academy Award for Best Picture at the 71st Academy Awards ceremony.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Madden_(director)</link></item><item><title>George Webb (actor)</title><description>George Augustus Webb (6 March 1912 – 30 December 1998) was a British actor, best known for television, including his role as "Daddy", the father of snooty Hyacinth Bucket in the sitcom Keeping Up Appearances.
The son of Henry Augustus Webb (1880–1926) and Gertrude (née Bolingbroke), Webb was born at 41 St Luke's Road, Paddington, London. He had two younger siblings, Denis Alfred (1913–1918), who was killed by a military vehicle at age five while picking flowers for his mother; and Joan (1915–1989), who died by suicide after years of ill health.
From his father's earlier marriage, Webb was the half brother of the actors Rita and Harry Webb. Webb died on 30 December 1998, aged 86, from natural causes.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Webb_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Rudy Reyes (actor)</title><description>Rudy Reyes (born December 3, 1971) is an American martial arts instructor, actor, and former active duty United States Marine.  He is best known for portraying himself in the HBO TV miniseries Generation Kill.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rudy_Reyes_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Nicholas Smith (actor)</title><description>Nicholas John Smith (5 March 1934 – 6 December 2015) was an English comedian and actor. He appeared in the BBC sitcom Are You Being Served?, playing Mr (Cuthbert) Rumbold, the manager of the fictional Grace Brothers department store.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nicholas_Smith_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ibrahim Ali Khan (actor)</title><description>Ibrahim Ali Khan Pataudi (born 5 March 2001) is an Indian actor who works in Hindi films. Born to actors Saif Ali Khan and Amrita Singh, he had his first acting role as a child as the younger version of his father's character in Tashan (2008). As an adult, he had his first leading role in the poorly-received Netflix romantic comedy film Nadaaniyan (2025).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ibrahim_Ali_Khan_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>