<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>John Roberts (actor)</title><description>John Roberts (born November 10, 1971) is an American actor, comedian, and writer who voices Linda Belcher on the animated sitcom Bob's Burgers.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Roberts_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, England, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>Michael Cimino (actor)</title><description>Michael Cimino ( sih-MEE-noh; born November 10, 1999) is an American actor. He is known for his roles as Victor Salazar in the Hulu television series Love, Victor, Bob Palmeri in Annabelle Comes Home and Ethan Morales on Never Have I Ever. Since 2022, he has voiced Kevin Grant-Gomez from the Disney Channel animated series Hamster &amp; Gretel. On November 10, 2022, he released his debut EP, I'm Somewhere Out There.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Cimino_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Paul Richards (actor)</title><description>Paul Richards (born Paul Richard Levitt; November 10, 1924 – December 10, 1974) was an American actor who appeared in films and on television in the 1950s, 1960s, and 1970s.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Richards_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Feroz Khan (actor)</title><description>Feroz Khan (born Zulfiqar Ali Shah Khan; 25 September 1935 — 27 April 2009) was an Indian actor, film editor, producer and director best known for his work in Indian cinema. He appeared in over 60 films throughout his career and became one of Bollywood's popular style icons. Feroz Khan rose to prominence with Phani Majumdar's drama film Oonche Log (1965), and starred in successful Hindi films, such as Arzoo (1965), Aag (1967), Safar (1970), Mela (1971), Apradh (1972), Geeta Mera Naam (1974), Khotte Sikkay (1974), Kaala Sona (1975), Dharmatma (1975), Nagin (1976), Shankar Shambhu (1976) and Qurbani (1980). The 2007 superhit Welcome (2007), was his final film.
He won the Filmfare Best Supporting Actor Award for Aadmi Aur Insaan (1969) in 1970, and was honored with the Filmfare Lifetime Achievement Award in 2000. He has been called "Clint Eastwood of India".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feroz_Khan_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>