<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Peter May (writer)</title><description>Peter May (born 20 December 1951) is a Scottish television screenwriter, novelist, and crime writer. He is the recipient of writing awards in Europe and America. The Blackhouse won the U.S. Barry Award for Crime Novel of the Year and the national literature award in France, the Cezam Prix Litteraire. The Lewis Man won the French daily newspaper Le Télégramme's 10,000-euro Grand Prix des Lecteurs. In 2014, Entry Island won both the Deanston's Scottish Crime Novel of the Year and the UK's ITV Crime Thriller Book Club Best Read of the Year Award. May's books have sold more than two million copies in the UK and several million internationally.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_May_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Mustafa the Poet</title><description>Mustafa Ahmed (born 28 July 1996), known as Mustafa, formerly known as Mustafa the Poet, is a Canadian poet, singer, songwriter, and filmmaker from Toronto. He released his debut EP, When Smoke Rises, in May 2021. His debut album, Dunya, was released on September 27, 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mustafa_the_Poet</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Scott McKay (actor)</title><description>Scott McKay (born Carl Gose, May 28, 1915 – March 16, 1987) was an American film, television and theatre actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_McKay_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ali Raza (actor)</title><description>Muhammad Ali Raza (born 28 August 1998) is a Pakistani actor and model who works in Urdu television. Raza is known for portraying Daniyal in Muhabbat Gumshuda Meri  (2023) and Shahnawaz Shah in Iqtidar (2024-2025). 
In January 2025, Dawn included him in the list of the 7 "Pakistani actors who stood out in 2024".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ali_Raza_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kim Ji-hoon (actor, born 1981)</title><description>Kim Ji-hoon (Korean: 김지훈; born May 9, 1981) is a South Korean actor. He is best known for his romantic comedies on television such as The Golden Age of Daughters-in-Law (2007), Love Marriage (also known as Matchmaker's Lover, 2008), Stars Falling from the Sky (also known as Wish Upon a Star, 2010), and My Cute Guys (2012). In 2010, he also appeared in the film Natalie, and cable mystery series Unsolved. In 2023 he appeared in Lee Chung-hyun's Netflix film Ballerina.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Ji-hoon_(actor,_born_1981)</link></item></channel></rss>