<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.
In 2009, the founders of the Royal Ballet were commemorated in a memorial floor stone and on 25 September 2010, the writer Elizabeth Gaskell was celebrated with the dedication of a panel in the memorial window. On 6 December 2011, former Poet Laureate Ted Hughes was commemorated with a floor stone. On 22 November 2013, the fiftieth anniversary of his death, writer C. S. Lewis was commemorated with a memorial floor stone. The poet Philip Larkin was commemorated with a floor stone dedicated on 2 December 2016.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>The Poets</title><description>The Poets were a Scottish blues, freakbeat and psychedelic pop band, who were managed and produced by Andrew Loog Oldham. Some of their singles were released on his label, Immediate Records. Their cover version of "Baby Don't You Do It" was produced by Immediate in-house record producer, Paul Raven (Gary Glitter).
Musically, the band's style contained elements of both the hard R&amp;B of the early Small Faces (both bands would cover "Baby Don't You Do It") and the Action along with the more melodic sounds of the Kinks,  the Searchers and the later period Small Faces. Visually, they sported an Edwardian look similar to the early Kinks with matching velvet jackets, ruffled shirts, tight pants, Beatle Boots and shag haircuts. Within the West of Scotland however, their look was interpreted as based on the poet Robert Burns' appearance in paintings of his time.
Their 1964 single "Now We're Thru'" was a No. 31 hit on the UK Singles Chart. However, later singles were not chart successes outside Scotland, and no full album was completed.
Some of their singles appear on various compilation albums, including the Nuggets II box set on Rhino Records (one song) and The Immediate Records Story (four songs) on Charly Records. One of their tracks, "That's the Way It's Got to Be" was on the soundtrack for the films Factory Girl and Frankenstein Meets the Space Monster.
Their former member, Hume Paton, born Hume Michael Paton, 6 October 1945, Bellshill, Glasgow, died on 30 April 2011, from a heart attack in Saint Georges, Grenada, West Indies at the age of 65. Another former member, Alan Weir, born 12 September 1943, Gartcosh, Lanarkshire died on 9 June 2010 from cancer in Cambridge, at the age of 67.  Another former member John Dawson, born 6 May 1944, Glasgow, Strathclyde died on 6 January 2002 in Glasgow of cancer, at the age of 57.
In 2011, the Poets reformed with original members George Gallacher and Fraser Watson, and on 2 December that year, played at the Eyes Wide Open club's 7th anniversary celebration. This was meant to be a one off, but just before the gig, the Poets' name appeared in the line-up to Le Beat Bespoke 8, listing them as playing on 8 April 2012.
Lead singer George Gallacher born 21 October 1943, Royston, Glasgow, died of a heart attack on 25 August 2012, at Glasgow Royal Infirmary at age 68 while travelling home after watching his beloved Partick Thistle win 3–0 against Dumbarton.
The remaining founder member, Tony Myles, now lives in Spain where he hosts various radio programs and continues to write music at his home studio in the Costa Blanca.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Poets</link></item><item><title>James Thomson (poet, born 1834)</title><description>James Thomson (23 November 1834 – 3 June 1882) — pen name Bysshe Vanolis — was a Scottish journalist, poet, and translator. He is remembered for The City of Dreadful Night (1874; 1880), a poetic allegory of urban suffering and despair. His pen name derives from the names of the poets Shelley and Novalis; both strong influences on him as a writer. Thomson's essays were written mainly for National Reformer, Secular Review, and Cope's Tobacco Plant. His longer poems include "The Doom of a City" (1854) in four parts, "Vane's Story" (1865), and the Orientalist ballad "Weddah and Om-El-Bonain". He admired and translated the works of the Italian poet Giacomo Leopardi and Heinrich Heine. In the title of his biography of Thomson, Bertram Dobell dubbed him "the Laureate of Pessimism".

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Thomson_(poet,_born_1834)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>David Lowery (director)</title><description>David Lowery (born December 26, 1980) is an American filmmaker.
His original work Ain't Them Bodies Saints (2013), starring Rooney Mara and Casey Affleck, was nominated for the Grand Jury Prize at the 2013 Sundance Film Festival. In 2016, he directed the Disney film Pete's Dragon (2016), a live-action film which he had co-written. It was a new work loosely based on the same original story as the Disney 1977 musical of the same name. In 2017, he directed the drama film A Ghost Story and in 2018, he directed The Old Man &amp; the Gun. In 2021, he directed the fantasy epic The Green Knight.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Lowery_(director)</link></item><item><title>Srikanth (actor, born 1968)</title><description>Meka Srikanth (born 23 March 1968) is an Indian actor who is known for works predominantly in Telugu cinema. He has appeared in more than 120 films. The actor has received one state Nandi Award, and one Filmfare Award South. He has starred in films like Swarabhishekam, which won the National Film Award for Best Feature Film in Telugu for 2004. Srikanth's another film Virodhi premiered at the Indian panorama section, at the 2011 International Film Festival of India. Sri Rama Rajyam also had a special screening at International Film Festival of India on 28 November 2011. He has also appeared in some other language films including  Kannada, Malayalam and Tamil films.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Srikanth_(actor,_born_1968)</link></item><item><title>Variety Studio: Actors on Actors</title><description>Variety Studio: Actors on Actors, also referred to as Actors on Actors, is an American entertainment talk show television series co-produced by PBS SoCal and Variety Media. It premiered on PBS SoCal on December 21, 2014.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variety_Studio:_Actors_on_Actors</link></item></channel></rss>