<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1958) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Priest (writer)</title><description>Priest (pseudonym) (born 13 June 1988) is a Chinese author whose works are published online. She has been actively writing since 2007 and has received several awards for her writing. She is signed by the web-based publisher Jinjiang Literature City. She is considered to be among the top five Chinese writers catering to women's interests. She is known for writing various genres of danmei, as well as novels featuring female protagonists. Her works have been adapted into manhua, donghua, and Chinese dramas. Many of her novels have been translated into Korean, Thai, Vietnamese, Traditional Chinese, and Japanese versions. The dramas Guardian, Legend of Fei, Word of Honor, and Justice in the Dark are  based on Priest's novels.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priest_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.
Over a dozen national governments continue the poet laureate tradition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Atlee (director)</title><description>Arun Kumar (born 21 September 1986), known professionally as Atlee, is an Indian film director, screenwriter and film producer best known for his work in Tamil cinema. He initially worked as an assistant director under S. Shankar in the films Enthiran (2010) and Nanban (2012). He made his directorial debut with the film Raja Rani (2013), produced by Fox Star Studios, for which he was awarded Best Debut Director by the Vijay Award and the Tamil Nadu State award for best dialogue writer. He is one of the highest-paid directors in India.
He directed the films Theri (2016), Mersal (2017) and Bigil (2019), all featuring Vijay, all of which became commercially successful at the box office and won several accolades. He then directed the Hindi-language Jawan (2023) starring Shah Rukh Khan, which emerged as his highest-grossing release. Atlee ranks among the most successful directors in Indian Cinema.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atlee_(director)</link></item><item><title>Ian Chen (actor)</title><description>Ian Chen (born September 7, 2006) is an American actor. He is known for his roles as Evan Huang in the ABC sitcom Fresh Off the Boat (2015–2020) and Eugene Choi in the DC Extended Universe films Shazam! (2019) and Shazam! Fury of the Gods (2023).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Chen_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Meteor Man (1993), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. Townsend is also known for his role as Donald "Duck" Matthews in his 1991 film The Five Heartbeats. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Vishal Singh (actor, born 1985)</title><description>Vishal Singh (born 7 September 1985) is an Indian model and actor who works in Hindi television. He is best known for his roles of Ayaan Nanda in Kuchh Is Tara and Jigar Chirag Modi in Saath Nibhaana Saathiya.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vishal_Singh_(actor,_born_1985)</link></item></channel></rss>