<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Anurag Singh (director)</title><description>Anurag Singh Thind (born 17 November 1975), is an Indian film director, screenwriter and producer who mainly works in Punjabi and Hindi cinema. Known for his comedy and period war genre films, he is widely recognized as one of the most influential film directors of Punjabi cinema.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anurag_Singh_(director)</link></item><item><title>Damon Evans (actor)</title><description>Damon Evans (born November 24, 1949) is an American actor best known as the second of two actors who portrayed Lionel Jefferson on the CBS sitcom The Jeffersons. He also portrayed the young Alex Haley (ages 17–25) in the ABC television miniseries Roots: The Next Generations.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Damon_Evans_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Brown (American actor)</title><description>Robert Brown (born Robin Adair MacKenzie Brown; November 17, 1926 – September 19, 2022) was an American film and television actor who was mostly active in the 1960s and 1970s.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Brown_(American_actor)</link></item><item><title>Justin Cooper (actor)</title><description>Justin Cooper (born November 17, 1988) is an American former child actor. He has starred in the film Liar Liar and in the sitcom Brother's Keeper. He serves as an executive producer of The Ben Maller Show on Fox Sports Radio.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Justin_Cooper_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kim Ji-hoon (actor, born 1981)</title><description>Kim Ji-hoon (Korean: 김지훈; born May 9, 1981) is a South Korean actor. He is best known for his romantic comedies on television such as The Golden Age of Daughters-in-Law (2007), Love Marriage (also known as Matchmaker's Lover, 2008), Stars Falling from the Sky (also known as Wish Upon a Star, 2010), and My Cute Guys (2013). In 2010, he also appeared in the film Natalie, and cable mystery series Joseon X-Files. In 2023 he appeared in Lee Chung-hyun's Netflix film Ballerina.  He was cast as a hired assassin in Amazon Prime Video 2025 TV series Butterfly.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Ji-hoon_(actor,_born_1981)</link></item><item><title>Feroz Khan (actor)</title><description>Feroz Khan (born Zulfiqar Ali Shah Khan; 25 September 1935 — 27 April 2009) was an Indian actor, film editor, producer and director best known for his work in Indian cinema. He appeared in over 60 films throughout his career and became one of Bollywood's popular style icons. Feroz Khan rose to prominence with Phani Majumdar's drama film Oonche Log (1965), and starred in successful Hindi films, such as Arzoo (1965), Aag (1967), Safar (1970), Mela (1971), Apradh (1972), Geeta Mera Naam (1974), Khotte Sikkay (1974), Kaala Sona (1975), Dharmatma (1975), Nagin (1976), Shankar Shambhu (1976) and Qurbani (1980). The 2007 superhit Welcome (2007), was his final film.
He won the Filmfare Best Supporting Actor Award for Aadmi Aur Insaan (1969) in 1970, and was honored with the Filmfare Lifetime Achievement Award in 2000. He has been called "Clint Eastwood of India".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feroz_Khan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Carl Lee (actor)</title><description>Carl Lee (born Carl Vincent Canegata; November 22, 1926 – April 17, 1986) was an American actor. His father was actor/professional boxer Canada Lee.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Lee_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>