<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Ousha the Poet</title><description>Ousha bint Khalifa Al Suwaidi (Arabic: عوشه بنت خليفة السويدي) also known as Fatat Al-Arab (Girl of the Arabs), Ousha Al Sha'er (Ousha the Poet) (1 January 1920 – 27 July 2018) was an Emirati poet. She is regarded as among the finest Arabic Nabati poets.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ousha_the_Poet</link></item><item><title>Christopher Jones (actor, born 1941)</title><description>William Franklin Jones (August 18, 1941 – January 31, 2014), known professionally as Christopher Jones, was an American actor. He was best known for his starring roles in the films Wild in the Streets (1968) and Ryan's Daughter (1970), and for playing the title role in the 1960s television series The Legend of Jesse James.
According to The New York Times, Jones' "talent and star power drew comparisons with James Dean," and he "seemed poised for stardom before abruptly abandoning his movie career in the late 1960s."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Jones_(actor,_born_1941)</link></item><item><title>Samuel Arnold (actor)</title><description>Samuel Arnold (born 11 July 1991) is a French actor. He gained popularity for starring in the Netflix TV series Emily in Paris.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samuel_Arnold_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ben Foster (actor)</title><description>Benjamin A. Foster (born October 29, 1980) is an American actor. His films include The Punisher (2004), X-Men: The Last Stand and Alpha Dog (both 2006), 30 Days of Night (2007), The Messenger and Pandorum (both 2009), The Mechanic (2011), Contraband (2012), Kill Your Darlings and Lone Survivor (both 2013), The Program (2015), Warcraft (2016), and Leave No Trace (2018). He has won an Independent Spirit Award for portraying Tanner Howard in Hell or High Water (2016). He also had a recurring role as Russell Corwin in Six Feet Under (2003–05).
Foster has often received praise from critics for his "intense" and "unhinged" performances in numerous films. Film critic Matt Zoller Seitz described Foster in 2016 as "one of those actors who makes even a bad film worth seeing. Sometimes he suggests the film you'd rather be watching."

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Foster_(actor)</link></item><item><title>William D. Gordon (actor)</title><description>William Douglas Gordon (January 4, 1918 – August 12, 1991) was an American actor, writer, director, story editor, and producer. Although he is best known for his writing credits, he acted occasionally on numerous TV series.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_D._Gordon_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>