<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Hernan Diaz (writer)</title><description>Hernan Diaz (born 1973) is an Argentine-American writer. His 2017 novel In the Distance was a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction, as well as the PEN/Faulkner Award for Fiction. He also received a Whiting Award. For his second novel Trust, he was awarded the 2023 Pulitzer Prize for Fiction.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hernan_Diaz_(writer)</link></item><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Priest (writer)</title><description>Priest (pseudonym) (born 13 June 1988) is a Chinese author whose works are published online. She has been actively writing since 2007 and has received several awards for her writing. She is signed by the web-based publisher Jinjiang Literature City. She is considered to be among the top five Chinese writers catering to women's interests. She is known for writing various genres of danmei, as well as novels featuring female protagonists. Her works have been adapted into manhua, donghua, and Chinese dramas. Many of her novels have been translated into Korean, Thai, Vietnamese, Traditional Chinese, and Japanese versions. The dramas Guardian, Legend of Fei, Word of Honor, and Justice in the Dark are  based on Priest's novels.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priest_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became the independent production company A24's highest-grossing release, and won the duo many awards, including  Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay. 

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Vipul Mehta (director)</title><description>Vipul Mehta (born July 8, 1975) is an Indian film director, screenwriter, and producer known for his work in Gujarati, Marathi, and Hindi cinema. Born in Mumbai,India, Mehta has made significant contributions to both regional and national film industries.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vipul_Mehta_(director)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor. He is best known for his role as Benedict, the second Bridgerton child, in the Netflix's Bridgerton. For his theatre work, he received number of accolades, including a WhatsOnStage Award and a nomination for a Laurence Olivier Award. He also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ian Chen (actor)</title><description>Ian Chen (born September 7, 2006) is an American actor. He is known for his roles as Evan Huang in the ABC sitcom Fresh Off the Boat (2015–2020) and Eugene Choi in the DC Extended Universe films Shazam! (2019) and Shazam! Fury of the Gods (2023).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Chen_(actor)</link></item><item><title>David Thornton (actor)</title><description>David Farrington Thornton (born June 12, 1953) is an American actor. He has appeared in John Q, Home Alone 3 as Earl Unger, Law &amp; Order, The Notebook, and The Other Woman, among other roles. He is the husband of singer songwriter Cyndi Lauper.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Thornton_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Freddy Rodriguez (actor)</title><description>Freddy Rodriguez (born January 17, 1975) is an American actor, known for his starring roles as Federico Diaz on Six Feet Under (2001–2005) and Benny Colon in Bull (2016–2021), as well as his recurring role as Gio on Ugly Betty (2007–2010). He also starred in the Robert Rodriguez (to whom he bears no relation) film Planet Terror (2007). In addition to an Emmy nomination for Six Feet Under, he received two SAG Awards and four Imagen Awards for his work.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freddy_Rodriguez_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Samuel Arnold (actor)</title><description>Samuel Arnold (born 11 July 1991) is a French actor. He gained popularity for starring in the Netflix TV series Emily in Paris.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samuel_Arnold_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Meteor Man (1993), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. Townsend is also known for his role as Donald "Duck" Matthews in his 1991 film The Five Heartbeats. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Anthony Edwards (actor)</title><description>Anthony Charles Edwards (born July 19, 1962) is an American actor, director, and producer. He played Dr. Mark Greene on the first eight seasons of ER, for which he received a Golden Globe Award and six Screen Actors Guild Awards, and was nominated for four consecutive Primetime Emmy Awards. He has appeared in various films and television series, including Fast Times at Ridgemont High, Top Gun, Zodiac, Gotcha!, Miracle Mile, Revenge of the Nerds, Planes, Northern Exposure, and Designated Survivor.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Edwards_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>