<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Mark Bailey (writer)</title><description>Mark Daniel Bailey (born November 21, 1968) is an American writer, best known for his documentary films, including Last Days in Vietnam (2014), Downfall: The Case Against Boeing (2022), and The Volcano: Rescue from Whakaari (2022). Bailey, together with his wife, filmmaker Rory Kennedy, own Moxie Films, a documentary film production company. The company produces documentaries "for broadcast and cable networks, including Netflix, HBO, PBS, A&amp;E, National Geographic, Showtime, Discovery Channel, MTV, TLC, Lifetime Television, the Oxygen Network, and the Sundance Channel as well as for educational foundations and philanthropic organizations."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Bailey_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Clive Bradley (screenwriter)</title><description>Clive Bradley (born 1959) is a British screenwriter who has written for film and television. After graduating from the National Film and Television School, he was one of the winners of the first Orange Prize for Screenwriting in 1999.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clive_Bradley_(screenwriter)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Meteor Man (1993), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. Townsend is also known for his role as Donald "Duck" Matthews in his 1991 film The Five Heartbeats. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>National poet</title><description>A national poet or national bard is a poet held by tradition and popular acclaim to represent the identity, beliefs and principles of a particular national culture. The national poet as culture hero is a long-standing symbol, to be distinguished from successive holders of a bureaucratically-appointed poet-laureate office. The idea and honoring of national poets emerged primarily during Romanticism, as a figure that helped consolidation of the nation states, as it provided validation of their ethno-linguistic groups.
Most national poets are historic figures, though a few contemporary writers working in relatively new or revived national literatures are also considered "national poets". Though not formally elected, national poets play a role in shaping a country's understanding of itself. Some nations may have more than one national poet; the idea of a single one is always a simplification. It has been argued that a national poet "must write poetry that closely identifies with the nation's cause – or is thought to do so", with an additional assumption being that "a national poet must write in a national language".
The following is a list of nations, with their associated national poets. It is not a list of sovereign states or countries, though many of the nations listed may also be such. The terms "nation" (as cultural concept), "country" (as geographical concept) and "state" (as political concept) are not synonyms.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_poet</link></item><item><title>Edward Thomas (poet)</title><description>Philip Edward Thomas (3 March 1878 – 9 April 1917) was a British writer of poetry and prose. He is sometimes considered a war poet, although few of his poems deal directly with his war experiences.  He only started writing poetry at the age of 36, but by that time he had already been a prolific critic, biographer, nature writer and travel writer for two decades. In 1915, he enlisted in the British Army to fight in the First World War and was killed in action during the Battle of Arras in 1917, soon after he arrived in France.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Thomas_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Jagannatha Dasa (Odia poet)</title><description>Jagannatha Dasa (c. 1490–1550), known by the honorific Atibadi, meaning "very great" (Odia: ଅତିବଡ଼ି ଜଗନ୍ନାଥ ଦାସ, romanized: Atibaḍi Jagannātha Dāsa, Odia: [ɔt̪ibɔɽi d͡ʒɔɡɔnnaːt̪ʰɔ d̪aːsɔ] ), was an Odia poet and litterateur. He was one of  the five great poets (along with Ananta Dasa, Jasobanta Dasa, Balarama Dasa and Achyutananda Dasa) in Odia literature, known as the Panchasakha ("five friends"). He wrote the Odia Bhagavata Purana  (Bhagabata).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jagannatha_Dasa_(Odia_poet)</link></item><item><title>John Patterson (director)</title><description>John Tiffin Patterson (April 4, 1940 – February 7, 2005) was a television director known for his work on drama series, who also made television films. He directed thirteen episodes of The Sopranos, including the first five season finales. Patterson was born in Buffalo, New York.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Patterson_(director)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born 4 July 1988) is an English actor. He is known for his role as Benedict in the Netflix period drama Bridgerton (2020–) and has also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016). He was nominated for a Laurence Olivier Award for his performance in the play A Little Life in 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Adam Scott (actor)</title><description>Adam Paul Scott (born April 3, 1973) is an American actor. He is best known for his role as Ben Wyatt in the NBC sitcom Parks and Recreation (2010–2015), for which he was twice nominated for a Critics' Choice Television Award, as well as for starring in the Apple TV+ thriller series Severance (since 2022), for which he was nominated for a Primetime Emmy Award and a Golden Globe Award.
Scott has also appeared in the films The Aviator (2004) and Step Brothers (2008), as well as the Starz sitcom Party Down (2009–2010; 2023), the HBO drama series Big Little Lies (2017–2019), and the NBC comedy series The Good Place (2016–2018). 

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adam_Scott_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ben Foster (actor)</title><description>Benjamin A. Foster (born October 29, 1980) is an American actor. His films include The Punisher (2004), X-Men: The Last Stand and Alpha Dog (both 2006), 30 Days of Night (2007), The Messenger and Pandorum (both 2009), The Mechanic (2011), Contraband (2012), Kill Your Darlings and Lone Survivor (both 2013), The Program (2015), Warcraft (2016), and Leave No Trace (2018). He has won an Independent Spirit Award for portraying Tanner Howard in Hell or High Water (2016). He also had a recurring role as Russell Corwin in Six Feet Under (2003–05).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Foster_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>