<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Mark Bailey (writer)</title><description>Mark Daniel Bailey (born November 21, 1968) is an American writer, best known for his documentary films, including Last Days in Vietnam (2014), Downfall: The Case Against Boeing (2022), and The Volcano: Rescue from Whakaari (2022). Bailey, together with his wife, filmmaker Rory Kennedy, own Moxie Films, a documentary film production company. The company produces documentaries "for broadcast and cable networks, including Netflix, HBO, PBS, A&amp;E, National Geographic, Showtime, Discovery Channel, MTV, TLC, Lifetime Television, the Oxygen Network, and the Sundance Channel as well as for educational foundations and philanthropic organizations."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Bailey_(writer)</link></item><item><title>The Last Poets</title><description>The Last Poets is a poetry collective and musical group that arose in the late 1960s as part of the African-American civil rights movement and black nationalism. The name was inspired by revolutionary South African poet Keorapetse Kgositsile who believed he was in the last era of poetry before guns took over.
The group originally comprised Jalaluddin Mansur Nuriddin, Umar Bin Hassan and Abiodun Oyewole. Lineup changes and departures led to offshoots, including The Original Last Poets composed of Oyewole, Gylan Kain and David Nelson. Critic Jason Ankeny wrote: "With their politically charged raps, taut rhythms, and dedication to raising African-American consciousness, the Last Poets almost single-handedly laid the groundwork for the emergence of hip-hop." The British music magazine NME stated, "Serious spokesmen like Gil Scott-Heron, The Last Poets, and later Gary Byrd, paved the way for the many socially committed Black [emcees] a decade later." 

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Poets</link></item><item><title>John Patterson (director)</title><description>John Tiffin Patterson (April 4, 1940 – February 7, 2005) was a television director known for his work on drama series, who also made television films. He directed thirteen episodes of The Sopranos, including the first five season finales. Patterson was born in Buffalo, New York.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Patterson_(director)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jason Lewis (actor)</title><description>Jason Lewis (born June 25, 1971) is an American actor and former fashion model best known as Jerry "Smith" Jerrod on Sex and the City (2003–04), Sex and the City (2008) and Sex and the City 2 (2010).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jason_Lewis_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Luke Thompson (actor)</title><description>Luke Thompson (born July 4, 1988), is an English actor. He is best known for his role as Benedict in the Netflix period drama Bridgerton (2020–present), and has also appeared in the BBC One drama In the Club (2014–2016). In 2024, he received a Laurence Olivier Award nomination for his performance in the stage adaptation of A Little Life.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Thompson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>