<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Mustafa the Poet</title><description>Mustafa Ahmed (born 28 July 1996), known mononymously as Mustafa, formerly known as Mustafa the Poet, is a Sudanese Canadian poet, singer, songwriter, and filmmaker from Toronto. He released his debut EP, When Smoke Rises, in May 2021. His debut album, Dunya, was released on September 27, 2024. It was shortlisted for the 2025 Polaris Music Prize.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mustafa_the_Poet</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>James Thomson (poet, born 1700)</title><description>James Thomson (c. 11 September 1700 – 27 August 1748) was a Scottish poet and playwright, known for his poems The Seasons and The Castle of Indolence, and for the lyrics of "Rule, Britannia!"</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Thomson_(poet,_born_1700)</link></item><item><title>Owen Cooper (actor)</title><description>Owen Patrick Cooper (born 5 December 2009) is an English actor. He gained recognition for his debut role portraying teenaged murder suspect Jamie Miller in the Netflix miniseries Adolescence (2025), winning the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Supporting Actor in a Limited or Anthology Series or Movie, making him the youngest male actor to win a Primetime Emmy Award.
He is scheduled to appear as young Heathcliff in Wuthering Heights (2026) and as Callum in the upcoming BBC series Film Club.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Owen_Cooper_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jung Joon-won (actor, born 1988)</title><description>Jung Jun Won (born January 13, 1988) is a South Korean actor. He is known for his role in the television series Resident Playbook.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jung_Joon-won_(actor,_born_1988)</link></item></channel></rss>