<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>James McBride (writer)</title><description>James McBride (born September 11, 1957) is an American writer and musician. He is the recipient of the 2013 National Book Award for fiction for his novel The Good Lord Bird.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_McBride_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, England, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>James Thomson (poet, born 1700)</title><description>James Thomson (c. 11 September 1700 – 27 August 1748) was a Scottish poet and playwright, known for his poems The Seasons and The Castle of Indolence, and for the lyrics of "Rule, Britannia!"</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Thomson_(poet,_born_1700)</link></item><item><title>Todd Williams (actor)</title><description>Todd Williams III (born September 11, 1977) is an American actor best known for his role as Officer Isaac Joiner on the crime drama television series The Chicago Code.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Todd_Williams_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Paul Douglas (actor)</title><description>Paul Douglas Fleischer (April 11, 1907 − September 11, 1959), known professionally as Paul Douglas, was an American actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Douglas_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Angus Sutherland (actor)</title><description>Angus Redford Sutherland (born September 3, 1982) is a Canadian-American producer and actor. In the early stages of his career, he was an actor before transitioning to producing.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angus_Sutherland_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>