<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1957) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>The Last Poets</title><description>The Last Poets is a poetry collective and musical group that arose in the late 1960s as part of the African-American civil rights movement and black nationalism. The name was inspired by revolutionary South African poet Keorapetse Kgositsile who believed he was in the last era of poetry before guns took over.
The group originally comprised Jalaluddin Mansur Nuriddin, Umar Bin Hassan and Abiodun Oyewole. Lineup changes and departures led to offshoots, including The Original Last Poets composed of Oyewole, Gylan Kain and David Nelson. Critic Jason Ankeny wrote: "With their politically charged raps, taut rhythms, and dedication to raising African-American consciousness, the Last Poets almost single-handedly laid the groundwork for the emergence of hip-hop." The British music magazine NME stated, "Serious spokesmen like Gil Scott-Heron, The Last Poets, and later Gary Byrd, paved the way for the many socially committed Black [emcees] a decade later."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Poets</link></item><item><title>John Sinclair (poet)</title><description>John Sinclair (October 2, 1941 – April 2, 2024) was an American poet, writer, and political activist from Flint, Michigan. Sinclair's defining style is jazz poetry, and he released most of his works in audio formats. Most of his pieces include musical accompaniment, usually by a varying group of collaborators dubbed Blues Scholars.
As an emerging young poet in the mid-1960s, Sinclair took on the role of manager for the Detroit rock band MC5. The band's politically charged music and its Yippie core audience dovetailed with Sinclair's own radical development. In 1968, while still working with the band, he conspicuously served as a founding member of the White Panther Party, a militantly anti-racist socialist group and counterpart of the Black Panther Party. Arrested for distribution of marijuana in 1969, Sinclair was given ten years in prison. The sentence was criticized by many as unduly harsh, and it galvanized a noisy protest movement led by prominent figures of the 1960s counterculture.  He was freed on March 9, 1972, by the Michigan Supreme Court when the possession of marijuana law was declared unconstitutional.
He was indicted for an alleged terrorist bombing of a covert CIA office.  That matter involved substantial litigation – his case against the government for illegal domestic surveillance was successfully pleaded to the US Supreme Court in United States v. U.S. District Court (1972).  It took the form of a Writ of Mandamus, which was won at the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit and an appeal on certiorari to the Supreme Court.  The wiretap evidence was suppressed, and the criminal case dropped. 
Sinclair eventually left the US and took up residency in Amsterdam. He continued to write and record and, from 2005, hosted a regular radio program, The John Sinclair Radio Show, as well as producing a line-up of other shows on his own radio station, Radio Free Amsterdam.
Sinclair was among the first people to purchase recreational marijuana when it became legal in Michigan on December 1, 2019.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Sinclair_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>John Clarke (actor)</title><description>John Clarke (April 14, 1931 – October 16, 2019) was an American television actor. Clarke is recognized for originating and portraying Mickey Horton on the NBC soap opera Days of Our Lives for 39 years, beginning with the debut of the program in 1965, until his retirement in 2004.
In 1959, Clarke acted with Ida Lupino in an episode of CBS's The Twilight Zone titled The Sixteen-Millimeter Shrine. In the 1961-1962 television season, he was cast in 27 episodes as Patrolman Joe Huddleston in Leslie Nielsen's ABC crime drama series, The New Breed.
His daughter is actress Melinda Clarke, who started out on Days of our Lives and later played Julie Cooper on the television series, The O.C.
Clarke died on October 16, 2019, from complications of pneumonia at the age of 88.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Clarke_(actor)</link></item><item><title>James Olson (actor)</title><description>James Olson (October 8, 1930 – April 17, 2022) was an American actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Olson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kevin Miles (American actor)</title><description>Kevin Miles (born Kevin Miles Julian Mimms, July 1990) is an American actor best known for his role as Jake, the spokesman for State Farm insurance company.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kevin_Miles_(American_actor)</link></item><item><title>William Campbell (actor)</title><description>William Campbell (October 30, 1923 – April 28, 2011) was an American actor who appeared in supporting roles in major film productions, and also starred in several low-budget B-movies and horror films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Campbell_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>