<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>David Shapiro (poet)</title><description>David Shapiro (January 2, 1947 – May 4, 2024) was an American poet, literary critic, and art historian. He wrote some twenty volumes of poetry, literary, and art criticism. He was first published at the age of thirteen, and his first book was published when he was eighteen.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Shapiro_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Hashim (poet)</title><description>Hashim Shah (Punjabi ہاشم شاہ (Shahmukhi), ਹਾਸ਼ਿਮ ਸ਼ਾਹ (Gurmukhi); b. 1735 d. 1843) was a Punjabi writer and Sufi poet, best known for his story Sassi Punnun (or Sassi Panhu). His family migrated from Holy city Madina to Punjab, India, where they began living at Jagdev Kalan, the biggest village in Ajnala tehsil, Amritsar district. Hashim Shah was born in Jagdev Kalan in 1735 or 1752 and lived in that village his entire life. He wrote three stories "Kissa Kaw" named Sassi Punnu, Sohni Mahiwal, and Shirin Farhad.
Hashim, besides following the family tradition of hikmat (physician), copunselling and Piri-Muridi, also worked as a carpenter for sustenance. He left the profession of carpentry when Maharaja Ranjit Singh and his courtiers extended their patronage to Hashim. Thereafter, he devoted his entire life to spiritual attainments and composing Sufistic (mystic) poetry.
Hashim Shah's poetry is unique in its own right. Credited as one of the best poets of his era many books have been written about him by his followers. His poetry has a certain style reverberating with description and sometimes sadness. The way he has narrated Sassi Punnu speaks for the depth in his words and the immense aptitude he had.
Sufism ran in Hashim's family. He, his father and grandfather practised piri-muridi. He took Sufism as an established belief. His Punjabi poetry reverberates with mysticism of high order and can be allegorically interpreted for Love Divine.
Hashim died in Ajnala, 1843 or 1823 and was buried in Tharpal village in Narowal District where every year Urs was held on or about 21st of Jeth (end May – early June).
In his poetic compositions his prosody is Punjabi though his vocabulary abounds in Hindi, Persian and Arabic words He has written the following books:

Qissa Shirin Farhad
Qissa Sohni Mahiwal
Qissa Sassi Punnun
Gyan Prakash
Dohre

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hashim_(poet)</link></item><item><title>List of Jewish film directors</title><description>This is a list of Jewish film directors. The countries listed are those where films were directed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Jewish_film_directors</link></item><item><title>David Thornton (actor)</title><description>David Farrington Thornton (born May 4, 1953) is an American actor. He has appeared in John Q, Home Alone 3 as Earl Unger, Law &amp; Order, The Notebook, and The Other Woman, among other roles. He is the husband of singer, songwriter and actress Cyndi Lauper.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Thornton_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Anthony Carrigan (actor)</title><description>Anthony Carrigan (born January 2, 1983) is an American actor. He is best known for playing Chechen mobster NoHo Hank in the HBO series Barry (2018–2023), for which he was nominated three times for the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Supporting Actor in a Comedy Series in 2019, 2022, and 2023. He is also known for playing Tyler Davies in the television series The Forgotten (2009–2010), Victor Zsasz in the FOX series Gotham (2014–2019), and the robot Dennis Caleb McCoy in Bill &amp; Ted Face the Music (2020).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Carrigan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Tom Irwin (actor)</title><description>Tom Irwin (born June 1, 1956) is an American film, television, and stage actor. Irwin is best known for his roles as Adrian Powell in the Lifetime comedy-drama series Devious Maids and as Graham Chase in the mid-1990s drama My So-Called Life.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Irwin_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Peter Hermann (actor)</title><description>Peter Hermann (born August 15, 1967) is an American actor. He may be best known for his roles as Charles Brooks in Younger, Trevor Langan in Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit, and Jack Boyle in Blue Bloods. Hermann is the husband of fellow Law &amp; Order franchise actor Mariska Hargitay, series lead of Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Hermann_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Anthony Edwards (actor)</title><description>Anthony Charles Edwards (born July 19, 1962) is an American actor, director, and producer. He played Dr. Mark Greene on the first eight seasons of ER, for which he received a Golden Globe Award and six Screen Actors Guild Awards, and was nominated for four consecutive Primetime Emmy Awards. He has appeared in various films and television series, including Fast Times at Ridgemont High, Top Gun, Zodiac, Gotcha!, Miracle Mile, Revenge of the Nerds, Planes, Northern Exposure, and Designated Survivor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Edwards_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>