<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Poets' Corner</title><description>Poets' Corner is a section of the southern transept of Westminster Abbey in London, where many poets, playwrights, and writers are buried or commemorated.
The first poet interred in Poets' Corner was Geoffrey Chaucer in 1400. William Shakespeare was commemorated with a monument in 1740, over a century after his death. Over the centuries, a tradition has grown up of interring or memorialising people there in recognition of their contribution to British culture. In the overwhelming majority of cases, the honour is awarded to writers.
In 2009, the founders of the Royal Ballet were commemorated in a memorial floor stone and on 25 September 2010, the writer Elizabeth Gaskell was celebrated with the dedication of a panel in the memorial window. On 6 December 2011, former Poet Laureate Ted Hughes was commemorated with a floor stone. On 22 November 2013, the fiftieth anniversary of his death, writer C. S. Lewis was commemorated with a memorial floor stone. The poet Philip Larkin was commemorated with a floor stone dedicated on 2 December 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poets%27_Corner</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became the independent production company A24's highest-grossing release, and won the duo many awards, including  Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>List of film director–composer collaborations</title><description>The following film directors and film score composers have worked together on multiple projects.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_film_director%E2%80%93composer_collaborations</link></item><item><title>Variety Studio: Actors on Actors</title><description>Variety Studio: Actors on Actors, also referred to as Actors on Actors, is an American entertainment talk show television series coproduced by PBS SoCal and Variety Media. It premiered on December 21, 2014, on PBS SoCal.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variety_Studio:_Actors_on_Actors</link></item><item><title>Reid Scott (actor)</title><description>Reid W. Scott  (born November 19, 1977) is an American actor. He is best known for his starring roles as Brendan "Brando" Dorff in the TBS comedy series My Boys (2006–2010), Dan Egan in the HBO comedy series Veep (2012–2019), and Gordon Ford in The Marvelous Mrs. Maisel (2022–2023). He also appeared in the romantic comedy film Home Again (2017), the superhero film Venom (2018), and the comedy-drama film Late Night (2019).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reid_Scott_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Martin McCann (actor)</title><description>Martin McCann (born 20 July 1983) is a Northern Irish actor. In 2020, he was listed as number 48 on The Irish Times list of Ireland's greatest film actors.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martin_McCann_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Wilson (actor)</title><description>Andrew Cunningham Wilson (born August 22, 1964) is an American actor and director. He is the older brother of actors Owen Wilson and Luke Wilson.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Wilson_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>