<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1958) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Mark Bailey (writer)</title><description>Mark Daniel Bailey (born November 21, 1968) is an American writer, best known for his documentary films, including Last Days in Vietnam (2014), Downfall: The Case Against Boeing (2022), and The Volcano: Rescue from Whakaari (2022). Bailey, together with his wife, filmmaker Rory Kennedy, own Moxie Films, a documentary film production company. The company produces documentaries "for broadcast and cable networks, including Netflix, HBO, PBS, A&amp;E, National Geographic, Showtime, Discovery Channel, MTV, TLC, Lifetime Television, the Oxygen Network, and the Sundance Channel as well as for educational foundations and philanthropic organizations."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Bailey_(writer)</link></item><item><title>James Thomson (poet, born 1700)</title><description>James Thomson (c. 11 September 1700 – 27 August 1748) was a Scottish poet and playwright, known for his poems The Seasons and The Castle of Indolence, and for the lyrics of "Rule, Britannia!"

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Thomson_(poet,_born_1700)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.
Over a dozen national governments continue the poet laureate tradition.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Mark Jackson (athletic director)</title><description>Mark Jackson (born September 14, 1972) is the athletic director for Northwestern University. Previously, Jackson was the senior associate athletic director for the University of Southern California and the athletic director for Villanova University.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Jackson_(athletic_director)</link></item><item><title>Srikanth (actor, born 1968)</title><description>Meka Srikanth (born 23 March 1968) is an Indian actor who is known for works predominantly in Telugu cinema. He has appeared in more than 120 films. The actor has received one state Nandi Award, and one Filmfare Award South. He has starred in films like Swarabhishekam, which won the National Film Award for Best Feature Film in Telugu for 2004. Srikanth's another film Virodhi premiered at the Indian panorama section, at the 2011 International Film Festival of India. Sri Rama Rajyam also had a special screening at International Film Festival of India on 28 November 2011. He has also appeared in some other language films including  Kannada, Malayalam and Tamil films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Srikanth_(actor,_born_1968)</link></item><item><title>Michael Gordon (film director)</title><description>Michael Gordon (born Irving Kunin Gordon; September 6, 1909 – April 29, 1993) was an American stage actor and stage and film director.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Gordon_(film_director)</link></item><item><title>Ian Chen (actor)</title><description>Ian Chen (born September 7, 2006) is an American actor. He is known for his roles as Evan Huang in the ABC sitcom Fresh Off the Boat (2015–2020) and Eugene Choi in the DC Extended Universe films Shazam! (2019) and Shazam! Fury of the Gods (2023).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Chen_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Alessandro Borghi (actor)</title><description>Alessandro Borghi (Italian: [alesˈsandro ˈborɡi]; born 19 September 1986) is an Italian actor. He has appeared in more than twenty films since 2006. He is part of the main cast of Suburra and Suburra: Blood on Rome. He won the David di Donatello for Best Actor in 2019 for his portrayal of building surveyor Stefano Cucchi, a victim of police brutality, in the film On My Skin.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alessandro_Borghi_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Vishal Singh (actor, born 1985)</title><description>Vishal Singh (born 7 September 1985) is an Indian model and actor who works in Hindi television. He is best known for his roles of Ayaan Nanda in Kuchh Is Tara and Jigar Chirag Modi in Saath Nibhaana Saathiya.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vishal_Singh_(actor,_born_1985)</link></item><item><title>Robert Townsend (actor)</title><description>Robert Townsend (born February 6, 1957) is an American actor, director, comedian, and writer. Townsend is best known for directing the films Hollywood Shuffle (1987), Eddie Murphy Raw (1987), The Meteor Man (1993), The Five Heartbeats (1991) and various other films and stand-up specials. He is especially known for his portrayal of The WB's sitcom The Parent 'Hood 's main character Robert Peterson, the series he created and directed select episodes of ran from 1995 to 1999. Townsend is also known for his role as Donald "Duck" Matthews in his 1991 film The Five Heartbeats. He later wrote, directed and produced Making the Five Heartbeats (2018), a documentary film about the production process and behind the scenes insight into creating the film. Townsend is also known for his production company Townsend Entertainment which has produced films Playin' for Love, In the Hive and more. During the 1980s and early–1990s, Townsend gained national exposure through his stand-up comedy routines and appearances on The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson. Townsend has worked with talent including Halle Berry, Morgan Freeman, Chris Tucker, Beyoncé, Denzel Washington, Ayo Edebiri, and many more.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Townsend_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>