<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1957) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Williams (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wesley Williams (born August 5, 1981) is an American actor, director, producer, and activist best known as Jackson Avery on Grey's Anatomy (2009–22; 2024). He has also appeared in films such as The Cabin in the Woods (2012) and The Butler (2013). He provided voice acting and motion capture for Markus in the video game Detroit: Become Human (2018).
He served as an executive producer of the Academy Award-winning short, Two Distant Strangers (2020), and the Tony Award-winning revival of Take Me Out (2022). He also acted in the latter and was nominated for a Tony Award for Best Featured Actor in a Play.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Williams_(actor)</link></item><item><title>David Thornton (actor)</title><description>David Farrington Thornton (born May 4, 1953) is an American actor. He has appeared in John Q, Home Alone 3 as Earl Unger, Law &amp; Order, The Notebook, and The Other Woman, among other roles. He is the husband of singer, songwriter and actress Cyndi Lauper.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Thornton_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Wilson (actor)</title><description>Andrew Cunningham Wilson (born August 22, 1964) is an American actor and director. He is the older brother of actors Owen Wilson and Luke Wilson.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Wilson_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>