<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Mark Bailey (writer)</title><description>Mark Daniel Bailey (born November 21, 1968) is an American writer, best known for his documentary films, including Last Days in Vietnam (2014), Downfall: The Case Against Boeing (2022), and The Volcano: Rescue from Whakaari (2022). Bailey, together with his wife, filmmaker Rory Kennedy, own Moxie Films, a documentary film production company. The company produces documentaries "for broadcast and cable networks, including Netflix, HBO, PBS, A&amp;E, National Geographic, Showtime, Discovery Channel, MTV, TLC, Lifetime Television, the Oxygen Network, and the Sundance Channel as well as for educational foundations and philanthropic organizations."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Bailey_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.
Over a dozen national governments continue the poet laureate tradition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Mohsin Naqvi (poet)</title><description>Mohsin Naqvi (10 May 1947 − 15 January 1996) was a Pakistani poet, known for his ghazals.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mohsin_Naqvi_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Ed Cox (poet)</title><description>Ed Cox (July 6, 1946 in Washington, D.C. – September 1, 1992) was an American poet.
He served in the U.S. Navy.
He studied at the University of Maryland with Rudd Fleming and Roderick Jellema.
He worked for the U.S. Association for the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees.
He read at Mass Transit, at the Community Book Shop on P Street.
He lived at 1345 Saratoga Ave. NE from 1959 to 1964, and 1920 S Street NW,4110 Emery St NW, and 1301 15th St. NW #720 in the 1980s. 
His papers are held by American University.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ed_Cox_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Matt Johnson (director)</title><description>Matt Johnson (born October 5, 1985) is a Canadian actor and filmmaker. He first attracted accolades for his low-budget independent feature films, including The Dirties (2013), which won Best Narrative Feature at the Slamdance Film Festival, and Operation Avalanche (2016), which premiered at the Sundance Film Festival.
Johnson achieved widespread critical and commercial acclaim for his third feature film, BlackBerry (2023), which documented the rise and fall of the BlackBerry phone. The film premiered in competition at the 73rd Berlin International Film Festival, and went on to win several accolades including the $50,000 Rogers Best Canadian Film Award from the Toronto Film Critics Association.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matt_Johnson_(director)</link></item><item><title>Max Winkler (director)</title><description>Max Daniel Winkler (born August 18, 1983) is an American director and screenwriter. His credits include directing the film Ceremony (2010), starring Michael Angarano and Uma Thurman. The film was Winkler's feature film directorial debut.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Winkler_(director)</link></item><item><title>Tyler Christopher (actor)</title><description>Tyler Christopher Baker (November 11, 1972 – October 31, 2023) was an American actor. He was best known for his roles as Nikolas Cassadine (1996–1999, 2003–2011, 2013–2016) and Connor Bishop (2004–2005) on the ABC soap opera General Hospital. 
In August 2016, it was announced that Christopher would be joining the cast of the NBC soap opera Days of Our Lives as the son of long-time villains Stefano DiMera and Vivian Alamain. His tenure on the show began December 29, 2017. Christopher left the series on March 20, 2019.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tyler_Christopher_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Benjamin Walker (actor)</title><description>Benjamin Walker Scodelario-Davis (né Davis; born June 21, 1982) is an American actor and stand-up comedian. He starred as Andrew Jackson in the musical Bloody Bloody Andrew Jackson, which premiered on Broadway in 2010. He has appeared in a number of Broadway productions, notably as Patrick Bateman in the 2016 musical adaptation of the novel American Psycho and as Chris Keller in the 2019 revival of All My Sons, for which he was nominated for a Tony Award for Best Featured Actor. On screen, he is known for his title role in the 2012 film Abraham Lincoln: Vampire Hunter, as well as his appearances in the films Kinsey, Flags of Our Fathers, and In the Heart of the Sea. In 2019, he starred as Erik Gelden in the third and final season of Marvel's Jessica Jones from Netflix. He plays the High King of the Ñoldorin Elves Ereinion Gil-galad in the Amazon Prime Video series The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benjamin_Walker_(actor)</link></item><item><title>David Thornton (actor)</title><description>David Farrington Thornton (born June 12, 1953) is an American actor. He has appeared in John Q, Home Alone 3 as Earl Unger, Law &amp; Order, The Notebook, and The Other Woman, among other roles. He is the husband of singer songwriter Cyndi Lauper.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Thornton_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Luke Norris (actor)</title><description>Luke Norris (born 1 September 1985)  is an English actor best known for playing Dr Dwight Enys in Poldark.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luke_Norris_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Joseph Quinn (actor)</title><description>Joseph Quinn (born 26 January 1994) is an English actor. He is best known for his role as Eddie Munson in the fourth season of the Netflix series Stranger Things (2022). His previous appearances were in the BBC One series Dickensian (2016), Howards End (2017), and Les Misérables (2018), and the Sky Atlantic series Catherine the Great (2019). He has since starred in the horror film A Quiet Place: Day One (2024).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joseph_Quinn_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Andrew Lawrence (actor)</title><description>Andrew Lawrence (born Andrew James Mignogna; January 12, 1988) is an American actor, filmmaker, podcaster and singer. He is known for his roles as Andy Roman in Brotherly Love (starring with his real life brothers Joey and Matthew) and T.J. Detweiler in Recess. Outside of his acting and music career, Lawrence made his directorial debut with the 2020 film The Office Mix-Up.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Lawrence_(actor)</link></item><item><title>John Reilly (actor, born 1934)</title><description>John Henry Matthew Reilly (November 11, 1934 – January 9, 2021) was an American film and television actor who appeared on soap operas, including General Hospital, Sunset Beach, and Passions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Reilly_(actor,_born_1934)</link></item><item><title>Christopher Jones (actor, born 1941)</title><description>William Frank Jones (August 18, 1941 – January 31, 2014), known professionally as Christopher Jones, was an American actor. He was best known for his starring roles in the films Wild in the Streets (1968) and Ryan's Daughter (1970), and for playing the title role in the 1960s television series The Legend of Jesse James.
According to The New York Times, Jones' "talent and star power drew comparisons with James Dean," and he "seemed poised for stardom before abruptly abandoning his movie career in the late 1960s."

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Jones_(actor,_born_1941)</link></item></channel></rss>