<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Larry Brown (writer)</title><description>William Larry Brown (July 9, 1951 – November 24, 2004) was an American novelist, non-fiction, and short story writer. He received numerous awards during his lifetime, including the Mississippi Institute of Arts and Letters award for fiction, the Lila Wallace-Reader's Digest Award, and Mississippi's Governor's Award For Excellence in the Arts. Brown was also the first two-time winner of the Southern Book Award for Fiction.
His notable works include Dirty Work, Joe, Father and Son, and Big Bad Love. The last of these was adapted for a 2001 film of the same name, starring Debra Winger and Arliss Howard. In 2013 a film adaptation of Joe was released, featuring Nicolas Cage.
Independent filmmaker Gary Hawkins, who wrote the screenplay for Joe, has directed an award-winning documentary of Brown's life and work in The Rough South of Larry Brown (2002).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larry_Brown_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Paul Lynch (writer)</title><description>Paul Lynch (born 1977) is an Irish novelist known for his poetic, lyrical style and exploration of complex themes. He has published five novels and has won several awards, including the 2018 Kerry Group Irish Fiction Award and the 2023 Booker Prize, for Prophet Song.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Lynch_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Chen Chen (poet)</title><description>Chen Chen (Chinese: 陳琛; pinyin: Chén Chēn, born March 9, 1989) is an American poet. His book, When I Grow Up I Want to Be a List of Further Possibilities, was longlisted for the 2017 National Book Award for Poetry. Chen serves on the poetry faculty for the low-residency MFA programs at New England College and Stonecoast. He served as Jacob Ziskind Poet-in-Residence at Brandeis University from 2018 to 2022.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chen_Chen_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Peter Hastings (director)</title><description>Peter Hastings (born January 9, 1960) is an American writer, director, and producer of animated television. He is known for The Epic Tales of Captain Underpants, Kung Fu Panda: Legends of Awesomeness, Animaniacs, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles and Pinky and the Brain. He has won six Emmy awards and a Peabody award. He also directed the musical film The Country Bears (2002) and wrote and directed the animated film Dog Man (2025).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Hastings_(director)</link></item><item><title>Jeeva (director)</title><description>Jeeva (21 September 1963 – 26 June 2007) was an Indian filmmaker, cinematographer and film director in Tamil, Hindi and Malayalam-language cinema. He was an established cinematographer in the late 90s and early 2000s.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeeva_(director)</link></item><item><title>List of directorial debuts</title><description>This is a list of film directorial debuts in chronological order. The films and dates referred to are a director's first commercial cinematic release. Many filmmakers have directed works which were not commercially released, for example early works by Orson Welles such as his filming of his stage production of Twelfth Night in 1933 or his experimental short film The Hearts of Age in 1934. Often, these early works were not intended for commercial release by intent, such as film school projects or inability to find distribution.
Subsequently, many directors learned their trade in the medium of television as it became popular in the 1940s and 1950s. Notable directors who did their first directorial work in this medium include Robert Altman, Sidney Lumet, and Alfonso Cuarón. As commercial television advertising became more cinematic in the 1960s and 1970s, many directors early work was in this medium, including directors such as Alan Parker and Ridley Scott. With the success of MTV and the popularity of music videos from the early 1980s, this gave another avenue for directors to hone their skills. Notable directors whose early work was in music videos include David Fincher, Jonathan Glazer, Michel Gondry, and Spike Jonze.
The following symbols indicate where a director has worked in another medium prior to directing commercially.
♦ Indicates where a director has created other earlier works for television
# Indicates when a director's earlier work is uncredited
† Indicates when a director's earlier work has not been released in cinemas, for example film school productions, short films or music videos.
Refer to individual entries for further detail.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_directorial_debuts</link></item><item><title>Charlie Hall (actor, born 1997)</title><description>Charlie Hall (born May 30, 1997) is an American television and film actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hall_(actor,_born_1997)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Bob May (actor)</title><description>Bob May (September 4, 1939 – January 18, 2009) was an American actor best remembered for playing The Robot on the television series Lost in Space, which debuted in 1965 and ran until 1968.  May appeared in all 83 episodes inside a prop costume built by Bob Stewart; the robot's voice was dubbed by Dick Tufeld, who was also the narrator of the series.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bob_May_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kim Ji-hoon (actor, born 1981)</title><description>Kim Ji-hoon (Korean: 김지훈; born May 9, 1981) is a South Korean actor. He is best known for his romantic comedies on television such as The Golden Age of Daughters-in-Law (2007), Love Marriage (also known as Matchmaker's Lover, 2008), Stars Falling from the Sky (also known as Wish Upon a Star, 2010), and My Cute Guys (2012). In 2010, he also appeared in the film Natalie, and cable mystery series Unsolved. In 2023 he appeared in Lee Chung-hyun's Netflix film Ballerina.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Ji-hoon_(actor,_born_1981)</link></item><item><title>Feroz Khan (actor)</title><description>Feroz Khan (born Zulfiqar Ali Shah Khan; 25 September 1939 — 27 April 2009) was an Indian actor, film editor, producer and director best known for his work in Indian cinema. He appeared in over 60 films throughout his career and became one of Bollywood's popular style icons. Feroz Khan is known for his roles in successful Hindi films, such as Arzoo (1965), Safar (1970), Upaasna (1971), Mela (1971), Apradh (1972), Khotte Sikkay (1974), Kaala Sona (1975), Dharmatma (1975), Nagin (1976), Qurbani (1980), Kachche Heere (1982), Janbaaz (1986), Dayavan (1988), Yalgaar (1992), Welcome (2007).
He won the Filmfare Best Supporting Actor Award for Aadmi Aur Insaan (1969) in 1970, and was honored with the Filmfare Lifetime Achievement Award in 2000. He has been called "the Clint Eastwood of the East".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feroz_Khan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Srikanth (actor, born 1968)</title><description>Meka Srikanth (born 23 March 1968) is an Indian actor who is known for works predominantly in Telugu cinema. He has appeared in more than 120 films. The actor has received one state Nandi Award, and one Filmfare Award South. He has starred in films like Swarabhishekam, which won the National Film Award for Best Feature Film in Telugu for 2004. Srikanth's another film Virodhi premiered at the Indian panorama section, at the 2011 International Film Festival of India. Sri Rama Rajyam also had a special screening at International Film Festival of India on 28 November 2011. He has also appeared in some other language films including  Kannada, Malayalam and Tamil films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Srikanth_(actor,_born_1968)</link></item><item><title>Steve Forrest (actor)</title><description>Steve Forrest (born William Forrest Andrews; September 29, 1925 – May 18, 2013) was an American actor who was well known for his role as Lt. Hondo Harrelson in the hit television series S.W.A.T., which was broadcast on ABC from 1975 to 1976. He was also known for his  performance in Mommie Dearest (1981).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Forrest_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>