<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>John Taylor (poet)</title><description>John Taylor (24 August 1578 – December 1653) was an English poet who dubbed himself "The Water Poet".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Taylor_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kerry James (actor)</title><description>Kerry James Horn (born August 2, 1986) is a Canadian actor and producer, known for Aliens in America (2007), and best known for his role as Caleb Odell on the CBC series Heartland.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kerry_James_(actor)</link></item><item><title>David Thornton (actor)</title><description>David Farrington Thornton (born June 12, 1953) is an American actor. He has appeared in John Q, Home Alone 3 as Earl Unger, Law &amp; Order, The Notebook, and The Other Woman, among other roles. He is the husband of singer, songwriter and actress Cyndi Lauper.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Thornton_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Peter (actor)</title><description>Peter Hermann (born August 15, 1967) is an American actor. He may be best known for his roles as Charles Brooks in Younger, Trevor Langan in Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit, and Jack Boyle in Blue Bloods. Hermann is the husband of fellow Law &amp; Order franchise actor Mariska Hargitay, series lead of Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Hermann_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Josh Dean (actor)</title><description>George Joshua Christian Dean (born December 3, 1979) is a Canadian actor and improvisor. He was born in Burnaby, British Columbia and raised in Edmonton, Alberta, where he performed in the improvised soap opera Die-Nasty and toured with improv company Rapid Fire Theatre.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Josh_Dean_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>