<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Robert King (writer)</title><description>Robert King (born 1959) is an American film and television writer and producer. He is married to Michelle King, who is also his writing and producing partner; the two are best known as the creators and showrunners of the legal drama series The Good Wife (2009–16), its spin-offs The Good Fight (2017–22) and Elsbeth (2024–present), and the supernatural drama Evil (2019–24).
The two are also the founders of their own production company, King Size Productions. Prior to his television work with his wife, King had worked extensively as a film screenwriter for a wide variety of genres. His credits include Cutthroat Island, which is regarded as one of the biggest box-office bombs in film history.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_King_(writer)</link></item><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>István Ágh (poet)</title><description>István Ágh (born István Nagy; 24 March 1938 in Iszkáz) is a Hungarian poet. He is the younger brother of László Nagy who was also a poet.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Istv%C3%A1n_%C3%81gh_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Srikanth (actor, born 1979)</title><description>Srikanth is an Indian actor known for his works predominantly in Tamil and Telugu films. He is credited as Sriram in Telugu films. He debuted in K. Balachander's tele serial Jannal – Marabu Kavithaigal (1999). His film debut was in the romantic film Roja Kootam (2002) and went on to star in more such films including April Maadhathil (2002), Parthiban Kanavu (2003) and Okariki Okaru (2003). He subsequently went on to portray action roles in  Drohi (2010). In 2012, he starred in Nanban, the Tamil remake of 3 Idiots, directed by S. Shankar.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Srikanth_(actor,_born_1979)</link></item><item><title>Neil Grayston (actor)</title><description>Neil Gordon Grayston (born March 24, 1981) is a Canadian actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neil_Grayston_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Ibrahim Ali Khan (actor)</title><description>Ibrahim Ali Khan Pataudi (born 5 March 2001) is an Indian actor who works in Hindi films. Born to actors Saif Ali Khan and Amrita Singh, he had his first acting role as a child as the younger version of his father's character in Tashan (2008). As an adult, he had his first leading role in the Netflix romantic comedy film Nadaaniyan (2025).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ibrahim_Ali_Khan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>David Bacon (actor)</title><description>David Bacon (born Gaspar Griswold Bacon Jr., March 24, 1914 – September 12, 1943) was an American stage and film actor.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Bacon_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>