<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Peter James (writer)</title><description>Peter J. James (born 22 August 1948) is a British writer of crime. He was born in Brighton, the son of Cornelia James, the former glovemaker to Queen Elizabeth II.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_James_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Christopher Mayer (American actor)</title><description>Christopher Mayer (born George Charles Mayer III; February 21, 1954 – July 23, 2011), also known as Chip Mayer, was an American actor. He was best known for portraying Vance Duke on The Dukes of Hazzard for 19 episodes during season 5 when cousins Coy and Vance Duke temporarily replaced Bo and Luke Duke (due to a salary dispute between producers and the original actors).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Mayer_(American_actor)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Ellis (actor, born 1933)</title><description>Robert Ellis (September 24, 1933 – November 23, 1973) was an American film and television actor in the 1940s and 1950s, who was the last actor to play Henry Aldrich on the radio series The Aldrich Family. 

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Ellis_(actor,_born_1933)</link></item><item><title>Ali Raza (actor)</title><description>Muhammad Ali Raza (born 28 August 1998) is a Pakistani actor and model who works in Urdu television. Raza is known for portraying Daniyal in Muhabbat Gumshuda Meri  (2023) and Shahnawaz Shah in Iqtidar (2024-2025). 
In January 2025, Dawn included him in the list of the 7 "Pakistani actors who stood out in 2024".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ali_Raza_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Robert Walker (actor, born 1940)</title><description>Robert Hudson Walker Jr. (April 15, 1940 – December 5, 2019) was an American actor who appeared in films including Easy Rider (1969) and was a familiar presence on television in the 1960s and early 1970s. He became less active in later decades.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Walker_(actor,_born_1940)</link></item><item><title>David Thornton (actor)</title><description>David Farrington Thornton (born May 4, 1953) is an American actor. He has appeared in John Q, Home Alone 3 as Earl Unger, Law &amp; Order, The Notebook, and The Other Woman, among other roles. He is the husband of singer, songwriter and actress Cyndi Lauper.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Thornton_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Alastair Duncan (actor, born 1958)</title><description>Alastair Duncan is a Scottish actor and real estate broker. He is best known for his role as DS Peter Livingstone in Taggart (1983-1987) and for his voice work in animation, films and video games, notably as Mimir in the God of War (2018) and its 2022 sequel.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alastair_Duncan_(actor,_born_1958)</link></item></channel></rss>