<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Norman Lewis (writer)</title><description>John Frederick Norman Lewis (28 June 1908 – 22 July 2003) was a British writer. While he is best known for his travel writing, he also wrote twelve novels and several volumes of autobiography.
Subjects he explored in his travel writing include life in Naples during the Allied liberation of Italy (Naples '44); Vietnam and French colonial Indochina (A Dragon Apparent); Indonesia (An Empire of the East);  Burma (Golden Earth); tribal peoples of India (A Goddess in the Stones); Sicily and the Mafia (The Honoured Society and In Sicily); and the destruction caused by Christian missionaries in Latin America and elsewhere (The Missionaries).
His newspaper article entitled "Genocide in Brazil" (1969) prompted the creation of Survival International—an organisation dedicated to the protection of indigenous peoples around the world.
Graham Greene described Lewis as "one of the best writers, not of any particular decade, but of our century".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norman_Lewis_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1949) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Ed Cox (poet)</title><description>Ed Cox (July 6, 1946 in Washington, D.C. – September 1, 1992) was an American poet.
He served in the U.S. Navy.
He studied at the University of Maryland with Rudd Fleming and Roderick Jellema.
He worked for the U.S. Association for the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees.
He read at Mass Transit, at the Community Book Shop on P Street.
He lived at 1345 Saratoga Ave. NE from 1959 to 1964, and 1920 S Street NW,4110 Emery St NW, and 1301 15th St. NW #720 in the 1980s. 
His papers are held by American University.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ed_Cox_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Ruth weiss (beat poet)</title><description>ruth weiss (June 24, 1928 – July 31, 2020), born Ruth Elisabeth Weisz, was a poet, performer, playwright and artist. Born in Germany, but of Austrian citizenship, weiss made her home and career in the United States. She was considered to be a member of the Beat Generation, a label she, in later years, embraced.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ruth_weiss_(beat_poet)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Chetan Anand (director)</title><description>Chetan Anand (3 January 1921 – 6 July 1997) was a Bollywood film producer, screenwriter and director from India, whose first film, Neecha Nagar, was awarded the Grand Prix Prize (now Golden Palm) at the first ever Cannes Film Festival in 1946. Later, he co-founded Navketan Films with his younger brother Dev Anand in 1949.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chetan_Anand_(director)</link></item><item><title>Vijay (actor)</title><description>Joseph Vijay Chandrasekhar (born 22 June 1974), known professionally as Vijay, is an Indian actor and politician who works in Tamil cinema. In a career spanning over three decades, Vijay has acted in 68 films and is one of the most commercially successful actors in Tamil cinema with multiple films amongst the highest-grossing Tamil films of all time and is amongst the highest paid actors in India. He has won several awards as an actor. Referred to as "Thalapathy" (transl. Commander), Vijay has a significant fan following.
Born in Madras to director S. A. Chandrasekhar, Vijay made his debut as a child actor in the Tamil film Vetri (1984). After a few roles as a child actor in his father’s films, he played his first lead role in the film Naalaiya Theerpu (1992) at the age of 18. Vijay continued doing lead roles for the next few years with notable films amongst them included Poove Unakkaga (1996), Love Today (1997), Kadhalukku Mariyadhai (1997), Thullatha Manamum Thullum (1999) and Kushi (2000). In 1998, he was awarded Kalaimaamani by the Government of Tamil Nadu for his role in Kadhalukku Mariyadhai.
In 2004, he starred in the blockbuster action-masala film Ghilli and with subsequent success of Thirupaachi (2005) and Pokkiri (2007) later, he established himself as one of the leading and commercially successful actors in Tamil cinema. Following a period of moderate success, Vijay acted in several critically and commercially successful films starting from early 2010s including Thuppakki (2012), Kaththi (2014), Mersal (2017), Sarkar (2018), Master (2021), Beast (2022), Leo (2023) and his penultimate film The Greatest of All Time (2024).
In February 2024, Vijay announced his retirement from films and his forthcoming entry into politics with the launch of his political party, known as Tamilaga Vettri Kazhagam.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vijay_(actor)</link></item><item><title>John Marquez (actor)</title><description>John Charles Marquez (born 5 June 1970) is a British actor and writer. He is best known for his role as PC Joseph Penhale in ITV drama series Doc Martin (2007–2022) and Ray Wilson in BBC One's drama In the Club (2014–2016).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Marquez_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>