<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Peter Hastings (director)</title><description>Peter Livingston Hastings (born January 9, 1960) is an American writer, director, and producer of animated television. He is known for The Epic Tales of Captain Underpants, Kung Fu Panda: Legends of Awesomeness, Animaniacs, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, Pinky and the Brain, and ABC's One Saturday Morning block. He has won six Emmy awards and a Peabody award. He also directed the musical film The Country Bears (2002) and wrote and directed the animated film Dog Man (2025).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Hastings_(director)</link></item><item><title>Brian Gibson (director)</title><description>Brian Gibson (22 September 1944 – 4 January 2004) was an English film and television director.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Gibson_(director)</link></item><item><title>Charlie Hall (actor, born 1997)</title><description>Charlie Hall (born May 30, 1997) is an American television and film actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hall_(actor,_born_1997)</link></item><item><title>Jesse White (actor)</title><description>Jesse White (born Jesse Marc Weidenfeld; January 3, 1917 – January 9, 1997) was an American actor who was best known for his portrayal as "Ol' Lonely" the repairman in Maytag television commercials from 1967 to 1988.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_White_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Anthony Carrigan (actor)</title><description>Anthony Carrigan (born January 2, 1983) is an American actor. He is best known for playing Chechen mobster NoHo Hank in the HBO series Barry (2018–2023), for which he was nominated three times for the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Supporting Actor in a Comedy Series in 2019, 2022, and 2023. 
He is also known for playing Tyler Davies in the television series The Forgotten (2009–2010), Victor Zsasz in the Fox series Gotham (2014–2019), the robot Dennis Caleb McCoy in Bill &amp; Ted Face the Music (2020), and Metamorpho in Superman (2025). In 2025, he also starred in the second season of the Peacock series Twisted Metal.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Carrigan_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Srikanth (actor, born 1968)</title><description>Meka Srikanth (born 23 March 1968) is an Indian actor who is known for works predominantly in Telugu cinema. He has appeared in more than 120 films. The actor has received one state Nandi Award, and one Filmfare Award South. He has starred in films like Swarabhishekam, which won the National Film Award for Best Feature Film in Telugu for 2004. Srikanth's another film Virodhi premiered at the Indian panorama section, at the 2011 International Film Festival of India. Sri Rama Rajyam also had a special screening at International Film Festival of India on 28 November 2011. He has also appeared in some other language films including Kannada, Malayalam and Tamil films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Srikanth_(actor,_born_1968)</link></item><item><title>Charles Lane (actor, born 1905)</title><description>Charles Lane (born Charles Gerstle Levison; January 26, 1905 – July 9, 2007) was an American character actor and centenarian whose career spanned 76 years.
A prolific actor who played hundreds of roles in both film and TV, Lane often played sour, scowling and disagreeable clerks, doctors, judges, and middle-management authority figures. Recalling in 1981 his many roles, he said "They were all good parts, but they were jerks. If you have a type established, though, and you're any good, it can mean considerable work for you." The New York Times reported that Lane's persona was so familiar to the public, "that people would come up to him in the street and greet him, because they thought they knew him from their hometowns." Lane's first film role, of more than 382, was as a hotel clerk in Smart Money (1931) starring Edward G. Robinson and James Cagney. Lane appeared in many Frank Capra films, including Mr. Deeds Goes to Town (1936), You Can't Take It with You (1938), Mr. Smith Goes to Washington (1939), Arsenic and Old Lace (1944), It's a Wonderful Life (1946) and Riding High (1950).
Lane transitioned smoothly into television, and is probably best remembered to TV viewers for his recurring role as the ever-scheming Homer Bedloe on Petticoat Junction. As well, Lucille Ball frequently cast Lane as a no-nonsense authority figure and comedic foe of her scatterbrained TV character on her TV series I Love Lucy, The Lucy–Desi Comedy Hour and The Lucy Show. Lane gave his last performance at the age of 101 as a narrator in 2006.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Lane_(actor,_born_1905)</link></item></channel></rss>