<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Mustafa the Poet</title><description>Mustafa Ahmed (born 28 July 1996), known as Mustafa, formerly known as Mustafa the Poet, is a Canadian poet, singer, songwriter, and filmmaker from Toronto. He released his debut EP, When Smoke Rises, in May 2021. His debut album, Dunya, was released on September 27, 2024.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mustafa_the_Poet</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Alexander Hanson (actor)</title><description>Alexander Harald St John Hanson (born 28 April 1961) is a Norwegian-English stage actor who has appeared in numerous plays and musicals in the West End, and also on Broadway.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Hanson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>William Campbell (actor)</title><description>William Campbell (October 30, 1923 – April 28, 2011) was an American actor who appeared in supporting roles in major film productions, and also starred in several low-budget B-movies and horror films.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Campbell_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Bruce Kirby (actor)</title><description>Bruce Kirby (born Bruno Giovanni Quidaciolu; April 28, 1925 – January 24, 2021) was an American character actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bruce_Kirby_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Srikanth (actor, born 1979)</title><description>Srikanth is an Indian actor known for his works predominantly in Tamil and Telugu films. He is credited as Sriram in Telugu films. He debuted in K. Balachander's tele serial Jannal – Marabu Kavithaigal (1999). His film debut was in the romantic film Roja Kootam (2002) and went on to star in more such films including April Maadhathil (2002), Parthiban Kanavu (2003) and Okariki Okaru (2003). He subsequently went on to portray action roles in  Drohi (2010). In 2012, he starred in Nanban, the Tamil remake of 3 Idiots, directed by S. Shankar.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Srikanth_(actor,_born_1979)</link></item><item><title>Ali Raza (actor)</title><description>Muhammad Ali Raza (born 28 August 1998) is a Pakistani actor and model who works in Urdu television. Raza is known for portraying Daniyal in Muhabbat Gumshuda Meri  (2023) and Shahnawaz Shah in Iqtidar (2024-2025). 
In January 2025, Dawn included him in the list of the 7 "Pakistani actors who stood out in 2024".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ali_Raza_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Eduardo Scarpetta (actor, born 1993)</title><description>Eduardo Scarpetta (born 14 April 1993) is an Italian actor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eduardo_Scarpetta_(actor,_born_1993)</link></item></channel></rss>