<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Patrick Hamilton (writer)</title><description>Anthony Walter Patrick Hamilton (17 March 1904 – 23 September 1962) was an English playwright and novelist.  
He was well regarded by Graham Greene and J. B. Priestley, and study of his novels has been revived because of their distinctive style, deploying a Dickensian narrative voice to convey aspects of inter-war London street culture. They display a strong sympathy for the poor, as well as an acerbic black humour. Doris Lessing wrote in The Times in 1968: "Hamilton was a marvellous novelist who's grossly neglected".
His two most successful plays, Rope (1929) and Gas Light (1938), were made into famous films: Alfred Hitchcock's Rope (1948); the UK-made Gaslight (1940), followed by the 1944 American version.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patrick_Hamilton_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Sanmao (writer)</title><description>Sanmao (Chinese: 三毛; pinyin: Sānmáo) was the pen name of Echo Chen Ping (born Chen Mao-ping; 26 March 1943 – 4 January 1991), a Taiwanese writer and translator. Her works range from autobiographical writing, travel writing and reflective novels, to translations of Spanish-language comic strips. She studied philosophy and taught German before becoming a career writer. Her pen name was adopted from the main character of Zhang Leping's most famous work, Sanmao. In English, she was also known as Echo or Echo Chan, the first name she used in Latin script, after the eponymous Greek nymph. Since childhood, she was said to have avoided writing the character "Mao" (懋) as it was too complex; later in life, she legally changed her name to Chen Ping.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sanmao_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>Evan Jones (Australian poet)</title><description>Evan Lloyd Jones (20 November 1931 – 3 August 2022) was an Australian poet and academic.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evan_Jones_(Australian_poet)</link></item><item><title>Brad Armstrong (director)</title><description>Brad Armstrong (born Rod Hopkins; September 23, 1965) is a Canadian pornographic actor, director, producer and screenwriter. He is currently under contract with Wicked Pictures. He has been known as one of the most popular leading men in the sex industry, as well as "The King of Porn" and "The Spielberg of Skin Directors".
Among the films he has directed is Octomom Home Alone (2012).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brad_Armstrong_(director)</link></item><item><title>Iván Nagy (director)</title><description>Iván Nagy (January 23, 1938 – March 23, 2015) was a Hungarian film and television director best known for directing theatrical and television films such as Bad Charleston Charlie, Skinner, Playing with Fire and Deadly Hero. Nagy also directed episodes of the television series CHiPs, Starsky &amp; Hutch, and The Hitchhiker.
Nagy was a convicted bookmaker, and was the former boyfriend of Hollywood madam Heidi Fleiss. He was featured in the documentary Heidi Fleiss: Hollywood Madam.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iv%C3%A1n_Nagy_(director)</link></item><item><title>Chetan Anand (director)</title><description>Chetan Anand (3 January 1921 – 6 July 1997) was a Bollywood film producer, screenwriter and director from India, whose first film, Neecha Nagar, was awarded the Grand Prix Prize (now Golden Palm) at the first ever Cannes Film Festival in 1946. Later, he co-founded Navketan Films with his younger brother Dev Anand in 1949.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chetan_Anand_(director)</link></item><item><title>Roger Clark (actor, born 1978)</title><description>Roger Clark (born July 14, 1978) is an Irish-American actor and voice actor. He is best known for portraying Arthur Morgan through performance capture in the 2018 video game Red Dead Redemption 2, a role which garnered him critical acclaim and numerous accolades.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Clark_(actor,_born_1978)</link></item><item><title>Nasir Khan (Indian actor)</title><description>Nasir Khan (11 January 1924 – 3 May 1974) was an Indian actor. He was the younger brother of actor Dilip Kumar and is the father of actor Ayub Khan.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nasir_Khan_(Indian_actor)</link></item><item><title>Ibrahim Ali Khan (actor)</title><description>Ibrahim Ali Khan Pataudi (born 5 March 2001) is an Indian actor who works in Hindi films. Born to actors Saif Ali Khan and Amrita Singh, he had his first acting role as a child as the younger version of his father's character in Tashan (2008). As an adult, he had his first leading role in the poorly-received Netflix romantic comedy film Nadaaniyan (2025).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ibrahim_Ali_Khan_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>