<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Jack O'Connor (writer)</title><description>John Woolf O'Connor  (January 22, 1902 – January 20, 1978) was a writer and outdoorsman, best known as a writer for Outdoor Life magazine, where he served as Shooting Editor for 31 years.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_O%27Connor_(writer)</link></item><item><title>The Poets</title><description>The Tortured Poets Department is the eleventh studio album by the American singer-songwriter Taylor Swift. It was released on April 19, 2024, through Republic Records, with a double album edition subtitled The Anthology being released two hours after the standard edition. Swift wrote and produced the album with Jack Antonoff and Aaron Dessner while she was embarking on the American leg of the Eras Tour in 2023.
Using autobiographical songwriting, The Tortured Poets Department reflects Swift's cathartic episode while she was experiencing personal upheavals amidst breakups and heightened fame. Its songs depict grief and emotional tumult caused by ill-fated romance in a hyperbolic and confrontational manner, exploring themes of mourning, depression, anger, delusion, erotic desires, and self-aware humor. Musically, The Tortured Poets Department features two production styles. The standard edition is largely minimalist, mid-tempo synth-pop, characterized by synthesizers, sustained bass, and programmed drums. The Anthology primarily consists of mellow, acoustic chamber pop and folk-pop ballads driven by piano and guitar. The album incorporates elements of electronica, country, rock, folk, and western.
Swift promoted the album via social media and music streaming platforms, and she included an extended set list for the Eras Tour in 2024. The Tortured Poets Department topped charts across Europe, Asia–Pacific, and the Americas; broke streaming and sales records; and became the global best-selling album of 2024. In the United States, The Tortured Poets Department became Swift's seventh album to open with over a million units and first to open with two million units, spent 17 weeks atop the Billboard 200, and was certified eight-times platinum by the Recording Industry Association of America. Its songs made Swift the first artist to monopolize the Billboard Hot 100's top 14 spots, with the lead single "Fortnight" featuring Post Malone topping the chart.
Critical reception of The Tortured Poets Department upon its release was mixed; positive reviews praised the cathartic narrative songwriting as emotionally resonant and deemed the album one of Swift's finest works, but negative reviews described the production as redundant and the lyrics verbose rather than poetic. Within weeks after the initial reviews, several journalists reassessed the album and appreciated the musical and lyrical nuances, opining that the criticism was overshadowed by Swift's media overexposure. The album received an ARIA Music Award, a Premios Odeón, a Japan Gold Disc Award, and five nominations at the 67th Annual Grammy Awards, including Album of the Year.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tortured_Poets_Department</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them Grammy Award nominations.
They wrote and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became A24's highest-grossing film, and won the duo many awards, including Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>Frank Pellegrino (actor)</title><description>Frank Joseph Pellegrino (May 19, 1944 – January 31, 2017) was an American actor and restaurateur.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Pellegrino_(actor)</link></item><item><title>James Sutton (actor)</title><description>James Cook (born 31 January 1983), better known as James Sutton, is an English actor known as John Paul McQueen on Hollyoaks (2006–2008, 2012–2017, 2019–2026) and Ryan Lamb on Emmerdale (2009–2011).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Sutton_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>