<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>The Last Poets</title><description>The Last Poets is a poetry collective and musical group that arose in the late 1960s as part of the African-American civil rights movement and black nationalism. The name was inspired by revolutionary South African poet Keorapetse Kgositsile who believed he was in the last era of poetry before guns took over.
The group originally comprised Jalaluddin Mansur Nuriddin, Umar Bin Hassan and Abiodun Oyewole. Lineup changes and departures led to offshoots, including The Original Last Poets composed of Oyewole, Gylan Kain and David Nelson. The versions of the group led by Nuriddin and Hassan had the largest impact on popular culture. The Last Poets were one of the earliest influences on hip-hop music. Critic Jason Ankeny wrote: "With their politically charged raps, taut rhythms, and dedication to raising African-American consciousness, the Last Poets almost single-handedly laid the groundwork for the emergence of hip-hop." The British music magazine NME stated, "Serious spokesmen like Gil Scott-Heron, The Last Poets, and later Gary Byrd, paved the way for the many socially committed Black [emcees] a decade later."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Poets</link></item><item><title>Poet laureate</title><description>A poet laureate (plural: poets laureate) is a poet officially appointed by a government or conferring institution, typically expected to compose poems for special events and occasions. Albertino Mussato of Padua and Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) of Arezzo were the first to be crowned poets laureate after the classical age, respectively in 1315 and 1342. In Britain, the term dates from the appointment of Bernard André by Henry VII of England. The royal office of Poet Laureate in England dates from the appointment of John Dryden in 1668.
In modern times a poet laureate title may be conferred by an organization such as the Poetry Foundation, which designates a Young People's Poet Laureate, unconnected with the National Youth Poet Laureate and the United States Poet Laureate.
The office is also popular with regional and community groups. Examples include the Pikes Peak Poet Laureate, which is designated by a "Presenting Partners" group from within the community, the Minnesota poet laureate chosen by the League of Minnesota Poets (est. 1934), the Northampton Poet Laureate chosen by the Northampton Arts Council, and the Martha's Vineyard Poet Laureate chosen by ten judges representing the Martha's Vineyard Poetry Society.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poet_laureate</link></item><item><title>John Oldham (poet)</title><description>John Oldham (9 August 1653 – 9 December 1683) was an English satirical poet and translator. John Dryden, England's first Poet Laureate, was one of his admirers and upon his death wrote an elegy "To the Memory of Mr. Oldham".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Oldham_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Max Winkler (director)</title><description>Max Daniel Winkler (born August 18, 1983) is an American director and screenwriter. His credits include directing the film Ceremony (2010), starring Michael Angarano and Uma Thurman. The film was Winkler's feature film directorial debut.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max_Winkler_(director)</link></item><item><title>Chakrapani (director)</title><description>Aluru Venkata Subbarao (5 August 1908 – 24 September 1975), popularly known by his pen name Chakrapani, was an Indian screenwriter, film producer, studio owner, and director in Telugu cinema. He received two Filmfare Awards and was notable for his association with Vijaya Vauhini Studios, one of Asia's largest studios at the time. Chakrapani was also a partner at Vijaya Productions alongside B. Nagi Reddi and co-founded Chandamama, the children's magazine.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chakrapani_(director)</link></item><item><title>Charlie Hall (actor, born 1997)</title><description>Charlie Hall (born May 30, 1997) is an American television and film actor.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Hall_(actor,_born_1997)</link></item><item><title>Jesse Johnson (actor)</title><description>Jesse Wayne Johnson (born December 7, 1982) is an American actor. He is the son of actors Don Johnson and Patti D'Arbanville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Johnson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Christopher Jones (actor, born 1941)</title><description>William Frank Jones (August 18, 1941 – January 31, 2014), known professionally as Christopher Jones, was an American actor. He was best known for his starring roles in the films Wild in the Streets (1968) and Ryan's Daughter (1970), and for playing the title role in the 1960s television series The Legend of Jesse James.
According to The New York Times, Jones' "talent and star power drew comparisons with James Dean," and he "seemed poised for stardom before abruptly abandoning his movie career in the late 1960s."

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Jones_(actor,_born_1941)</link></item></channel></rss>