<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Clyde Phillips (writer)</title><description>Clyde B. Phillips (born October 3, 1949) is an American film producer, television writer, television producer, and novelist.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clyde_Phillips_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Hamish Hamilton (director)</title><description>Hamish Hamilton (born Mark Hamilton; 8 April 1966) is a British director. He has directed the Super Bowl halftime show annually since 2010.  He has also directed the Academy Awards and the MTV Video Music Awards, and worked with music artists such as Mariah Carey, Eminem, Madonna, The Who and U2. He directed the opening and closing ceremonies for the 2012 Summer Olympics.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hamish_Hamilton_(director)</link></item><item><title>Anthony Edwards (actor)</title><description>Anthony Charles Edwards (born July 19, 1962) is an American actor, director, and producer. He played Dr. Mark Greene on the first eight seasons of ER, for which he received a Golden Globe Award and six Screen Actors Guild Awards, and was nominated for four consecutive Primetime Emmy Awards. He has appeared in various films and television series, including Fast Times at Ridgemont High, Top Gun, Zodiac, Gotcha!, Miracle Mile, Revenge of the Nerds, Planes, Northern Exposure, and Designated Survivor.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Edwards_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Kim Su-hyeon (actor, born 1970)</title><description>Kim Su-hyeon (born February 20, 1970) is a South Korean actor. Best known as a supporting actor (notably in films directed by Ryoo Seung-wan), Kim played his first feature film leading role in the indie Sleepless Night (2013).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Su-hyeon_(actor,_born_1970)</link></item><item><title>Robert Walker (actor, born 1940)</title><description>Robert Hudson Walker Jr. (April 15, 1940 – December 5, 2019) was an American actor who appeared in films including Easy Rider (1969) and was a familiar presence on television in the 1960s and early 1970s. He became less active in later decades.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Walker_(actor,_born_1940)</link></item></channel></rss>