<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Notable Artists Born Today</title><link>http://example.com/artists</link><description>RSS feed of notable writers, poets, directors, and actors born on this day in history.</description><item><title>Mark Bailey (writer)</title><description>Mark Daniel Bailey (born November 21, 1968) is an American writer, best known for his documentary films, including Last Days in Vietnam (2014), Downfall: The Case Against Boeing (2022), and The Volcano: Rescue from Whakaari (2022). Bailey, together with his wife, filmmaker Rory Kennedy, own Moxie Films, a documentary film production company. The company produces documentaries "for broadcast and cable networks, including Netflix, HBO, PBS, A&amp;E, National Geographic, Showtime, Discovery Channel, MTV, TLC, Lifetime Television, the Oxygen Network, and the Sundance Channel as well as for educational foundations and philanthropic organizations."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Bailey_(writer)</link></item><item><title>Priest (writer)</title><description>Priest (pseudonym) (born 13 June 1988) is a Chinese author whose works are published online. She has been actively writing since 2007 and has received several awards for her writing. She is signed by the web-based publisher Jinjiang Literature City. She is considered to be among the top five Chinese writers catering to women's interests. She is known for writing various genres of danmei, as well as novels featuring female protagonists. Her works have been adapted into manhua, donghua, and Chinese dramas. Many of her novels have been translated into Korean, Thai, Vietnamese, Traditional Chinese, and Japanese versions. The dramas Guardian, Legend of Fei, Word of Honor, and Justice in the Dark are  based on Priest's novels.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Priest_(writer)</link></item><item><title>List of productions impacted by the 2023 Writers Guild of America strike</title><description>The 2023 Writers Guild of America strike had a significant impact on the film and television industries of the United States, causing many film and television projects to shut down or postpone production. It is the largest interruption to American film and television production since the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, as well as the largest labor stoppage for the Writers Guild of America (WGA) since the 2007–08 strike.
On July 14, 2023, SAG-AFTRA joined the WGA in its own strike, halting production on any remaining film or television series that previously had continued during the WGA strike. On September 24, 2023, the WGA suspended picketing upon reaching a tentative agreement. Following a vote, the union leadership voted to end the strike on September 27, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.
The SAG-AFTRA strike ended on November 9, 2023, at 12:01 a.m. PDT.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_productions_impacted_by_the_2023_Writers_Guild_of_America_strike</link></item><item><title>Yang Lian (poet)</title><description>Yang Lian (Chinese: 楊煉 Yáng Liàn; born 22 February 1955) is a Swiss-Chinese poet associated with the Misty Poets  and also with the Searching for Roots school.  He was born in Bern, Switzerland, in 1955 and was raised in Beijing, China. where he attended primary school.
His education was interrupted by the outbreak of the Cultural Revolution after 1966. In 1974, he was sent to Changping county near Beijing to undergo "re-education through labor", where he undertook a variety of tasks including digging graves. In 1977, after the Cultural Revolution had ended and Mao Zedong had died, Yang returned to Beijing, where he worked with the state broadcasting service.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yang_Lian_(poet)</link></item><item><title>Daniels (directors)</title><description>Daniel Kwan (born February 10, 1988) and Daniel Scheinert (born June 7, 1987), known collectively as the Daniels, are an American filmmaking duo. They began their career as directors of music videos, including ones for "Houdini" (2012) by Foster the People and "Turn Down for What" (2013) by DJ Snake and Lil Jon, both of which earned them nominations at the Grammy Awards.
They have since ventured into film, having written and directed the absurdist comedy-dramas Swiss Army Man (2016) and Everything Everywhere All at Once (2022). The latter became the independent production company A24's highest-grossing release, and won the duo many awards, including  Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniels_(directors)</link></item><item><title>List of directorial debuts</title><description>This is a list of film directorial debuts in chronological order. The films and dates referred to are a director's first commercial cinematic release. Many filmmakers have directed works which were not commercially released, for example early works by Orson Welles such as his filming of his stage production of Twelfth Night in 1933 or his experimental short film The Hearts of Age in 1934. Often these early works were not intended for commercial release either by intent, such as film school projects or inability to find distribution.
Subsequently, many directors learned their trade in the medium of television as it became popular in the 1940s and 1950s. Notable directors who did their first directorial work in this medium include Robert Altman, Sidney Lumet, and Alfonso Cuarón. As commercial television advertising became more cinematic in the 1960s and 1970s, many directors early work was in this medium, including directors such as Alan Parker and Ridley Scott. With the success of MTV and the popularity of music videos from the early 1980s, this gave another avenue for directors to hone their skills. Notable directors whose early work was in music videos include David Fincher, Jonathan Glazer, Michel Gondry, and Spike Jonze.
The following symbols indicate where a director has worked in another medium prior to directing commercially.
♦ Indicates where a director has created other earlier works for television
# Indicates when a director's earlier work is uncredited
† Indicates when a director's earlier work has not been released in cinemas, for example film school productions, short films or music videos.
Refer to individual entries for further detail.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_directorial_debuts</link></item><item><title>Ian Chen (actor)</title><description>Ian Chen (born September 7, 2006) is an American actor. He is known for his roles as Evan Huang in the ABC sitcom Fresh Off the Boat (2015–2020) and Eugene Choi in the DC Extended Universe films Shazam! (2019) and Shazam! Fury of the Gods (2023).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ian_Chen_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Jonathan Ward (actor)</title><description>Jonathan Ward (born February 24, 1970) is an American retired actor. He has starred mostly in television series and television films, but has also appeared in a small number of feature films, including the critically maligned 1988 cult film Mac and Me. His acting debut was on Broadway as Michael in Peter Pan.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jonathan_Ward_(actor)</link></item><item><title>David Thornton (actor)</title><description>David Farrington Thornton (born June 12, 1953) is an American actor. He has appeared in John Q, Home Alone 3 as Earl Unger, Law &amp; Order, The Notebook, and The Other Woman, among other roles. He is the husband of singer songwriter Cyndi Lauper.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Thornton_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Screen Actors Guild Awards</title><description>Screen Actors Guild Awards (also known as SAG Awards) are accolades given by the Screen Actors Guild-American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG-AFTRA). The award was founded in 1995 to recognize outstanding performances in movie and prime time television. SAG Awards have been one of the major awards events in the Hollywood film industry since then, along with the Golden Globe Awards and the Oscars. SAG awards focus both on individual performances and on the work of the entire ensemble of a drama series and comedy series, and the cast of a motion picture.
Nominations for the awards come from two committees, one for film and one for television, each numbering 2,100 members of the union, randomly selected anew each year, with the full membership (165,000 as of 2012) available to vote for the winners. It is considered an indicator of success at the Academy Awards in acting categories. The awards have been telecast on TNT from 1998 to 2022, and have been simulcast on TBS from 2007 to 2022. In May 2022 it was announced that both TNT and TBS will no longer air the awards. In January 2023, it was announced that Netflix will air the awards live beginning in 2024 as part of a new multi-year partnership, with the 2023 ceremony being announced to be live streamed on Netflix's YouTube channel as Netflix was still working out its live streaming capabilities at the time of the announcement.
The inaugural SAG Awards aired live on February 25, 1995, from Universal Studios' Stage 12. The second SAG awards aired live from the Santa Monica Civic Auditorium, while subsequent awards have been held at the Shrine Auditorium. On December 4, 2017, it was announced that the awards show would have its first host in its then twenty-four year history, with actress Kristen Bell presiding over the ceremony. As of 2023, Shakespeare in Love is the only film to receive nominations for all four acting categories and the ensemble award and Everything Everywhere All at Once is the only film to receive four awards, including the ensemble award.
The statuette given, a nude male figure holding both a mask of comedy and a mask of tragedy, is called "The Actor". It is 16 inches (41 cm) tall, weighs over 12 pounds (5.4 kg), is cast in solid bronze, and produced by the American Fine Arts Foundry in Burbank, California.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screen_Actors_Guild_Awards</link></item><item><title>Michael Dobson (actor)</title><description>Michael Dobson (born August 12, 1966) is a British-born Canadian voice actor and voice director, who works for various studios in British Columbia, Canada. He voiced Starscream in the Transformers Unicron Trilogy (Armada, Energon, and Cybertron), Supreme Kai and Nappa in the Ocean dub of Dragon Ball Z, Cobra Commander in G.I. Joe: Spy Troops and G.I. Joe: Valor vs. Venom, Blob in X-Men: Evolution, Leonardo in Ninja Turtles: The Next Mutation, Big Ears in Make Way for Noddy, Bulk Biceps in My Little Pony: Friendship Is Magic, Bull Dog in Krypto the Superdog, Pythor in Ninjago, and William "Will" Nekton and Captain Hammerhead  in  The Deep.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Dobson_(actor)</link></item><item><title>Benjamin Walker (actor)</title><description>Benjamin Walker Scodelario-Davis (né Davis; born June 21, 1982) is an American actor and stand-up comedian. He starred as Andrew Jackson in the musical Bloody Bloody Andrew Jackson, which premiered on Broadway in 2010. He has appeared in a number of Broadway productions, notably as Patrick Bateman in the 2016 musical adaptation of the novel American Psycho and as Chris Keller in the 2019 revival of All My Sons, for which he was nominated for a Tony Award for Best Featured Actor. On screen, he is known for his title role in the 2012 film Abraham Lincoln: Vampire Hunter, as well as his appearances in the films Kinsey, Flags of Our Fathers, and In the Heart of the Sea. In 2019, he starred as Erik Gelden in the third and final season of Marvel's Jessica Jones from Netflix. He plays the High King of the Ñoldorin Elves Ereinion Gil-galad in the Amazon Prime Video series The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benjamin_Walker_(actor)</link></item></channel></rss>