<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Arts-Related Events Today</title><link>http://example.com/arts</link><description>RSS feed of arts-related events (artworks, books, other arts) that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>The Books</title><description>The Books were an American-Dutch duo, formed in New York City in 1999, consisting of guitarist and vocalist Nick Zammuto and cellist Paul de Jong. Their music typically incorporated samples of obscure sounds and speech. They released three critically acclaimed albums on the German label Tomlab, and released their fourth studio album, The Way Out, on Temporary Residence Limited in July 2010.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Books</link></item><item><title>List of Nancy Drew books</title><description>The character of Nancy Drew – ghostwritten and credited to the pseudonymous Carolyn Keene – has appeared in a number of series over the years.
620 Nancy Drew books have been published as of August 2025 over thirteen series, as follows:

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Nancy_Drew_books</link></item><item><title>List of Fear Street books</title><description>This is a list of books from the Fear Street book series created and written by R. L. Stine. The first book, The New Girl was published in 1989. Various spin-off series were written, including the Fear Street Sagas and Ghosts of Fear Street. More than 80 million Fear Street books have been sold as of 2003. The books appeared in many bestseller lists, including The New York Times Best Seller list for children, USA Today bestseller list and Publishers Weekly bestseller list, and the series was listed as the bestselling young-adult book series of all time.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Fear_Street_books</link></item><item><title>Martial arts</title><description>Martial arts are codified systems and traditions of combat. They are practiced for a number of reasons ranging from; violent street fighting, self-defense, military and law enforcement; to non-violent exercising, ceremonial, competition; physical, mental, and spiritual development; entertainment; and to preserve the intangible cultural heritage of a nation. The term "martial arts" was originally used to refer to the traditions of East Asia, but has subsequently been applied to other practices which originated outside that region.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Martial_arts</link></item></channel></rss>