<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Arts-Related Events Today</title><link>http://example.com/arts</link><description>RSS feed of arts-related events (artworks, books, other arts) that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>List of Animorphs books</title><description>This is a list of all books in the Animorphs series by K. A. Applegate. For a list of authors who ghostwrote much of this series using Applegate's name, see Animorphs ยง Ghostwriters.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Animorphs_books</link></item><item><title>List of Star Wars books</title><description>Star Wars is an American epic space-opera media franchise, centered on a film series created by George Lucas that includes Star Wars (1977), The Empire Strikes Back (1980), and Return of the Jedi (1983). The series depicts the adventures of various characters "a long time ago in a galaxy far, far away". Many derivative Star Wars works have been produced in conjunction with, between, and after the original trilogy of films, and later installments. This body of work was collectively known as the Star Wars Expanded Universe for decades.
In October 2012, The Walt Disney Company acquired Lucasfilm for $4.06 billion. In April 2014, Lucasfilm rebranded the Expanded Universe material as Star Wars Legends and declared it non-canon to the Star Wars franchise. The company's focus would be shifted towards a restructured Star Wars canon based on new material. The first new canon adult novel was Star Wars: A New Dawn by John Jackson Miller, published in September 2014.
This is a list of original novels, novel adaptations, original junior novels, junior novel adaptations, young readers, and short stories in the Star Wars franchise. This list does not include journals, graphic novels or comic books, which can be found in the list of Star Wars comic books. Reference books and roleplaying gamebooks can be found at the list of Star Wars reference books.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Star_Wars_books</link></item><item><title>Electronic Arts</title><description>Electronic art is a form of art that makes use of electronic media. More broadly, it refers to technology and/or electronic media. It is related to information art, new media art, video art, digital art, interactive art, internet art, and electronic music. It is considered an outgrowth of conceptual art and systems art.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_art</link></item></channel></rss>