<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Arts-Related Events Today</title><link>http://example.com/arts</link><description>RSS feed of arts-related events (artworks, books, other arts) that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>The Books</title><description>The Books were an American-Dutch duo, formed in New York City in 1999, consisting of guitarist and vocalist Nick Zammuto and cellist Paul de Jong. Their music typically incorporated samples of obscure sounds and speech. They released three critically acclaimed albums on the German label Tomlab, and released their fourth studio album, The Way Out, on Temporary Residence Limited in July 2010.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Books</link></item><item><title>List of Animorphs books</title><description>This is a list of all books in the Animorphs series by K. A. Applegate. For a list of authors who ghostwrote much of this series using Applegate's name, see Animorphs ยง Ghostwriters.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Animorphs_books</link></item><item><title>List of Fear Street books</title><description>This is a list of books from the Fear Street book series created and written by R. L. Stine. The first book, The New Girl was published in 1989. Various spin-off series were written, including the Fear Street Sagas and Ghosts of Fear Street. More than 80 million Fear Street books have been sold as of 2003. The books appeared in many bestseller lists, including The New York Times Best Seller list for children, USA Today bestseller list and Publishers Weekly bestseller list, and the series was listed as the bestselling young-adult book series of all time.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Fear_Street_books</link></item><item><title>Electronic Arts</title><description>Electronic art is a form of art that makes use of electronic media. More broadly, it refers to technology and/or electronic media. It is related to information art, new media art, video art, digital art, interactive art, internet art, and electronic music. It is considered an outgrowth of conceptual art and systems art.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_art</link></item></channel></rss>