<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Arts-Related Events Today</title><link>http://example.com/arts</link><description>RSS feed of arts-related events (artworks, books, other arts) that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>List of Goosebumps books</title><description>This is a list of books from the Goosebumps book series written by R. L. Stine and published by Scholastic. The first book, Welcome to Dead House, was published in July 1992. Numerous spin-off series were written by Stine, including Goosebumps Series 2000 (published from 1998 to 2000), Goosebumps Gold (which was never released), Give Yourself Goosebumps (1995 to 2000), Goosebumps HorrorLand (2008 to 2012), Goosebumps Most Wanted (2012 to 2016) and Goosebumps Slappyworld (2017 to 2023). More than 400 million Goosebumps books have been sold, making it the best-selling series of all time for several years. At one point, Goosebumps sold 4 million books a month. A film based on the books was released on October 16, 2015.
A new book series called Goosebumps House of Shivers set after Slappyworld started in September 2023.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Goosebumps_books</link></item><item><title>List of best-selling books</title><description>This page provides lists of best-selling books and book series to date and in any language. "Best-selling" refers to the estimated number of copies sold of each book, rather than the number of books printed or currently owned. Comics and textbooks are not included in this list. The books are listed according to the highest sales estimate as reported in reliable, independent sources.
According to Guinness World Records as of 1995, the Bible is the best sold book of all time with an estimated 5 billion copies sold and distributed. Sales estimates for other printed religious texts include at least 800 million copies for the Qur'an and 190 million copies for the Book of Mormon. Also, a single publisher has produced more than 140 million copies of the Bhagavad Gita. The total number could be much higher. Among non-religious texts, the Quotations from Chairman Mao Tse-tung, also known as the Little Red Book, has produced a wide array of sales and distribution figures—with estimates ranging from 800 million to over 6.5 billion printed volumes. Some claim the distribution ran into the "billions" and some cite "over a billion" official volumes between 1966 and 1969 alone as well as "untold numbers of unofficial local reprints and unofficial translations". Exact print figures for these and other books may also be missing or unreliable since these kinds of books may be produced by many different and unrelated publishers, in some cases over many centuries. All books of a religious, ideological, philosophical or political nature have thus been excluded from the lists of best-selling books below for these reasons.
Many books lack comprehensive sales figures as book selling and reselling figures prior to the introduction of point of sale equipment was based on the estimates of book sellers, publishers or the authors themselves. For example, one of the one volume Harper Collins editions of The Lord of the Rings was recorded to have sold only 967,466 copies in the UK by 2009 (the source does not cite the start date), but at the same time the author's estate claimed global sales figures of in excess of 150 million. Accurate figures are only available from the 1990s and in western nations such as US, UK, Canada and Australia, although figures from the US are available from the 1940s. Further, e-books have not been included as out of copyright texts are often available free in this format. Examples of books with claimed high sales include The Count of Monte Cristo by Alexandre Dumas, Don Quixote by Miguel de Cervantes, Journey to the West by Wu Cheng'en and The Lord of the Rings (which has been sold as both a three volume series, The Fellowship of the Ring, The Two Towers, and The Return of the King, as a single combined volume and as a six volume set in a slipcase) by J. R. R. Tolkien. Hence, in cases where there is too much uncertainty, they are excluded from the list.
Having sold more than 600 million copies worldwide, Harry Potter by J. K. Rowling is the best-selling book series in history. The first novel in the series, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone, has sold in excess of 120 million copies, making it one of the best-selling books of all time. As of June 2017, the series has been translated into 85 languages, placing Harry Potter among history's most translated literary works. The last four books in the series consecutively set records as the fastest-selling books of all time, and the final installment, Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows, sold roughly fifteen million copies worldwide within twenty-four hours of its release. With twelve million books printed in the first US run, it also holds the record for the highest initial print run for any book in history.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_best-selling_books</link></item><item><title>Detroit Institute of Arts</title><description>The Detroit Institute of Arts (DIA) is a museum institution located in Midtown Detroit, Michigan. It has one of the largest and most significant art collections in the United States. With over 100 galleries, it covers 658,000 square feet (61,100 m2) with a major renovation and expansion project completed in 2007 that added 58,000 square feet (5,400 m2). The DIA collection is regarded as among the top six museums in the United States with an encyclopedic collection which spans the globe from ancient Egyptian and European works to contemporary art. Its art collection is valued in billions of dollars, up to $8.1 billion USD according to a 2014 appraisal. The DIA campus is located in Detroit's Cultural Center Historic District, about 2 miles (3.2 km) north of the downtown area, across from the Detroit Public Library near Wayne State University.
The museum building is highly regarded by architects. The original building, designed by Paul Philippe Cret, is flanked by north and south wings with the white marble as the main exterior material for the entire structure. The campus is part of the city's Cultural Center Historic District listed in the National Register of Historic Places. The museum's first painting was donated in 1883 and its collection consists of over 65,000 works. With about 677,500 visitors annually for 2015, the DIA is among the most visited art museums in the world. The Detroit Institute of Arts hosts major art exhibitions; it contains a 1,150-seat theatre designed by architect C. Howard Crane, a 380-seat hall for recitals and lectures, an art reference library, and a conservation services laboratory.
In 2023, readers of USA Today voted the Detroit Institute of Arts the No. 1 art museum in the United States.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Detroit_Institute_of_Arts</link></item><item><title>Electronic Arts</title><description>Electronic art is a form of art that makes use of electronic media. More broadly, it refers to technology and/or electronic media. It is related to information art, new media art, video art, digital art, interactive art, internet art, and electronic music. It is considered an outgrowth of conceptual art and systems art.

The term electronic art is almost synonymous to computer art and digital art. The latter two terms, and especially the term computer-generated art are mostly used for visual artworks generated by computers. However, electronic art has a much broader connotation, referring to artworks that include any type of electronic component, such as works in music, dance, architecture and performance. It is an interdisciplinary field in which artists, scientists and engineers often collaborate when creating their works. The art historian of electronic art Edward A. Shanken works to document current and past experimental art with a focus on the intersection of art, science, and technology. Other writers on the topic of electronic art include Frank Popper, Dominique Moulon, Sarah Cook, and Christiane Paul. 
Electronic art often features components of interactivity.  Artists make use of technologies like the Internet, computer networks, robotics, wearable technology, digital painting, wireless technology and immersive virtual reality. As the technologies used to deliver works of electronic art become obsolete, electronic art faces serious issues around the challenge to preserve artwork beyond the time of its contemporary production. Currently, research projects are underway to improve the preservation and documentation of the fragile electronic arts heritage (see DOCAM – Documentation and Conservation of the Media Arts Heritage). Digital graphics software such as Photoshop allows for the digital manipulation of analog photographs, the creation of wholly electronic images, and application of AI-enhanced generative fills. 

With the advancements in lightweight microchips, wireless capabilities, sensors and motion tracking technology, new mediums in digital art and performance have become possible. Technology has the capability to augment and manipulate reality as well as audience or viewer perception. Motion tracking suits are used in creating 3D renders of animated characters for film and video games. The animation or CGI produced can be edited and adjusted before viewing, but research into real time rendering for live performance art is being streamlined through the use of artificial intelligence, automation, and programing. Live renders are similarly used in the metaverse to create more realistic avatar movement and expression. Further implications of wearable technology include audio and music production. Laurie Anderson is a performance artist who used a suit equipped with amplified tactile sensors. She used her movements to create music, as various body parts were assigned different percussive or instrumental sounds and tones when hit or moved. Similar to this musical tech is the SOMI-1 device as used in the dance performance entitled “My body is an instrument” by: Mike Tyus and Luca Renzi.  This piece of technology was designed by the company Instrument of Things; the SOMI-1 is a small proprioceptive disk that tracks movement and translates it into sound.  

International Symposium for Electronic Art (ISEA), organized annually since 1988, international
Ars Electronica Symposium, organized yearly since 1979 by Ars Electronica in Linz, Austria
Dutch Electronic Art Festival (DEAF), organized yearly since 1994 by V2 Institute for the Unstable Media in Rotterdam, the Netherlands
Electronic Language International Festival (FILE) organized yearly since 2000 in São Paulo, Brazil
The Prix Ars Electronica, a major yearly award for several categories of electronic art

Notable artists working in electronic art include:

Nicolas Bourriaud, Relational Aesthetics, Dijon: Les Presses du Réel, 2002, orig. 1997
Paul Brown, Charlie Gere, Nicholas Lambert, Catherine Mason (eds.), White Heat Cold Logic: British Computer Art 1960–1980, Cambridge, MA: The MIT Press, 2006
Christine Buci-Glucksmann, "L’art à l’époque du virtuel", in Frontières esthétiques de l’art, Arts 8, Paris: L’Harmattan, 2004
Frank Popper, Art of the Electronic Age, Thames &amp; Hudson, 1997
Joline Blais and Jon Ippolito, At the Edge of Art, Thames &amp; Hudson, 2006
Charlie Gere, Digital Culture, Reaktion, 2002.  ISBN 978-1-86189-143-3
Oliver Grau (2003). Virtual Art: From Illusion to Immersion (Leonardo Book Series). Cambridge, Massachusetts: The MIT Press/Leonardo Books. ISBN 0-262-07241-6.
Oliver Grau (Ed.): Media Art Histories, MIT Press/Leonardo Books, 2007.
Mark Hansen, New Philosophy for New Media, Cambridge, MA: The MIT Press, 2004
Norman M. Klein, "Spaces Between: Traveling Through Bleeds, Apertures, and Wormholes Inside the Database Novel," in Third Person: Authoring and Exploring Vast Narratives, Pat Harrigan and Noah Wardip-Fruin (eds.), Cambridge, MA: The MIT Press, 2009
Donald Kuspit "Del Atre Analogico al Arte Digital" in Arte Digital Y Videoarte, Kuspit, D. (ed.), Consorcio del Circulo de Bellas Artes, Madrid, pp. 33–34 &amp; 3 color images
Donald Kuspit, The Matrix of Sensations, VI: Digital Artists and the New Creative Renaissance
Alan Liu, The Laws of Cool: Knowledge Work and the Culture of Information, The University of Chicago Press, pp. 331–336 &amp; 485–486
Dominic McIver Lopes, A Philosophy of Computer Art, London: Routledge, 2009
Lev Manovich, The Language of New Media, Cambridge, Massachusetts: The MIT Press/Leonardo Books, 2001. ISBN 0-262-63255-1
Lev Manovich, Ten Key Texts on Digital Art: 1970–2000, Leonardo, Volume 35, Number 5, October 2002, pp. 567–569
Yucef Merhi, Artists' Fellowship – 2009 Digital/Electronic Arts, New York Foundation for the Arts, 2009
Robert C. Morgan Digital Hybrids, art press, Volume 255
Christiane Paul, Digital Art, Thames &amp; Hudson
Frank Popper, From Technological to Virtual Art, The MIT Press/Leonardo Books, 2007
Frank Popper, Origins and Development of Kinetic Art, Studio Vista and New York Graphic Society, 1968
Frank Popper, Die Kinetische Kunst-Licht und Bewegung, Umweltkunst und Aktion, Dumont Schauberg, 1975
Frank Popper, Le Déclin de l'objet, Le Chêne, 1975
Dick Higgins, Intermedia, 1966. Reprinted in Donna De Salvo (ed.), Open Systems Rethinking Art c. 1970, London: Tate Publishing, 2005
Margot Lovejoy, Digital Currents: Art in the Electronic Age, Routledge, 2004
Frank Popper, Art—Action and Participation, New York University Press, 1975
Frank Popper, Origins and Development of Kinetic Art, New York Graphic Society/Studio Vista, 1968
Frank Popper, Réflexions sur l'exil, l'art et l'Europe : Entretiens avec Aline Dallier, Klincksieck, 1998
Frank Popper, Ecrire sur l'art : De l'art optique a l'art virtuel, L'Harmattan, 2007
Fred Forest, Art et Internet, Editions Cercle D'Art / Imaginaire Mode d'Emploi
Sarah J. Rogers (ed.), Body Mécanique: Artistic Explorations of Digital Realms, Columbus, Ohio, Wexner Center for the Arts, The Ohio State University, 1998* Edward A. Shanken Selected Writings on Art and Technology http://artexetra.com
Edward A. Shanken Art and Electronic Media. London: Phaidon, 2009. ISBN 978-0-7148-4782-5
Rainer Usselmann, The Dilemma of Media Art: Cybernetic Serendipity at the ICA London. Archived 2016-03-04 at the Wayback Machine, Cambridge, Massachusetts: The MIT Press/Leonardo Journal,  Volume 36, Number 5, October 2003, pp. 389–396
Bruce Wands, Art of the Digital Age, London: Thames &amp; Hudson, 2006. ISBN 978-0500238172

Stephen Wilson: extensive list of "information arts" links
newArteest, list of prominent digital artists
New Media Art book (wiki edition)</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_art</link></item><item><title>Mixed martial arts</title><description>Mixed martial arts (MMA) is a full-contact combat sport based on striking, grappling and ground fighting, incorporating techniques from various combat sports from around the world. The first documented use of the term mixed martial arts was in a review of UFC 1 by television critic Howard Rosenberg in 1993.
During the early 20th century, various interstylistic contests took place throughout Japan and in the countries of the East Asia. At the same time, in Brazil, there was a phenomenon called vale tudo, which became known for unrestricted fights between various styles such as judo/Brazilian jiu-jitsu, catch wrestling/luta livre, Muay Thai, and capoeira. Another precursor to modern MMA was the 1976 Ali vs. Inoki exhibition bout (which ended in a draw after 15 rounds), fought between boxer Muhammad Ali and wrestler Antonio Inoki in Japan, where it later inspired the foundation of Shooto in 1985, Pancrase in 1993, and the Pride Fighting Championships in 1997.
In the 1990s, the Gracie family brought their Brazilian jiu-jitsu style, first developed in Brazil from the 1920s, to the United States – which culminated in the founding of the Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) promotion company in 1993. The company held an event with almost no rules, mostly due to the influence of Art Davie and Rorion Gracie attempting to replicate vale tudo fights that existed in Brazil and would later implement a different set of rules (example: eliminating kicking a grounded opponent), which differed from other leagues which were more in favour of realistic, street-like fights.
Originally promoted as a competition to find the most effective martial arts for real unarmed combat, competitors from different fighting styles were pitted against one another in contests with relatively few rules. Later, individual fighters incorporated multiple martial arts into their style. MMA promoters were pressured to adopt additional rules to increase competitors' safety, to comply with sport regulations and to broaden mainstream acceptance of the sport. Following these changes, the sport has seen increased popularity with a pay-per-view business that rivals boxing and professional wrestling.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mixed_martial_arts</link></item></channel></rss>