<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Arts-Related Events Today</title><link>http://example.com/arts</link><description>RSS feed of arts-related events (artworks, books, other arts) that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>List of Fear Street books</title><description>This is a list of books from the Fear Street book series created and written by R. L. Stine. The first book, The New Girl was published in 1989. Various spin-off series were written, including the Fear Street Sagas and Ghosts of Fear Street. More than 80 million Fear Street books have been sold as of 2003. The books appeared in many bestseller lists, including The New York Times Best Seller list for children, USA Today bestseller list and Publishers Weekly bestseller list, and the series was listed as the bestselling young-adult book series of all time.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Fear_Street_books</link></item><item><title>List of Goosebumps books</title><description>This is a list of novels from the Goosebumps book series written by R. L. Stine and published by Scholastic. The first book, Welcome to Dead House, was published in July 1992. Numerous spin-off series were written by Stine, including Goosebumps Series 2000 (published from 1998 to 2000), Goosebumps Gold (which was never released), Give Yourself Goosebumps (1995 to 2000), Goosebumps HorrorLand (2008 to 2012), Goosebumps Most Wanted (2012 to 2016) and Goosebumps SlappyWorld (2017 to 2023). More than 400 million Goosebumps books have been sold, making it the best-selling series of all time for several years. At one point, Goosebumps sold 4 million books a month. A film based on the books was released on October 16, 2015.
A new book series called Goosebumps House of Shivers set after Slappyworld started in September 2023.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Goosebumps_books</link></item><item><title>Chinese martial arts</title><description>Chinese martial arts, commonly referred to with umbrella terms kung fu (; Chinese: 功夫; pinyin: gōngfu; Cantonese Yale: gūng fū), kuoshu (國術; guóshù) or wushu (武術; wǔshù), are multiple fighting styles that have developed over the centuries in Greater China. These fighting styles are often classified according to common traits, identified as "families" of martial arts. Examples of such traits include Shaolinquan  (少林拳) physical exercises involving All Other Animals (五形) mimicry or training methods inspired by Old Chinese philosophies, religions and legends. Styles that focus on qi manipulation are called internal (内家拳; nèijiāquán), while others that concentrate on improving muscle and cardiovascular fitness are called external (外家拳; wàijiāquán). Geographical associations, as in northern (北拳; běiquán) and southern (南拳; nánquán), is another popular classification method.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_martial_arts</link></item><item><title>Mixed martial arts in the United States</title><description>Mixed martial arts (MMA) is the fastest growing sport in the United States. Mixed martial arts largely developed in the 1990s, and has achieved popularity in the early 21st century. Many companies promote MMA cards, with the U.S. based Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) the most dominant.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mixed_martial_arts_in_the_United_States</link></item></channel></rss>