<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Famous Explorations on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/explorations</link><description>RSS feed of famous explorations that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>The Exploration Company</title><description>The Exploration Company (TEC) is a European aerospace company developing reusable spacecraft. Founded in 2021, TEC is headquartered in Munich and Bordeaux, with additional offices in Italy, the United States (in Houston) and the MENA region. The company embraces a pan-European identity.
TEC’s main project is developing Nyx, a family of modular, reusable spacecraft designed for missions to Low Earth Orbit (LEO), lunar orbit, and the Moon. Its vehicles aim to serve cargo transport, re-entry missions, and future human spaceflight needs.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Exploration_Company</link></item><item><title>Exploration of Mars</title><description>The planet Mars has been explored remotely by spacecraft. Probes sent from Earth, beginning in the late 20th century, have yielded a large increase in knowledge about the Martian system, focused primarily on understanding its geology and habitability potential. Engineering interplanetary journeys is complicated and the exploration of Mars has experienced a high failure rate, especially the early attempts. Roughly sixty percent of all spacecraft destined for Mars failed before completing their missions, with some failing before their observations could begin. Some missions have been met with unexpected success, such as the twin Mars Exploration Rovers, Spirit and Opportunity, which operated for years beyond their specification.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration_of_Mars</link></item><item><title>Exploration Park</title><description>Exploration Park is a partnership formed in 2011 between NASA's Kennedy Space Center (KSC) and Space Florida. There are 299 Acres on KSC property, but outside the NASA badge controlled area.
As of March 2016, companies have the opportunity to lease office or research facilities, or build their own facilities.  The park is aimed at research and development, office, and light manufacturing commercial activities.
The leased land and agreement with Space Florida is a part of the NASA's efforts to "grow and deploy commercial space capabilities."

Space Life Sciences Lab is a major facility on site
CASIS is located at KSC in the Space Life Sciences Lab (SLSL) which is a founding element (in 2011) of the Exploration Park initiative
Blue Origin broke ground on a new rocket manufacturing facility in Exploration Park in June 2016.
OneWeb is building a satellite manufacturing facility onsite.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration_Park</link></item><item><title>Criticism of space exploration</title><description>Human space exploration has been criticized on several grounds. Opponents point to the substantial financial costs, suggesting that funds allocated for space exploration could be better spent addressing urgent issues on Earth, such as poverty, healthcare, education, and environmental degradation. Critics express concerns about risks to human life, environmental impacts like potential contamination of celestial bodies, and the possibility of militarizing space, which could exacerbate geopolitical tensions. These critiques reflect ongoing debates over resource allocation, technological priorities, and the responsibilities of humanity both on Earth and in outer space.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Criticism_of_space_exploration</link></item></channel></rss>