<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Famous Explorations on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/explorations</link><description>RSS feed of famous explorations that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Exploration of Mars</title><description>The planet Mars has been explored remotely by spacecraft. Probes sent from Earth, beginning in the late 20th century, have yielded a large increase in knowledge about the Martian system, focused primarily on understanding its geology and habitability potential. Engineering interplanetary journeys is complicated and the exploration of Mars has experienced a high failure rate, especially the early attempts. Roughly sixty percent of all spacecraft destined for Mars failed before completing their missions, with some failing before their observations could begin. Some missions have been met with unexpected success, such as the twin Mars Exploration Rovers, Spirit and Opportunity, which operated for years beyond their specification.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration_of_Mars</link></item><item><title>The Exploration Company</title><description>The Exploration Company (TEC) is a European aerospace company developing reusable spacecraft and space logistics solutions to advance sustainable exploration beyond Earth. Founded in 2021, TEC is headquartered in Munich and Bordeaux, with additional offices in Italy, the United States (in Houston) and the MENA region. The company embraces a pan-European identity.
TEC’s main project is developing Nyx, a family of modular, reusable spacecraft designed for missions to Low Earth Orbit (LEO), lunar orbit, and the Moon. Its vehicles aim to serve cargo transport, re-entry missions, and future human spaceflight needs.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Exploration_Company</link></item><item><title>Timeline of Solar System exploration</title><description>This is a timeline of Solar System exploration ordering events in the exploration of the Solar System by date of spacecraft launch.
It includes:

All spacecraft that have left Earth orbit for the purposes of Solar System exploration (or were launched with that intention but failed), including lunar probes.
A small number of pioneering or notable Earth-orbiting craft.
It does not include:

Centuries of terrestrial telescopic observation.
The great majority of Earth-orbiting satellites.
Space probes leaving Earth orbit that are not concerned with Solar System exploration (such as space telescopes targeted at distant galaxies, cosmic background radiation observatories, and so on).
Probes that failed at launch.
The dates listed are launch dates, but the achievements noted may have occurred some time later—in some cases, a considerable time later (for example, Voyager 2, launched 20 August 1977, did not reach Neptune until 1989).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_Solar_System_exploration</link></item><item><title>Metamaterials: Physics and Engineering Explorations</title><description>Metamaterials: Physics and Engineering Explorations  is a book length introduction to the fundamental research and advancements in electromagnetic composite substances known as electromagnetic metamaterials. The discussion encompasses examination of the physics of metamaterial interactions, the designs, and the perspectives of engineering regarding these materials. Also included  throughout the book are potential applications, which are discussed at various points in each section of each chapter.  The book encompasses a variety of theoretical, numerical, and experimental perspectives.
This book has been cited by a few hundred other peer-reviewed research efforts, mostly peer-reviewed science articles.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metamaterials:_Physics_and_Engineering_Explorations</link></item><item><title>Portuguese maritime exploration</title><description>Portuguese maritime explorations resulted in numerous territories and maritime routes recorded by the Portuguese on journeys during the 15th and 16th centuries. Portuguese sailors were at the vanguard of European exploration, chronicling and mapping the coasts of Africa and Asia, then known as the East Indies, Canada and Brazil (the West Indies), in what became known as the Age of Discovery. 
Methodical expeditions started in 1419 along the coast of West Africa under the sponsorship of prince Henry the Navigator, whence Bartolomeu Dias reached the Cape of Good Hope and entered the Indian Ocean in 1488. Ten years later, in 1498, Vasco da Gama led the first fleet around Africa to the Indian subcontinent, arriving in Calicut and starting a maritime route from Portugal to India. Portuguese explorations then proceeded to southeast Asia, where they reached Japan in 1542, forty-four years after their first arrival in India. In 1500, the Portuguese nobleman Pedro Álvares Cabral became the first European to discover Brazil.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portuguese_maritime_exploration</link></item><item><title>Exploration–exploitation dilemma</title><description>The exploration–exploitation dilemma, also known as the explore–exploit tradeoff, is a fundamental concept in decision-making that arises in many domains. It is depicted as the balancing act between two opposing strategies. Exploitation involves choosing the best option based on current knowledge of the system (which may be incomplete or misleading), while exploration involves trying out new options that may lead to better outcomes in the future at the expense of an exploitation opportunity. Finding the optimal balance between these two strategies is a crucial challenge in many decision-making problems whose goal is to maximize long-term benefits.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration%E2%80%93exploitation_dilemma</link></item><item><title>Timeline of space exploration</title><description>This is a timeline of space exploration which includes notable achievements, first accomplishments and milestones in humanity's exploration of outer space.
This timeline generally does not distinguish achievements by a specific country or private company, as it considers humanity as a whole. See otherwise the timeline of private spaceflight or look for achievements by each space agency.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_space_exploration</link></item></channel></rss>