<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Famous Explorations on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/explorations</link><description>RSS feed of famous explorations that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Exploration of Mars</title><description>The planet Mars has been explored remotely by spacecraft. Probes sent from Earth, beginning in the late 20th century, have yielded a large increase in knowledge about the Martian system, focused primarily on understanding its geology and habitability potential. Engineering interplanetary journeys is complicated and the exploration of Mars has experienced a high failure rate, especially the early attempts. Roughly sixty percent of all spacecraft destined for Mars failed before completing their missions, with some failing before their observations could begin. Some missions have been met with unexpected success, such as the twin Mars Exploration Rovers, Spirit and Opportunity, which operated for years beyond their specification.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration_of_Mars</link></item><item><title>Timeline of space exploration</title><description>This is a timeline of space exploration which includes notable missions, achievements, first accomplishments and milestones in humanity's exploration of outer space.
This timeline generally does not distinguish achievements by a specific country or private company, as it considers humanity as a whole. See otherwise the timeline of private spaceflight or look for achievements by each space agency.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_space_exploration</link></item><item><title>The Exploration Company</title><description>The Exploration Company (TEC) is a European aerospace company developing reusable spacecraft. TEC is headquartered in Munich, Bordeaux, and Oberpfaffenhofen with additional offices in Italy, France, Houston (US), and the MENA region. The company embraces a pan-European identity. The Exploration Company was founded in July 2021 by Hélène Huby (CEO) with a group of space engineers who had worked together on European space programs at Airbus and ArianeGroup, including Orion-ESM and ATV. TEC's main project is developing Nyx, a family of modular, reusable spacecraft designed for missions to Low Earth Orbit (LEO), lunar orbit, and the Moon. Its vehicles aim to serve cargo transport, re-entry missions, and future human spaceflight needs.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Exploration_Company</link></item><item><title>Exploration of North America</title><description>European powers employed sailors and geographers to map and explore North America with the goal of economic, religious and military expansion. The combative and rapid nature of this exploration is the result of a series of countering actions by neighboring European nations to ensure no single country had garnered enough wealth and power from the Americas to militarily tip the scales over on the European continent.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration_of_North_America</link></item><item><title>Exploration of Mercury</title><description>The exploration of Mercury has long had a minor role in the space interests of the world. It is the least explored inner planet. As of 2025, the Mariner 10, MESSENGER, and BepiColombo missions have been the only spacecraft that have made close observations of Mercury. MESSENGER made three flybys before entering orbit around Mercury. BepiColombo, a joint mission between the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA) and the European Space Agency, is to deliver two probes into Mercury orbit in 2026, having previously made six flybys of the tiny planet. MESSENGER and BepiColombo are intended to gather complementary data to help scientists understand many of the mysteries discovered by Mariner 10's flybys.
Compared to other planets, Mercury is difficult to explore. The speed required to reach it is relatively high, and its proximity to the Sun makes it difficult to maneuver a spacecraft into a stable orbit around it. As a result, all spacecraft sent to visit Mercury as of 2025 have required a complex trajectory of gravity assists, highly efficient ion propulsion, or both. The thermal environment around Mercury is also challenging, with probes utilizing sunshields, specially designed materials, or radiators to survive the heat so close to the Sun.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration_of_Mercury</link></item></channel></rss>