<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Famous Explorations on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/explorations</link><description>RSS feed of famous explorations that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Age of Discovery</title><description>The Age of Discovery (c. 1418 – c. 1620), also known as the Age of Exploration, was part of the early modern period and overlapped with the Age of Sail. It was a period from approximately the 15th to the 17th century, during which seafarers from European countries explored, colonized, and conquered regions across the globe. The Age of Discovery was a transformative period when previously isolated parts of the world became connected to form the world-system, and laid the groundwork for globalization. The extensive overseas exploration, particularly the opening of maritime routes to the East Indies and European colonization of the Americas by the Spanish and Portuguese, later joined by the English, French and Dutch, spurred international global trade. The interconnected global economy of the 21st century has its origins in the expansion of trade networks during this era.
The exploration created colonial empires and marked an increased adoption of colonialism as a government policy in several European states. As such, it is sometimes synonymous with the first wave of European colonization. This colonization reshaped power dynamics causing geopolitical shifts in Europe and creating new centers of power beyond Europe. Having set human history on the global common course, the legacy of the Age still shapes the world today.
European oceanic exploration started with the maritime expeditions of Portugal to the Canary Islands in 1336, and with the Portuguese discoveries of the Atlantic archipelagos of Madeira and Azores, the coast of West Africa in 1434, and the establishment of the sea route to India in 1498 by Vasco da Gama, which initiated the Portuguese maritime and trade presence in Kerala and the Indian Ocean. Spain sponsored and financed the transatlantic voyages of Christopher Columbus, which from 1492 to 1504 marked the start of colonization in the Americas, and the expedition of the Portuguese explorer Ferdinand Magellan to open a route from the Atlantic to the Pacific, which later achieved the first circumnavigation of the globe between 1519 and 1522. These Spanish expeditions significantly impacted European perceptions of the world. These discoveries led to numerous naval expeditions across the Atlantic, Indian, and Pacific Oceans, and land expeditions in the Americas, Asia, Africa, and Australia that continued into the 19th century, followed by Polar exploration in the 20th century.
European exploration initiated the Columbian exchange between the Old World (Europe, Asia, and Africa) and New World (Americas). This exchange involved the transfer of plants, animals, human populations (including slaves), communicable diseases, and culture across the Eastern and Western Hemispheres. The Age of Discovery and European exploration involved mapping the world, shaping a new worldview and facilitating contact with distant civilizations. The continents drawn by European mapmakers developed from abstract "blobs" into the outlines more recognizable to us. Simultaneously, the spread of new diseases, especially affecting American Indians, led to rapid declines in some populations. The era saw widespread enslavement, exploitation and military conquest of indigenous peoples, concurrent with the growing economic influence and spread of Western culture, science and technology leading to a faster-than-exponential population growth world-wide.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Age_of_Discovery</link></item><item><title>Deep space exploration</title><description>Deep-space exploration is the branch of astronomy, astronautics, and space technology that is involved with exploring the distant regions of outer space. However, little consensus has been reached on the meaning of "distant" regions. In some contexts, it is used to refer to interstellar space. The International Telecommunication Union defines deep space to start at a distance of 2 million km (1.2 million mi) (about 0.01 AU) from Earth's surface. NASA's Deep Space Network has variously used criteria of 16,000–32,000 km (9,900–19,900 mi) from Earth. Physical exploration of space is conducted both by human spaceflights (deep-space astronautics) and by robotic spacecraft.
At present the farthest space probe humankind has constructed and launched from Earth is Voyager 1, which was announced on December 5, 2011, to have reached the outer edge of the Solar System, and entered interstellar space on August 25, 2012. Deep space exploration further than this vessel's capacity is not yet possible due to limitations in the propulsion technology currently available.
Some of the best candidates for future deep space engine technologies include nuclear fusion propulsion, laser/maser propulsion,  and antimatter. The latter, beamed propulsion, appears to be the best candidate for deep space exploration presently available, since it uses known physics and known technology that is being developed for other purposes.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_space_exploration</link></item><item><title>The Exploration Company</title><description>The Exploration Company (TEC) is a European aerospace company developing reusable spacecraft and space logistics solutions to advance sustainable exploration beyond Earth. Founded in 2021, TEC is headquartered in Munich and Bordeaux, with additional offices in Italy, the United States (in Houston) and the MENA region. The company embraces a pan-European identity, uniting expertise across the continent to strengthen Europe's role in the global space economy.
TEC’s flagship project is Nyx, a family of modular, reusable spacecraft designed for missions to Low Earth Orbit (LEO), the Moon, and beyond. Its vehicles aim to serve cargo transport, re-entry missions, and future human spaceflight needs.  By focusing on scalable, cost-effective technologies, TEC contributes to Europe's strategic autonomy in space while fostering international collaboration.
Building on Europe’s tradition of cooperation and innovation, TEC operates with a global perspective, maintaining partnerships and offices beyond Europe, including in the United States and other key regions. 
With a mission deeply rooted in European values of unity, progress, and sustainability, TEC is positioning itself as a driving force for the next era of space exploration.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Exploration_Company</link></item><item><title>Exploration of Mars</title><description>The planet Mars has been explored remotely by spacecraft. Probes sent from Earth, beginning in the late 20th century, have yielded a large increase in knowledge about the Martian system, focused primarily on understanding its geology and habitability potential. Engineering interplanetary journeys is complicated and the exploration of Mars has experienced a high failure rate, especially the early attempts. Roughly sixty percent of all spacecraft destined for Mars failed before completing their missions, with some failing before their observations could begin. Some missions have been met with unexpected success, such as the twin Mars Exploration Rovers, Spirit and Opportunity, which operated for years beyond their specification.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration_of_Mars</link></item><item><title>Timeline of space exploration</title><description>This is a timeline of space exploration which includes notable achievements, first accomplishments and milestones in humanity's exploration of outer space.
This timeline generally does not distinguish achievements by a specific country or private company, as it considers humanity as a whole. See otherwise the timeline of private spaceflight or look for achievements by each space agency.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_space_exploration</link></item><item><title>Exploration of North America</title><description>European powers employed sailors and geographers to map and explore North America with the goal of economic, religious and military expansion. The combative and rapid nature of this exploration is the result of a series of countering actions by neighboring European nations to ensure no single country had garnered enough wealth and power from the Americas to militarily tip the scales over on the European continent.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration_of_North_America</link></item></channel></rss>