<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>List of inventors killed by their own invention</title><description>This is a list of people whose deaths were in some manner caused by or directly related to a product, process, procedure, or other technological innovation that they invented or designed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_inventors_killed_by_their_own_invention</link></item><item><title>Four Great Inventions</title><description>The Four Great Inventions are inventions from imperial China that are celebrated in Chinese culture for their historical significance and as symbols of ancient China's advanced science and technology. They are the compass, gunpowder, papermaking and printing.
These four inventions had a profound impact on the development of civilization throughout the world. However, some modern Chinese scholars have opined that other Chinese inventions were perhaps more sophisticated and had a greater impact on Chinese civilization – the Four Great Inventions serve merely to highlight the technological interaction between East and West.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Great_Inventions</link></item><item><title>Invention Secrecy Act</title><description>The Invention Secrecy Act of 1951 (Pub. L. 82–256, 66 Stat. 3, enacted February 1, 1952, codified at 35 U.S.C. ch. 17) is a United States federal law that authorizes the government to suppress disclosure of certain inventions for reasons of national security. The statute empowers selected federal agencies to decide whether a patent application poses a risk and to compel its classification under secrecy orders. In practice, secrecy orders have been imposed not only on inventions affecting military defense but also on those alleged to threaten economic stability, with critics noting that many such restrictions rest on speculative or unproven harms. The law applies broadly to all inventions in the United States for which a patent is filed or granted (35 U.S.C. § 181). Every patent application is reviewed, and thousands of inventions are manually screened each year. Any federal agency with "classifying powers" can order a restriction under the Act.
Secrecy orders can bar public disclosure entirely, prohibit sales to anyone outside the defense sector, block exports, and seal restricted applications as classified. According to reporting in Wired and Slate, the United States Patent and Trademark Office has at times considered applying secrecy orders to inventions deemed disruptive to established industries. Inventors whose work is restricted may petition for compensation, but scholars note that courts have often denied claims on the ground that inventors cannot show "actual damages" while their inventions remain suppressed.
Critics, including attorneys and academics, describe the system as lacking oversight and limiting avenues of appeal. Commentators have likened secrecy orders to uncompensated takings under the Fifth Amendment to the United States Constitution, and legal scholars argue that the regime is "inherently unfair" because inventors are automatically denied a quarter of their patent's assessed value while being unable to prove harm. Historians note that officials manage secrecy orders to avoid judicial precedents on the Act's constitutionality. Other critics contend that secrecy orders chill research, stall economic development, and entrench the military–industrial complex by sidelining independent inventors and dual-use technologies. The statutory rationale in 35 U.S.C. § 181 is that secrecy orders are needed when disclosure "might be detrimental to the national security." Most scholarly commentary has been critical of the regime, though one law review article has argued limited secrecy may be justified in biotechnology patents.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_Secrecy_Act</link></item><item><title>Invention promotion firm</title><description>An invention promotion firm or invention submission corporation provides services to inventors to help them in  develop or market their inventions. These firms may offer to evaluate the patentability of inventions, file patent applications, build prototypes, license them to manufacturers, and otherwise market.  They are distinguished from more conventional consulting firms and law firms offering the same or similar services in that they market their services primarily to amateur inventors through the mass media.
The US government estimates that hundreds of companies offer invention-promotion services and that “virtually all of them are either ineffective or outright fraudulent. One official at the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office says he believes there are fewer than a half-dozen legitimate invention promoters in the country”.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_promotion_firm</link></item><item><title>List of lost inventions</title><description>This is a list of lost inventions - technologies whose capabilities can no longer be produced in their original form. It does not include theoretical inventions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_lost_inventions</link></item><item><title>Proposed directive on the patentability of computer-implemented inventions</title><description>The Proposal for a Directive of the European Parliament and of the Council on the patentability of computer-implemented inventions (Commission proposal COM(2002) 92), procedure number 2002/0047 (COD) was a proposal for a European Union (EU) directive aiming to harmonise national patent laws and practices concerning the granting of patents for computer-implemented inventions, provided they meet certain criteria. The European Patent Office describes a computer-implemented invention (CII) as "one which involves the use of a computer, computer network or other programmable apparatus, where one or more features are realised wholly or partly by means of a computer program".
The proposal became a major focus for conflict between those who regarded the proposed directive as a way to codify the case law of the Boards of Appeal of the European Patent Office (unrelated to the EU institutions) in the sphere of computing, and those who asserted that the directive is an extension of the patentability sphere, not just a harmonisation, that ideas are not patentable and that the expression of those ideas is already adequately protected by the law of copyright.
Following several years of debate and numerous conflicting amendments to the proposal, the proposal was rejected on 6 July 2005 by the European Parliament by an overwhelming majority of 648 to 14 votes.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proposed_directive_on_the_patentability_of_computer-implemented_inventions</link></item></channel></rss>