<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>List of inventors killed by their own invention</title><description>This is a list of people whose deaths were in some manner caused by or directly related to a product, process, procedure, or other technological innovation that they invented or designed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_inventors_killed_by_their_own_invention</link></item><item><title>Four Great Inventions</title><description>The Four Great Inventions are inventions from imperial China that are celebrated in Chinese culture for their historical significance and as symbols of ancient China's advanced science and technology. They are the compass, gunpowder, papermaking and printing.
These four inventions had a profound impact on the development of civilization throughout the world. However, some modern Chinese scholars have opined that other Chinese inventions were perhaps more sophisticated and had a greater impact on Chinese civilization – the Four Great Inventions serve merely to highlight the technological interaction between East and West.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Great_Inventions</link></item><item><title>2 and 3 Part Inventions</title><description>2 and 3 Part Inventions is a ballet made by New York City Ballet ballet master Jerome Robbins on students at its affiliated school, the School of American Ballet, to Bach's Inventions and Sinfonias, BWV 772–801, (1720–23). The premiere took place on Saturday, 4 June 1994 at the Juilliard Theater, Lincoln Center. The City Ballet premiere was Thursday, 19 January 1995, and it was revived for City Ballet's 90th anniversary celebration of the choreographer, performed again by students from S.A.B.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2_and_3_Part_Inventions</link></item><item><title>New Invention (song)</title><description>"New Invention" is a song by American rock duo I Dont Know How But They Found Me. It was released through Fearless Records on October 2, 2020, as the third single for their debut studio album, Razzmatazz (2020). The song was written by bassist and vocalist Dallon Weekes, Chad Walsh, David Walsh, and Tim Pagnotta, with production by the latter. Lyrically, it explores themes of anxiety and belonging, complemented by a bass-driven, synth-heavy power pop sound consistent with their base alternative rock style.
A lyric video was released alongside the single, featuring the duo interacting with an old supercomputer on the same set of "Leave Me Alone". Following its release, the song gained traction, charting at number 27 on Billboard's Alternative Airplay chart and achieving virality on TikTok in Australia. Other renditions of "New Invention" were released throughout 2021, including a remix featuring Tessa Violet and a live performance.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Invention_(song)</link></item><item><title>List of lost inventions</title><description>This is a list of lost inventions - technologies whose capabilities can no longer be produced in their original form. It does not include theoretical inventions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_lost_inventions</link></item><item><title>Invention of the integrated circuit</title><description>The first planar monolithic integrated circuit (IC) chip was demonstrated in 1960. The idea of integrating electronic circuits into a single device was born when the German physicist and engineer Werner Jacobi developed and patented the first known integrated transistor amplifier in 1949 and the British radio engineer Geoffrey Dummer proposed to integrate a variety of standard electronic components in a monolithic semiconductor crystal in 1952. A year later, Harwick Johnson filed a patent for a prototype IC. Between 1953 and 1957, Sidney Darlington and Yasuo Tarui (Electrotechnical Laboratory) proposed similar chip designs where several transistors could share a common active area, but there was no electrical isolation to separate them from each other.
These ideas could not be implemented by the industry, until a breakthrough came in late 1958. Three people from three U.S. companies solved three fundamental problems that hindered the production of integrated circuits. Jack Kilby of Texas Instruments patented the principle of integration, created the first prototype ICs and commercialized them. Kilby's invention was a hybrid integrated circuit (hybrid IC), rather than a monolithic integrated circuit (monolithic IC) chip. Between late 1958 and early 1959, Kurt Lehovec of Sprague Electric Company developed a way to electrically isolate components on a semiconductor crystal, using p–n junction isolation.
The first monolithic IC chip was invented by Robert Noyce of Fairchild Semiconductor. He invented a way to connect the IC components (aluminium metallization) and proposed an improved version of insulation based on the planar process technology developed by Jean Hoerni. On September 27, 1960, using the ideas of Noyce and Hoerni, a group of Jay Last's at Fairchild Semiconductor created the first operational semiconductor IC. Texas Instruments, which held the patent for Kilby's invention, started a patent war, which was settled in 1966 by the agreement on cross-licensing.
There is no consensus on who invented the IC. The American press of the 1960s named four people: Kilby, Lehovec, Noyce and Hoerni; in the 1970s the list was shortened to Kilby and Noyce. Kilby was awarded the 2000 Nobel Prize in Physics "for his part in the invention of the integrated circuit". In the 2000s, historians Leslie Berlin, Bo Lojek and Arjun Saxena reinstated the idea of multiple IC inventors and revised the contribution of Kilby. Modern IC chips are based on Noyce's monolithic IC, rather than Kilby's hybrid IC.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_of_the_integrated_circuit</link></item></channel></rss>