<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>Invention Secrecy Act</title><description>The Invention Secrecy Act of 1951 (Pub. L. 82–256, 66 Stat. 3, enacted February 1, 1952, codified at 35 U.S.C. ch. 17) is a body of United States federal law designed to prevent disclosure of new inventions and technologies that, in the opinion of selected federal agencies, present an alleged threat to the economic stability or national security of the United States.
The Invention Secret Act allows the United States government to classify ideas and patents under "Secrecy Orders", which indefinitely restrict public knowledge of them. The law applies to all inventions in the United States regardless of what the idea or invention is, if a patent is applied for or granted.35 U.S.C. § 181 All patents filed within the United States are required to be reviewed, and thousands of ideas and inventions are manually reviewed every year. Any Federal government agency with "classifying powers" may request any patent be restricted under the Invention Secrecy Act.
Ideas restricted by the Invention Secrecy Act's Secrecy Orders can be prohibited from any public disclosure; sales to any party except the United States military industry or exports to other nations can be prohibited; and can even be sealed from the public as classified. Any appeals are limited to the United States Federal agency that itself restricted the ideas.  The United States Patent and Trademark Office has investigated the possibility of restricting new technologies if those new ideas may be disruptive to existing industries. The Invention Secrecy Act has been criticized for lack of oversight and impacts on future scientific research by inventors, industry, attorneys and academics.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_Secrecy_Act</link></item><item><title>List of inventors killed by their own invention</title><description>This is a list of people whose deaths were in some manner caused by or directly related to a product, process, procedure, or other technological innovation that they invented or designed.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_inventors_killed_by_their_own_invention</link></item><item><title>Unity of invention</title><description>In most patent laws, unity of invention is a formal administrative requirement that must be met for a patent application to proceed to grant. An issued patent can claim only  one invention or a group of closely related inventions. The purpose of this requirement is administrative as well as financial. The requirement serves to preclude the possibility of filing one patent application for several inventions, while paying only one set of fees (filing fee, search fee, examination fee, renewal fees, and so on). Unity of invention also makes the classification of patent documents easier.
The WIPO and the EPO determine the unity of claims in a patent based on the presence of a common "special technical feature", which is usually equated with inventive step. On the other hand, the USPTO uses for its domestic applications a very different approach ("independent or distinct"), which is based on the fields of use for each claim,  justifying this approach by a "burden on the examiner" to search different areas of technology. The patent offices in Japan and China, similarly to the USPTO, also demand splitting patent applications into multiple divisionals as a means of increasing the monetary revenue of the offices.
When a patent application is objected to on the ground of a lack of unity, it may be still considered for patent protection, unlike for example in the case where the invention is found to be lacking novelty. A divisional application can usually be filed for the second invention, and for the further inventions, if any. Alternatively, the applicant may counterargue that there is unity of invention.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unity_of_invention</link></item><item><title>The Invention of Lying</title><description>The Invention of Lying is a 2009 American romantic comedy fantasy film written and directed by comedian Ricky Gervais and writer Matthew Robinson in their directorial debuts. The film stars Gervais as the first human with the ability to lie in a world where people can only tell the truth. The cast also includes Jennifer Garner, Jonah Hill, Louis C.K., Jeffrey Tambor, Fionnula Flanagan, Rob Lowe, Philip Seymour Hoffman and Tina Fey.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 14, 2009, and was released in the United States on October 2, 2009 by Warner Bros. Pictures and Focus Features. It grossed $32.7 million against a $18.5 million budget.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Invention_of_Lying</link></item><item><title>The Invention of Solitude</title><description>The Invention of Solitude is Paul Auster's debut memoir, published in 1982. The book is divided into two parts. The first part, Portrait of an Invisible Man, is about the sudden death of Auster's father. The second part, The Book of Memory, is a narrative in the third person.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Invention_of_Solitude</link></item><item><title>Shakespeare: The Invention of the Human</title><description>Shakespeare: The Invention of the Human is a survey of the works of Shakespeare, published in 1998 by literary critic Harold Bloom.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shakespeare:_The_Invention_of_the_Human</link></item><item><title>Stimpy's Invention</title><description>"Stimpy's Invention" is the twelfth episode and series finale of the first season of The Ren &amp; Stimpy Show. It originally aired on Nickelodeon in the United States on February 23, 1992.
The episode was frequently delayed, hence premiering as the final episode of the season; it received critical acclaim, with critics praising its animation and complex theme. It remains one of the most well known and popular episodes of the series.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stimpy%27s_Invention</link></item></channel></rss>