<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>List of inventors killed by their own invention</title><description>This is a list of people whose deaths were in some manner caused by or directly related to a product, process, procedure, or other technological innovation that they invented or designed.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_inventors_killed_by_their_own_invention</link></item><item><title>Invention (film)</title><description>Invention is a 2024 American drama film, directed and produced by Courtney Stephens, from a screenplay by Stephens and Callie Hernandez. It stars Hernandez, Sahm McGlynn, Lucy Kaminsky, Tony Torn, James N. Kienitz Wilkins, Joe Swanberg and Caveh Zahedi.
It had its world premiere at the 77th Locarno Film Festival on August 11, 2024, and was released on April 18, 2025.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_(film)</link></item><item><title>Four Great Inventions</title><description>The Four Great Inventions are inventions from imperial China that are celebrated in Chinese culture for their historical significance and as symbols of ancient China's advanced science and technology. They are the compass, gunpowder, papermaking and printing.
These four inventions had a profound impact on the development of civilization throughout the world. However, some modern Chinese scholars have opined that other Chinese inventions were perhaps more sophisticated and had a greater impact on Chinese civilization – the Four Great Inventions serve merely to highlight the technological interaction between East and West.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Great_Inventions</link></item><item><title>The Invention</title><description>An invention is a unique or novel device, method, composition, idea, or process. An invention may be an improvement upon a machine, product, or process for increasing efficiency or lowering cost. It may also be an entirely new concept. If an idea is unique enough either as a stand-alone invention or as a significant improvement over the work of others, it can be patented. A patent, if granted, gives the inventor a proprietary interest in the patent over a specific period of time, which can be licensed for financial gain.
An inventor creates or discovers an invention. The word inventor comes from the Latin verb invenire, invent-, to find. Although inventing is closely associated with science and engineering, inventors are not necessarily engineers or scientists. The ideation process may be augmented by the applications of algorithms and methods from the domain collectively known as artificial intelligence .
Some inventions can be patented.  The system of patents was established to encourage inventors by granting limited-term, limited monopoly on inventions determined to be sufficiently novel, non-obvious, and useful or has industrial applicability. A patent is jurisdictional, meaning that a patent only provides rights to the patent owner within the jurisdiction (Country or Countries) in which the patent was obtained. A patent provides the patent owner (who may or may not be an inventor) the right to exclude others from making, using, offering for sale, or selling an invention or importing it into the jurisdiction. The rules and requirements for patenting an invention vary by country and the process of obtaining a patent is often expensive.
Another meaning of invention is cultural invention, which is an innovative set of useful social behaviours adopted by people and passed on to others. The Institute for Social Inventions collected many such ideas in magazines and books. Invention is also an important component of artistic and design creativity. Inventions often extend the boundaries of human knowledge, experience or capability.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention</link></item><item><title>Stimpy's Invention</title><description>"Stimpy's Invention" is the twelfth episode and season finale of the first season of The Ren &amp; Stimpy Show. It originally aired on Nickelodeon in the United States on February 23, 1992. It was written by John Kricfalusi and Bob Camp, with Kricfalusi serving as director.
In the episode, Stimpy creates a series of absurd and impractical inventions, much to Ren's frustration. When one particularly infuriates Ren, Stimpy mistakenly sees his anger as unhappiness and begins to "fix it" by inventing the Happy Helmet, a psychological control device that forces happiness. During a manic performance of Happy Happy Joy Joy, Ren briefly regains self-control and uses a hammer to destroy the helmet, ultimately confronting Stimpy.
The episode had a very troubled production and took a year to complete, due to frequent delays and revisions, high-quality animation, and clashes with Nickelodeon. Premiering as the final episode of the season, it received critical acclaim, with critics praising its animation and complex theme, especially the Happy Happy Joy Joy scene. It remains one of the most well-known and popular episodes of the series.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stimpy%27s_Invention</link></item></channel></rss>