<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>List of inventors killed by their own invention</title><description>This is a list of people whose deaths were in some manner caused by or directly related to a product, process, procedure, or other technological innovation that they invented or designed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_inventors_killed_by_their_own_invention</link></item><item><title>The Invention of Lying</title><description>The Invention of Lying is a 2009 romantic comedy fantasy film written and directed by comedian Ricky Gervais and writer Matthew Robinson in their directorial debuts. The film stars Gervais as the first human with the ability to lie in a world where people can only tell the truth. The cast also includes Jennifer Garner, Jonah Hill, Louis C.K., Jeffrey Tambor, Fionnula Flanagan, Rob Lowe, Philip Seymour Hoffman and Tina Fey.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 14, 2009, and was released in the United States on October 2, 2009 by Warner Bros. Pictures and Focus Features. It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $32.7 million against a $18.5 million budget.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Invention_of_Lying</link></item><item><title>Four Great Inventions</title><description>The Four Great Inventions are inventions from ancient China that are celebrated in Chinese culture for their historical significance and as symbols of ancient China's advanced science and technology. They are the compass, gunpowder, papermaking and printing.
These four inventions had a profound impact on the development of civilization throughout the world. However, some modern Chinese scholars have opined that other Chinese inventions were perhaps more sophisticated and had a greater impact on Chinese civilization – the Four Great Inventions serve merely to highlight the technological interaction between East and West.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Great_Inventions</link></item><item><title>Invention promotion firm</title><description>An invention promotion firm or invention submission corporation provides services to inventors to help them in  develop or market their inventions. These firms may offer to evaluate the patentability of inventions, file patent applications, build prototypes, license them to manufacturers, and otherwise market.  They are distinguished from more conventional consulting firms and law firms offering the same or similar services in that they market their services primarily to amateur inventors through the mass media.
The US government estimates that hundreds of companies offer invention-promotion services and that “virtually all of them are either ineffective or outright fraudulent. One official at the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office says he believes there are fewer than a half-dozen legitimate invention promoters in the country”.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_promotion_firm</link></item><item><title>List of Scottish inventions and discoveries</title><description>Scottish inventions and discoveries are objects, processes or techniques either partially or entirely invented, innovated, or discovered by a person born in or descended from Scotland. In some cases, an invention's Scottishness is determined by the fact that it came into existence in Scotland (e.g., animal cloning), by non-Scots working in the country. Often, things that are discovered for the first time are also called "inventions" and in many cases there is no clear line between the two.
Some Scottish contributions have indirectly and directly led to controversial political ideas and policies, such as the measures taken to enforce British hegemony in the time of the British Empire. Scottish inventions have been noted as "revolutionising" the world numerous times, made possible by the "boundless imagination and inspired creativity" of the inventors who created them.
Even before the Industrial Revolution, Scots have been at the forefront of innovation and discovery across a wide range of spheres. Some of the most significant products of Scottish ingenuity include James Watt's steam engine, improving on that of Thomas Newcomen, the bicycle, macadamisation (not to be confused with tarmac or tarmacadam), Alexander Graham Bell's invention of the first practical telephone, John Logie Baird's invention of television, Alexander Fleming's discovery of penicillin and insulin.
The following is a list of inventions, innovations, or discoveries that are known or generally recognised as being Scottish.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Scottish_inventions_and_discoveries</link></item></channel></rss>