<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>The Invention of Lying</title><description>The Invention of Lying is a 2009 American romantic comedy fantasy film written and directed by comedian Ricky Gervais and writer Matthew Robinson in their directorial debuts. The film stars Gervais as the first human with the ability to lie in a world where people can only tell the truth. The cast also includes Jennifer Garner, Jonah Hill, Louis C.K., Jeffrey Tambor, Fionnula Flanagan, Rob Lowe, Philip Seymour Hoffman and Tina Fey.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 14, 2009, and was released in the United States on October 2, 2009 by Warner Bros. Pictures and Focus Features. It grossed $32.7 million against a $18.5 million budget.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Invention_of_Lying</link></item><item><title>Invention USA</title><description>Invention USA is an American reality television series on the History Channel that debuted on December 9, 2011. The series features inventor and technologist Reichart Von Wolfsheild and Scotty Ziegler (replacing theoretical physicist Garrett Lisi) as they travel around America to oversee the work of amateur inventors.  Season 2 premiered on November 26, 2012.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_USA</link></item><item><title>The Invention of Love</title><description>The Invention of Love is a 1997 British play by Tom Stoppard portraying the life of poet A. E. Housman, focusing specifically on his personal life and love for a college classmate. The play is written from the viewpoint of Housman, dealing with his memories at the end of his life, and contains many classical allusions. The Invention of Love won both the Evening Standard Award (U.K.) and the New York Drama Critics Circle Award (U.S.) 
Considered by many to be Stoppard's finest play, it has been called "esoteric". In fact, to demystify the play's many historical and academic references, the New York production team provided the audiences with a 30-page booklet on the political and artistic history of the late-Victorian period. Harold Bloom, a scholar of Walter Pater, contended that the character of Housman and those in his circle are fabulated for dramatic effect, and the play's difficulties are not historical but its own. This clarified, he cited it in 2003 as Stoppard's "masterpiece to date".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Invention_of_Love</link></item><item><title>Timeline of Irish inventions and discoveries</title><description>Irish inventions and discoveries are objects, processes or techniques which owe their existence either partially or entirely to an Irish person. Often, things which are discovered for the first time, are also called "inventions", and in many cases, there is no clear line between the two. Below is a list of such inventions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_Irish_inventions_and_discoveries</link></item><item><title>Gadget: Invention, Travel, &amp; Adventure</title><description>Gadget: Invention, Travel, &amp; Adventure (or Gadget: Past as Future) is an adventure game designed by Haruhiko Shono and first released by Synergy Interactive in 1993, following his earlier works Alice: An Interactive Museum (1991) and L-Zone (1992). Like Shono's earlier titles, Gadget uses pre-rendered 3D computer graphics  and resembles a point-and-click adventure game similar to Myst (1993), but with a strictly linear storyline culminating in a fixed finale. It thus sometimes tends to be classified more as an interactive movie rather than a video game. The story centers around a future dominated by retro technology from the 1920s and 1930s, especially streamlined locomotives and flying machines.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gadget:_Invention,_Travel,_%26_Adventure</link></item><item><title>Four Great Inventions</title><description>The Four Great Inventions are inventions from ancient China that are celebrated in Chinese culture for their historical significance and as symbols of ancient China's advanced science and technology. They are the compass, gunpowder, papermaking and printing.
These four inventions had a profound impact on the development of civilization throughout the world. However, some modern Chinese scholars have opined that other Chinese inventions were perhaps more sophisticated and had a greater impact on Chinese civilization – the Four Great Inventions serve merely to highlight the technological interaction between East and West.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Great_Inventions</link></item><item><title>List of Canadian inventions, innovations, and discoveries</title><description>Canadian inventions and discoveries are objects, processes, or techniques—invented, innovated, or discovered—that owe their existence either partially or entirely to a person born in Canada, a citizen of Canada, or a company or organization based in Canada. Some of these inventions were funded by National Research Council Canada (NRCC), which has been an important factor in innovation and technological advancement. Often, things discovered for the first time are also called inventions and in many cases, there is no clear line between the two.
The following is a list of inventions, innovations or discoveries known or generally recognized to be Canadian.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Canadian_inventions,_innovations,_and_discoveries</link></item><item><title>Re-Invention World Tour</title><description>The Re-Invention World Tour (billed as Re-Invention World Tour 2004) was the sixth concert tour by American singer-songwriter Madonna, in support of her ninth studio album American Life (2003). The tour began on May 24, 2004, at The Forum in Inglewood, United States, and ended on September 14 at the Pavilhão Atlântico in Lisbon, Portugal. Additionally, it marked Madonna's first concerts in Portugal and Ireland. Rumors of a concert tour first began circulating in October 2003, but nothing was confirmed until March 2004. According to some, the title Re-Invention was a dig at Madonna's critics who, throughout her career, had talked about her "reinventing herself"; the singer said she chose this name because she wanted to "re-invent" her old material. A number of songs were rehearsed for the tour, with twenty-four making the final setlist. Like past Madonna tours, Re-Invention was divided into different thematic acts: Marie Antoinette, Military, Circus, Acoustic, and Scottish-Tribal. The wardrobe was created by designers Arianne Phillips, Stella McCartney, Christian Lacroix, and Karl Lagerfeld.
Critical reviews ranged from positive to mixed. The singer was praised for performing the "classic" songs from her catalogue ―which had been absent from her previous Drowned World Tour (2001)― but the concert's themes and political tones were criticized. Nonetheless, it was awarded Top Tour at the 2004 Billboard Touring Awards. Re-Invention proved to be a commercial success, with total sell-outs and multiple extra dates being added. It became the highest-grossing concert tour of 2004, earning over $125 million from 56 shows, and an audience of over 900,000. Fellow singer Elton John then accused Madonna of lip-synching, which was denied by her representatives and John later apologized. The documentary chronicling the tour, I'm Going to Tell You a Secret, was directed by Jonas Åkerlund and released in 2005.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Re-Invention_World_Tour</link></item></channel></rss>