<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>Invention</title><description>An invention is a unique or novel device, method, composition, idea or process. An invention may be an improvement upon a machine, product, or process for increasing efficiency or lowering cost. It may also be  an entirely new concept. If an idea is unique enough either as a stand-alone invention or as a significant improvement over the work of others, it can be patented. A patent, if granted, gives the inventor a proprietary interest in the patent over a specific period of time, which can be licensed for financial gain.
An inventor creates or discovers an invention. The word inventor comes from the Latin verb invenire, invent-, to find. Although inventing is closely associated with science and engineering, inventors are not necessarily engineers or scientists. Due to advances in artificial intelligence, the term "inventor" no longer exclusively applies to an occupation (see human computers).
Some inventions can be patented.  The system of patents was established to encourage inventors by granting limited-term, limited monopoly on inventions determined to be sufficiently novel, non-obvious, and useful. A patent legally protects the intellectual property rights of the inventor and legally recognizes that a claimed invention is actually an invention. The rules and requirements for patenting an invention vary by country and the process of obtaining a patent is often expensive.
Another meaning of invention is cultural invention, which is an innovative set of useful social behaviours adopted by people and passed on to others. The Institute for Social Inventions collected many such ideas in magazines and books. Invention is also an important component of artistic and design creativity. Inventions often extend the boundaries of human knowledge, experience or capability.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention</link></item><item><title>Invention Secrecy Act</title><description>The Invention Secrecy Act of 1951 (Pub. L.Tooltip Public Law (United States) 82–256, 66 Stat. 3, enacted February 1, 1952, codified at 35 U.S.C. ch. 17) is a body of United States federal law designed to prevent disclosure of new inventions and technologies that, in the opinion of selected federal agencies, present an alleged threat to the economic stability or national security of the United States.
The Invention Secret Act allows the United States government to classify ideas and patents under "Secrecy Orders", which indefinitely restrict public knowledge of them. The law applies to all inventions in the United States regardless of what the idea or invention is, if a patent is applied for or granted.35 U.S.C. § 181 All patents filed within the United States are required to be reviewed, and thousands of ideas and inventions are manually reviewed every year. Any Federal government agency with "classifying powers" may request any patent be restricted under the Invention Secrecy Act.
Ideas restricted by the Invention Secrecy Act's Secrecy Orders can be prohibited from any public disclosure; sales to any party except the United States military industry or exports to other nations can be prohibited; and can even be sealed from the public as classified. Any appeals are limited to the United States Federal agency that itself restricted the ideas.  The United States Patent and Trademark Office has investigated the possibility of restricting new technologies if those new ideas may be disruptive to existing industries. The Invention Secrecy Act has been criticized for lack of oversight and impacts on future scientific research by inventors, industry, attorneys and academics.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_Secrecy_Act</link></item><item><title>Father of Invention</title><description>Father of Invention is a 2010 American comedy–drama film directed by Trent Cooper, and stars Kevin Spacey, Camilla Belle and Johnny Knoxville.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Father_of_Invention</link></item><item><title>Invention of Knowledge</title><description>Invention of Knowledge is a studio album by Anderson/Stolt, a musical collaboration formed by singer-songwriters and musicians Jon Anderson and Roine Stolt. It was released on 24 June 2016 by InsideOutMusic. The project originated in 2014 after Anderson had performed with Stolt on a progressive rock-themed cruise, and the two decided to record an album. The recording process involved Anderson recording ideas in demo form in California and sending them online to Stolt in Sweden, who would develop music based on them. Invention of Knowledge was recorded in Sweden by several musicians, including Tom Brislin, Daniel Gildenlöw, and members of Stolt's band The Flower Kings.
Invention of Knowledge received some positive reviews from critics. It charted in several countries, and reached number 58 on the UK Albums Chart. Anderson and Stolt discussed the idea of performing the album live on tour, but no tour for the album was mounted. As of 2023, the collaboration between the two artists appears to have concluded and no further releases are planned.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_of_Knowledge</link></item><item><title>List of inventors killed by their own invention</title><description>This is a list of people whose deaths were in some manner caused by or directly related to a product, process, procedure, or other technological innovation that they invented or designed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_inventors_killed_by_their_own_invention</link></item><item><title>American Heritage of Invention &amp; Technology</title><description>Invention &amp; Technology Magazine (formerly known as American Heritage of Invention &amp; Technology) is a quarterly magazine dedicated to the history of technology. It was launched with sponsorship from General Motors in the summer of 1985 as a spinoff of American Heritage magazine. Later, the magazine had a partnership with the National Inventors Hall of Fame.

“Our subject matter is actually nothing less than the making of the world we live in, and the stories of all the extraordinary people who made it,” wrote Frederick Allen, the Founding Editor, in 1985. He noted that the field of the history of technology is relatively new. "Up to now there has been no general magazine of wide circulation reporting on it. A gap exists between the findings of the scholars and the educated public," he wrote.
There were three issues of the magazine a year until 1992, when it became quarterly. Following the Summer 2007 issue (volume 23, number 1), publication was suspended (along with American Heritage itself). Publication of the magazine resumed with the Summer 2008 issue (volume 23, number 2), under the slightly changed title American Heritage's Invention &amp; Technology. Publication was suspended after the Winter 2011 issue (volume 25, number 4).
Invention &amp; Technology relaunched in 2020 with grants from the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation and Charles Koch Institute and donations from 700 subscribers. Its first new issue included profiles of 50 women inventors with articles by Dr. Shirley Ann Jackson, President of Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Sylvia Acevedo, CEO of the Girl Scouts, and C. Daniel Mote Jr., former president of the University of Maryland.
Contributors have included such writers about the history of technology as W. Bernard Carlson, Tom D. Crouch, Julie M. Fenster, Robert Friedel, William S. Hammack, Stephen Hawking, T. A. Heppenheimer, Thomas P. Hughes, Sebastian Junger, Arthur Molella, Henry Petroski, Robert C. Post, and Mark Wolverton.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Heritage_of_Invention_%26_Technology</link></item><item><title>Collective Invention</title><description>Collective Invention (Korean: 돌연변이) is a South Korean black comedy film written and directed by Kwon Oh-kwang. It is about a hapless fish-man's meteoric rise to celebrity and subsequent fall from grace. The film was screened in the Vanguard section of the 2015 Toronto International Film Festival.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collective_Invention</link></item></channel></rss>