<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>List of inventors killed by their own invention</title><description>This is a list of people whose deaths were in some manner caused by or directly related to a product, process, procedure, or other technological innovation that they invented or designed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_inventors_killed_by_their_own_invention</link></item><item><title>Re-Invention</title><description>The Re-Invention World Tour (billed as Re-Invention World Tour 2004) was the sixth concert tour by American singer Madonna, launched in support of her ninth studio album, American Life (2003). It began on May 24, 2004, at the Forum in Inglewood, California, and concluded on September 14 at the Pavilhão Atlântico in Lisbon, Portugal. The tour marked Madonna's return to the stage after three years and included her first-ever concerts in both Portugal and Ireland. Initially rumored in late 2003 and officially announced in March 2004, the tour's title referenced the singer's reputation for reinvention, as well as her aim to rework and reimagine older songs. The 24-track set list was divided into five thematic acts —Marie Antoinette, Military, Circus, Acoustic, and Scottish-Tribal— with costumes designed by Arianne Phillips, Stella McCartney, Christian Lacroix, and Karl Lagerfeld.
Critical reception ranged from positive to mixed. While many praised Madonna for performing the "classic hits" absent from her previous Drowned World Tour (2001), others critiqued the concert's themes and political tones. Nevertheless, the tour was a commercial triumph, grossing over $125 million ($208.09 million in 2024 dollars) from 56 sold-out shows and drawing an audience of more than 900,000, making it the highest-grossing tour of 2004. It won Top Tour at the 2004 Billboard Touring Awards. Controversy briefly surrounded the tour when Elton John accused Madonna of lip syncing —a claim denied by her team and later retracted by John. The tour was later chronicled in the 2005 documentary I'm Going to Tell You a Secret, directed by Jonas Åkerlund.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Re-Invention_World_Tour</link></item><item><title>The Invention of Lying</title><description>The Invention of Lying is a 2009 romantic comedy fantasy film written and directed by comedian Ricky Gervais and writer Matthew Robinson in their directorial debuts. The film stars Gervais as the first human with the ability to lie in a world where people can only tell the truth. The cast also includes Jennifer Garner, Jonah Hill, Louis C.K., Jeffrey Tambor, Fionnula Flanagan, Rob Lowe, Philip Seymour Hoffman and Tina Fey.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 14, 2009, and was released in the United States on October 2, 2009 by Warner Bros. Pictures and Focus Features. It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $32.7 million against a $18.5 million budget.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Invention_of_Lying</link></item><item><title>Invention (film)</title><description>Invention is a 2024 American drama film, directed and produced by Courtney Stephens, from a screenplay by Stephens and Callie Hernandez. It stars Hernandez, Sahm McGlynn, Lucy Kaminsky, Tony Torn, James N. Kienitz Wilkins, Joe Swanberg and Caveh Zahedi.
It had its world premiere at the 77th Locarno Film Festival on August 11, 2024, and was released on April 18, 2025.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_(film)</link></item><item><title>Four Great Inventions</title><description>The Four Great Inventions are inventions from imperial China that are celebrated in Chinese culture for their historical significance and as symbols of ancient China's advanced science and technology. They are the compass, gunpowder, papermaking and printing.
These four inventions had a profound impact on the development of civilization throughout the world. However, some modern Chinese scholars have opined that other Chinese inventions were perhaps more sophisticated and had a greater impact on Chinese civilization – the Four Great Inventions serve merely to highlight the technological interaction between East and West.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Great_Inventions</link></item></channel></rss>