<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>List of inventors killed by their own invention</title><description>This is a list of people whose deaths were in some manner caused by or directly related to a product, process, procedure, or other technological innovation that they invented or designed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_inventors_killed_by_their_own_invention</link></item><item><title>Four Great Inventions</title><description>The Four Great Inventions are inventions from imperial China that are celebrated in Chinese culture for their historical significance and as symbols of ancient China's advanced science and technology. They are the compass, gunpowder, papermaking and printing.
These four inventions had a profound impact on the development of civilization throughout the world. However, some modern Chinese scholars have opined that other Chinese inventions were perhaps more sophisticated and had a greater impact on Chinese civilization – the Four Great Inventions serve merely to highlight the technological interaction between East and West.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Great_Inventions</link></item><item><title>List of lost inventions</title><description>This is a list of lost inventions - technologies whose capabilities can no longer be produced in their original form. It does not include theoretical inventions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_lost_inventions</link></item><item><title>Invention Secrecy Act</title><description>The Invention Secrecy Act of 1951 (Pub. L. 82–256, 66 Stat. 3, enacted February 1, 1952, codified at 35 U.S.C. ch. 17) is a body of United States federal law designed to prevent disclosure of new inventions and technologies that, in the opinion of selected federal agencies, present an alleged threat to the economic stability or national security of the United States.
The Invention Secret Act allows the United States government to classify ideas and patents under "Secrecy Orders", which indefinitely restrict public knowledge of them. The law applies to all inventions in the United States regardless of what the idea or invention is, if a patent is applied for or granted.35 U.S.C. § 181 All patents filed within the United States are required to be reviewed, and thousands of ideas and inventions are manually reviewed every year. Any Federal government agency with "classifying powers" may request any patent be restricted under the Invention Secrecy Act.
Ideas restricted by the Invention Secrecy Act's Secrecy Orders can be prohibited from any public disclosure; sales to any party except the United States military industry or exports to other nations can be prohibited; and can even be sealed from the public as classified. Any appeals are limited to the United States Federal agency that itself restricted the ideas.  The United States Patent and Trademark Office has investigated the possibility of restricting new technologies if those new ideas may be disruptive to existing industries. The Invention Secrecy Act has been criticized for lack of oversight and impacts on future scientific research by inventors, industry, attorneys and academics.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_Secrecy_Act</link></item><item><title>Invention of the integrated circuit</title><description>The first planar monolithic integrated circuit (IC) chip was demonstrated in 1960. The idea of integrating electronic circuits into a single device was born when the German physicist and engineer Werner Jacobi developed and patented the first known integrated transistor amplifier in 1949 and the British radio engineer Geoffrey Dummer proposed to integrate a variety of standard electronic components in a monolithic semiconductor crystal in 1952. A year later, Harwick Johnson filed a patent for a prototype IC. Between 1953 and 1957, Sidney Darlington and Yasuo Tarui (Electrotechnical Laboratory) proposed similar chip designs where several transistors could share a common active area, but there was no electrical isolation to separate them from each other.
These ideas could not be implemented by the industry, until a breakthrough came in late 1958. Three people from three U.S. companies solved three fundamental problems that hindered the production of integrated circuits. Jack Kilby of Texas Instruments patented the principle of integration, created the first prototype ICs and commercialized them. Kilby's invention was a hybrid integrated circuit (hybrid IC), rather than a monolithic integrated circuit (monolithic IC) chip. Between late 1958 and early 1959, Kurt Lehovec of Sprague Electric Company developed a way to electrically isolate components on a semiconductor crystal, using p–n junction isolation.
The first monolithic IC chip was invented by Robert Noyce of Fairchild Semiconductor. He invented a way to connect the IC components (aluminium metallization) and proposed an improved version of insulation based on the planar process technology developed by Jean Hoerni. On September 27, 1960, using the ideas of Noyce and Hoerni, a group of Jay Last's at Fairchild Semiconductor created the first operational semiconductor IC. Texas Instruments, which held the patent for Kilby's invention, started a patent war, which was settled in 1966 by the agreement on cross-licensing.
There is no consensus on who invented the IC. The American press of the 1960s named four people: Kilby, Lehovec, Noyce and Hoerni; in the 1970s the list was shortened to Kilby and Noyce. Kilby was awarded the 2000 Nobel Prize in Physics "for his part in the invention of the integrated circuit". In the 2000s, historians Leslie Berlin, Bo Lojek and Arjun Saxena reinstated the idea of multiple IC inventors and revised the contribution of Kilby. Modern IC chips are based on Noyce's monolithic IC, rather than Kilby's hybrid IC.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_of_the_integrated_circuit</link></item><item><title>The Love Invention</title><description>The Love Invention is the debut solo studio album by British singer and musician Alison Goldfrapp. It was released on 12 May 2023 as her first full-length project under her own name, away from her efforts as part of electropop duo Goldfrapp. Singles from the album include "Digging Deeper" featuring Claptone, "Fever" featuring Paul Woolford, and "So Hard So Hot".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Love_Invention</link></item><item><title>Level of invention</title><description>Level of invention (or degree of inventiveness, or level of solution, or rank of solution, or rank of invention) is a relative degree of changes to the previous system (or solution) in the result of solution of inventive problem (one containing a contradiction). Term was defined and introduced by TRIZ author G. S. Altshuller.
After initially reviewing 200,000 patent abstracts, Altshuller selected 40,000 as representatives of high level inventive solutions. The remainder involved direct improvements easily recognized within the specialty of the system.
Altshuller separated the patents' different degrees of inventiveness into five levels:

Level 1 – Routine design problems solved by methods well known within the specialty. Usually no invention needed.
example: use of coal for writing
Level 2 – Minor improvements to an existing system using methods known within the industry.
example: graphite pencil (wrapped coal stick)
Level 3 – Fundamental improvement to an existing system using methods known outside the industry.
example: ink pen (ink instead of coal)
Level 4 – A new generation of a system that entails a new principle for performing the system's primary functions. Solutions are found more often in science than technology.
example: printer (another whole system for writing)
Level 5 – A rare scientific discovery or pioneering invention of an essentially new system.
example: electronic pen&amp;paper (see Anoto)
These levels of invention are applied to solutions rather than problems requiring a system of solution.
Also level of invention and the potential for innovation in any nation, geographical area or economic activity is as measurement in the concept of innovative capacity originally introduced by Prof. Suarez-Villa in 1990.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Level_of_invention</link></item></channel></rss>