<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>List of inventors killed by their own invention</title><description>This is a list of people whose deaths were in some manner caused by or directly related to a product, process, procedure, or other technological innovation that they invented or designed.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_inventors_killed_by_their_own_invention</link></item><item><title>Invention (film)</title><description>Invention is a 2024 American drama film, directed and produced by Courtney Stephens, from a screenplay by Stephens and Callie Hernandez. It stars Hernandez, Sahm McGlynn, Lucy Kaminsky, Tony Torn, James N. Kienitz Wilkins, Joe Swanberg and Caveh Zahedi.
It had its world premiere at the 77th Locarno Film Festival on August 11, 2024, and was released on April 18, 2025.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_(film)</link></item><item><title>List of lost inventions</title><description>This is a list of lost inventions - technologies whose capabilities can no longer be produced in their original form. It does not include theoretical inventions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_lost_inventions</link></item><item><title>Advanced Research and Invention Agency</title><description>The Advanced Research and Invention Agency, or ARIA, is a research funding agency of the UK government, announced on 19 February 2021 and formally established on 26 January 2023.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Research_and_Invention_Agency</link></item><item><title>Invention Secrecy Act</title><description>The Invention Secrecy Act of 1951 (Pub. L. 82–256, 66 Stat. 3, enacted February 1, 1952, codified at 35 U.S.C. ch. 17) is a body of United States federal law designed to prevent disclosure of new inventions and technologies that, in the opinion of selected federal agencies, present an alleged threat to the economic stability or national security of the United States.
The Invention Secret Act allows the United States government to classify ideas and patents under "Secrecy Orders", which indefinitely restrict public knowledge of them. The law applies to all inventions in the United States regardless of what the idea or invention is, if a patent is applied for or granted.35 U.S.C. § 181 All patents filed within the United States are required to be reviewed, and thousands of ideas and inventions are manually reviewed every year. Any Federal government agency with "classifying powers" may request any patent be restricted under the Invention Secrecy Act.
Ideas restricted by the Invention Secrecy Act's Secrecy Orders can be prohibited from any public disclosure; sales to any party except the United States military industry or exports to other nations can be prohibited; and can even be sealed from the public as classified. Any appeals are limited to the United States Federal agency that itself restricted the ideas.  The United States Patent and Trademark Office has investigated the possibility of restricting new technologies if those new ideas may be disruptive to existing industries. The Invention Secrecy Act has been criticized for lack of oversight and impacts on future scientific research by inventors, industry, attorneys and academics.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_Secrecy_Act</link></item><item><title>Stimpy's Invention</title><description>"Stimpy's Invention" is the twelfth episode and season finale of the first season of The Ren &amp; Stimpy Show. It originally aired on Nickelodeon in the United States on February 23, 1992. It was written by John Kricfalusi and Bob Camp, with Kricfalusi serving as director.
In the episode, Stimpy creates a series of absurd and impractical inventions, much to Ren's frustration. When one particularly infuriates Ren, Stimpy mistakenly sees his anger as unhappiness and begins to "fix it" by inventing the Happy Helmet, a psychological control device that forces happiness. During a manic performance of Happy Happy Joy Joy, Ren briefly regains self-control and uses a hammer to destroy the helmet, ultimately confronting Stimpy.
The episode had a very troubled production and took a year to complete, due to frequent delays and revisions, high-quality animation, and clashes with Nickelodeon. Premiering as the final episode of the season, it received critical acclaim, with critics praising its animation and complex theme, especially the Happy Happy Joy Joy scene. It remains one of the most well-known and popular episodes of the series.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stimpy%27s_Invention</link></item><item><title>List of Indian inventions and discoveries</title><description>This list of Indian inventions and discoveries details the inventions, scientific discoveries and contributions of India, including those from the historic Indian subcontinent and the modern-day Republic of India. It draws from the whole cultural and technological 
of India|cartography, metallurgy, logic, mathematics, metrology and mineralogy were among the branches of study pursued by its scholars. During recent times science and technology in the Republic of India has also focused on automobile engineering, information technology, communications as well as research into space and polar technology.
For the purpose of this list, the inventions are regarded as technological firsts developed within territory of India, as such does not include foreign technologies which India acquired through contact or any Indian origin living in foreign country doing any breakthroughs in foreign land. It also does not include not a new idea, indigenous alternatives, low-cost alternatives, technologies or discoveries developed elsewhere and later invented separately in India, nor inventions by Indian emigres or Indian diaspora in other places. Changes in minor concepts of design or style and artistic innovations do not appear in the lists.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Indian_inventions_and_discoveries</link></item></channel></rss>