<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Inventions on This Day</title><link>http://example.com/inventions</link><description>RSS feed of inventions that happened on this day of the month.</description><item><title>Four Great Inventions</title><description>The Four Great Inventions are inventions from imperial China that are celebrated in Chinese culture for their historical significance and as symbols of ancient China's advanced science and technology. They are the compass, gunpowder, papermaking and printing.
These four inventions had a profound impact on the development of civilization throughout the world. However, some modern Chinese scholars have opined that other Chinese inventions were perhaps more sophisticated and had a greater impact on Chinese civilization – the Four Great Inventions serve merely to highlight the technological interaction between East and West.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Great_Inventions</link></item><item><title>Timeline of Irish inventions and discoveries</title><description>Irish inventions and discoveries are objects, processes or techniques which owe their existence either partially or entirely to an Irish person. Often, things which are discovered for the first time, are also called "inventions", and in many cases, there is no clear line between the two. Below is a list of such inventions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_Irish_inventions_and_discoveries</link></item><item><title>Proposed directive on the patentability of computer-implemented inventions</title><description>The Proposal for a Directive of the European Parliament and of the Council on the patentability of computer-implemented inventions (Commission proposal COM(2002) 92), procedure number 2002/0047 (COD) was a proposal for a European Union (EU) directive aiming to harmonise national patent laws and practices concerning the granting of patents for computer-implemented inventions, provided they meet certain criteria. The European Patent Office describes a computer-implemented invention (CII) as "one which involves the use of a computer, computer network or other programmable apparatus, where one or more features are realised wholly or partly by means of a computer program".
The proposal became a major focus for conflict between those who regarded the proposed directive as a way to codify the case law of the Boards of Appeal of the European Patent Office (unrelated to the EU institutions) in the sphere of computing, and those who asserted that the directive is an extension of the patentability sphere, not just a harmonisation, that ideas are not patentable and that the expression of those ideas is already adequately protected by the law of copyright.
Following several years of debate and numerous conflicting amendments to the proposal, the proposal was rejected on 6 July 2005 by the European Parliament by an overwhelming majority of 648 to 14 votes.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proposed_directive_on_the_patentability_of_computer-implemented_inventions</link></item><item><title>The Invention of Lying</title><description>The Invention of Lying is a 2009 romantic comedy fantasy film written and directed by comedian Ricky Gervais and writer Matthew Robinson in their directorial debuts. The film stars Gervais as the first human with the ability to lie in a world where people can only tell the truth. The cast also includes Jennifer Garner, Jonah Hill, Louis C.K., Jeffrey Tambor, Fionnula Flanagan, Rob Lowe, Philip Seymour Hoffman and Tina Fey.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 14, 2009, and was released in the United States on October 2, 2009 by Warner Bros. Pictures and Focus Features. It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $32.7 million against a $18.5 million budget.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Invention_of_Lying</link></item><item><title>The Love Invention</title><description>The Love Invention is the debut solo studio album by British singer and musician Alison Goldfrapp. It was released on 12 May 2023 as her first full-length project under her own name, away from her efforts as part of electropop duo Goldfrapp. Singles from the album include "Digging Deeper" featuring Claptone, "Fever" featuring Paul Woolford, and "So Hard So Hot".</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Love_Invention</link></item><item><title>Invention Secrecy Act</title><description>The Invention Secrecy Act of 1951 (Pub. L. 82–256, 66 Stat. 3, enacted February 1, 1952, codified at 35 U.S.C. ch. 17) is a United States federal law that authorizes the government to prevent disclosure of certain inventions and technologies for reasons of national security. The statute permits selected federal agencies to determine whether a patent application or idea presents a threat, and to compel classification of that subject matter under secrecy orders. In practice, secrecy orders have been applied not only to inventions that may affect military defense but also to those viewed as raising risks to economic stability, and some commentators have described them as being imposed on inventions presenting only an alleged threat of such harm. The law applies to all inventions in the United States for which a patent is applied for or granted (35 U.S.C. § 181). All patents filed within the United States are required to be reviewed, and thousands of ideas and inventions are manually screened each year. Any Federal government agency with "classifying powers" may request that a patent be restricted under the Invention Secrecy Act.
Ideas subject to secrecy orders can be prohibited from any public disclosure; sales to any party except the United States military industry or exports to other nations can be prohibited; and restricted applications may even be sealed from the public as classified. Any appeals are limited to the United States Federal agency that itself imposed the restriction. The United States Patent and Trademark Office has investigated the possibility of applying secrecy orders to new technologies if those ideas might be disruptive to existing industries.
The Invention Secrecy Act has been criticized for lack of oversight and for negative impacts on future scientific research by inventors, industry, attorneys, and academics. Critics point to the limited appeal options available to inventors and the possibility of agencies restricting patents with minimal explanation. Concerns have also been raised about how secrecy orders intersect with innovation, markets, and the military–industrial complex more broadly.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invention_Secrecy_Act</link></item><item><title>List of Chinese inventions</title><description>China has been the source of many innovations, scientific discoveries and inventions. This includes the Four Great Inventions: papermaking, the compass, gunpowder, and early printing (both woodblock and movable type). The list below contains these and other inventions in ancient and modern China attested by archaeological or historical evidence, including prehistoric inventions of Neolithic and early Bronze Age China.
The historical region now known as China experienced a history involving mechanics, hydraulics and mathematics applied to horology, metallurgy, astronomy, agriculture, engineering, music theory, craftsmanship, naval architecture and warfare. Use of the plow during the Neolithic period Longshan culture (c. 3000–c. 2000 BC) allowed for high agricultural production yields and rise of Chinese civilization during the Shang dynasty (c. 1600–c. 1050 BC). Later inventions such as the multiple-tube seed drill and the heavy moldboard iron plow enabled China to sustain a much larger population through improvements in agricultural output.
By the Warring States period (403–221 BC), inhabitants of China had advanced metallurgic technology, including the blast furnace and cupola furnace, and the finery forge and puddling process were known by the Han dynasty (202 BC–AD 220). A sophisticated economic system in imperial China gave birth to inventions such as paper money during the Song dynasty (960–1279). The invention of gunpowder in the mid 9th century during the Tang dynasty led to an array of inventions such as the fire lance, land mine, naval mine, hand cannon, exploding cannonballs, multistage rocket and rocket bombs with aerodynamic wings and explosive payloads. Differential gears were utilized in the south-pointing chariot for terrestrial navigation by the 3rd century during the Three Kingdoms. With the navigational aid of the 11th century compass and ability to steer at sea with the 1st century sternpost rudder, premodern Chinese sailors sailed as far as East Africa. In water-powered clockworks, the premodern Chinese had used the escapement mechanism since the 8th century and the endless power-transmitting chain drive in the 11th century. They also made large mechanical puppet theaters driven by waterwheels and carriage wheels and wine-serving automatons driven by paddle wheel boats.
For the purposes of this list, inventions are regarded as technological firsts developed in China, and as such does not include foreign technologies which the Chinese acquired through contact, such as the windmill from the Middle East or the telescope from early modern Europe. It also does not include technologies developed elsewhere and later invented separately by the Chinese, such as the odometer, water wheel, and chain pump. Scientific, mathematical or natural discoveries made by the Chinese, changes in minor concepts of design or style and artistic innovations do not appear on the list.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Chinese_inventions</link></item></channel></rss>