<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Presidents Birth Dates</title><link>http://example.com/presidents-birth-dates</link><description>RSS feed of birth dates of presidents from various countries.</description><item><title>List of presidents of the United States by home state</title><description>These lists give the states of birth and of primary affiliation for each president of the United States.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_presidents_of_the_United_States_by_home_state</link></item><item><title>List of presidents of the Philippines</title><description>Under the Constitution of the Philippines, the president of the Philippines (Filipino: Pangulo ng Pilipinas) is both the head of state and government, and serves as the commander-in-chief of the country's armed forces. The president is directly elected by qualified voters to a six-year term and must be "a natural-born citizen of the Philippines, a registered voter, able to read and write, at least forty years of age on the day of the election, and a resident of the Philippines for at least ten years immediately preceding such election". No elected president can seek re-election. Upon resignation, or removal from the office, the vice president assumes the post. A president's successor who hasn't served for more than four years can still seek a full term for the presidency.
The incumbent president is Bongbong Marcos, who assumed office on June 30, 2022.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_presidents_of_the_Philippines</link></item><item><title>List of presidents of India</title><description>The president of India is the head of state of the Republic of India and the supreme commander of the Indian Armed Forces. The president is referred to as the first citizen of India. Although vested with these powers by the Constitution of India, the position is largely a ceremonial one and executive powers are de facto exercised by the prime minister.
The president is elected by the Electoral College composed of elected members of the parliament houses, the Lok Sabha and the Rajya Sabha, and also members of the Saasana Sabha or Vidhan Sabha, the state legislative assemblies. Presidents may remain in office for a tenure of five years, as stated by article 56, part V, of the Constitution of India. In the case where a president's term of office is terminated early or during the absence of the president, the vice president assumes office. By article 70 of part V, the parliament may decide how to discharge the functions of the president where this is not possible, or in any other unexpected contingency.
There have been 15 presidents of India since the post was established when India was declared as a republic with the adoption of the Indian constitution in 1950. Apart from these fifteen, three acting presidents have also been in office for short periods of time. V. V. Giri became the acting president in 1969 after Zakir Husain died in office. Giri was elected president a few months later. He remains the only person to have held office both as a president and acting president. Rajendra Prasad, the first president of India, is the only person to have held office for two terms.
Seven presidents have been members of a political party before being elected. Six of these were active party members of the Indian National Congress. The Janata Party has had one member, Neelam Sanjiva Reddy, who later became president. Two presidents, Zakir Husain and Fakhruddin Ali Ahmed, have died in office. Their vice presidents served as acting presidents until a new president was elected. Following Zakir Husain's death, two acting presidents held office until the new president, V. V. Giri, was elected. When Giri resigned to take part in the presidential elections, he was succeeded by Mohammad Hidayatullah as acting president. Pratibha Patil is the first woman to hold the office, elected in 2007.
On 25 July 2022, Droupadi Murmu took office as the president of India, becoming the second woman and the first tribal person to hold the office.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_presidents_of_India</link></item><item><title>List of vice presidents of the United States by age</title><description>This is a list of vice presidents of the United States by age. The first table charts the age of each vice president of the United States at the time of that person's inauguration (first inauguration if that person was elected to multiple and consecutive terms), at the time that that person left office, and at the time of that person's death. Each vice president's age at death and that person's lifespan are measured in two ways; this is to allow for the differing number of leap days occurring within each one's life. The first figure is the number of days between date of birth and date of death, allowing for leap days; in parentheses the same period given in years and days, with the years being the number of whole years that the vice president lived, and the days being the number of days after that person's last birthday. Where the vice president is still living, lifespan is calculated through July 27, 2025.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_vice_presidents_of_the_United_States_by_age</link></item><item><title>List of vice presidents of the Philippines</title><description>The vice president of the Philippines is the second-highest executive official in the government of the Philippines. The vice president is directly elected by qualified voters to a six-year term, and may be a cabinet member without confirmation from the Commission on Appointments and is first in the presidential line of succession.
The incumbent vice president is Sara Duterte, who assumed office on June 30, 2022.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_vice_presidents_of_the_Philippines</link></item><item><title>List of presidents of the United States by date of death</title><description>The following is a list of presidents of the United States by date of death, plus additional lists of presidential death related statistics. Of the 45 people who have served as President of the United States since the office came into existence in 1789, 40 have died – eight of them while in office.
The oldest president at the time of death was Jimmy Carter, who died at 100 years, 89 days. John F. Kennedy, assassinated at the age of 46 years, 177 days, was the youngest to have died in office; the youngest to have died by natural causes was James K. Polk, who died of cholera at the age of 53 years, 225 days.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_presidents_of_the_United_States_by_date_of_death</link></item><item><title>List of vice presidents of the United States by home state</title><description>This is a list of vice presidents of the United States by place of primary affiliation. Some vice presidents have been born in one state, but are commonly associated with another. New York was the birth state of eight vice presidents, the most of any state: George Clinton, Daniel D. Tompkins, Martin Van Buren, Millard Fillmore, Schuyler Colfax, William A. Wheeler, Theodore Roosevelt, and James S. Sherman. New York was also the home state of an additional four vice presidents—Aaron Burr, Chester A. Arthur, Levi P. Morton, and Nelson Rockefeller.
While political pundits have traditionally argued that the vice-presidential candidates have little effect on election outcomes in their home state, in 2016, political scientists Boris Heersink and Brenton D. Peterson argued that vice-presidential candidates did in fact offer a home-state advantage. In an article published in American Politics Research, they presented analysis of elections spanning 1884 to 1992, which "suggest that vice-presidential candidates increase their tickets’ performance in their home states by 2.67 percentage points on average—considerably higher than previous studies have found."</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_vice_presidents_of_the_United_States_by_home_state</link></item><item><title>List of presidents of the United States</title><description>The president of the United States is the head of state and head of government of the United States, indirectly elected to a four-year term via the Electoral College. Under the U.S. Constitution, the officeholder leads the executive branch of the federal government and is the commander-in-chief of the United States Armed Forces.
The first president, George Washington, won a unanimous vote of the Electoral College. The incumbent president is Donald Trump, who assumed office on January 20, 2025. Since the office was established in 1789, 45 men have served in 47 presidencies; the discrepancy arises from two individuals elected to nonconsecutive terms: Grover Cleveland is counted as both the 22nd and 24th president, while Trump is counted as both the 45th and 47th president.
The presidency of William Henry Harrison, who died 31 days after taking office in 1841, was the shortest in American history. Franklin D. Roosevelt served the longest, over twelve years, before dying early in his fourth term in 1945. He is the only U.S. president to have served more than two terms. Since the ratification of the Twenty-second Amendment to the United States Constitution in 1951, no person may be elected president more than twice, and no one who has served more than two years of a term to which someone else was elected may be elected more than once.
Four presidents died in office of natural causes (William Henry Harrison, Zachary Taylor, Warren G. Harding, and Franklin D. Roosevelt), four were assassinated (Abraham Lincoln, James A. Garfield, William McKinley, and John F. Kennedy), and one resigned (Richard Nixon, facing impeachment and removal from office). John Tyler was the first vice president to assume the presidency during a presidential term, setting the precedent that a vice president who does so becomes the fully functioning president with a new, distinct administration.
Throughout most of its history, American politics has been dominated by political parties. The Constitution is silent on the issue of political parties, and at the time it came into force in 1789, no organized parties existed. Soon after the 1st Congress convened, political factions began rallying around dominant Washington administration officials, such as Alexander Hamilton and Thomas Jefferson. Concerned about the capacity of political parties to destroy the fragile unity holding the nation together, Washington remained unaffiliated with any political faction or party throughout his eight-year presidency. He was, and remains, the only U.S. president who never affiliated with a political party.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_presidents_of_the_United_States</link></item></channel></rss>