<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>List of saints</title><description>This sortable list of Christian saints includes—where known—a surname, location, and personal attribute (or those attributes included as part of the historical name).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_saints</link></item><item><title>Saints in Anglicanism</title><description>Saints in Christianity are a people recognised as having lived a holy life and as being an exemplar and model for other Christians.  Beginning in the 10th century, the Catholic Church began to centralise and formalise the process of recognising saints through canonisation.
Saints who had been canonised when the Church of England was in communion with Rome generally continued to be recognised as saints after the English Reformation in the 16th century.
Since the split with Rome, the Church of England sometimes uses the word hero or heroine to recognise those holy people whom the church synod or an individual church praises as having had special benevolence.  It considers such muted terms a reversion to a more simple and cautious doctrine which emphasises empowerment (subsidiarity) to all members and components of the church.
The provinces of the Anglican Communion therefore commemorate many of the saints in the General Roman Calendar, often on the same days.
In some cases, Anglican Calendars have kept pre-1954 celebratory days that the Roman Catholic Church has since moved or abolished.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saints_in_Anglicanism</link></item><item><title>Calendar of saints (Church of England)</title><description>The Church of England commemorates many of the same saints as those in the General Roman Calendar, mostly on the same days, but also commemorates various notable (often post-Reformation) Christians who have not been canonised by Rome, with a particular though not exclusive emphasis on those of English origin. There are differences in the calendars of other churches of the Anglican Communion (see Saints in Anglicanism).
The only person canonised in a near-conventional sense by the Church of England since the English Reformation is King Charles the Martyr (King Charles I), although he is not widely recognised by Anglicans as a saint outside the Society of King Charles the Martyr. The Church of England has no mechanism for canonising saints, and unlike the Roman Catholic Church it makes no claims regarding the heavenly status of those whom it commemorates in its calendar. For this reason, the Church of England avoids the use of the prenominal title "Saint" with reference to uncanonised individuals and is restrained in what it says about them in its liturgical texts. In order not to seem to imply grades of sanctity, or to discriminate between holy persons of the pre- and post-Reformation periods, the title "Saint" is not used at all in the calendar, even with reference to those who have always been known by that title, for example the Apostles.
No Old Testament figures are commemorated in the Church of England calendar, but the litany "Thanksgiving for the Holy Ones of God" (included in Common Worship: Times and Seasons on pp. 558–560, immediately after "The Eucharist of All Saints") includes ten names from before Christ, so they are presumably not excluded on principle, and could be considered among the saints.
The ninth Lambeth Conference held in 1958 clarified the commemoration of Saints and Heroes of the Christian Church in the Anglican Communion. Resolution 79 stated:

There is no single calendar for the various churches making up the Anglican Communion; each makes its own calendar suitable for its local situation.  As a result, the calendar here contains a number of figures important in the history of the English church.  Calendars in different provinces will focus on figures more important to those different countries.  At the same time, different provinces often borrow important figures from each other's calendars as the international importance of different figures becomes clear.  In this way the calendar of the Church of England has importance beyond the immediate purpose of supporting the liturgy of the English Church. It is, for example, one of the key sources of the calendar for the international daily office Oremus.
Holy Days are variously categorised as Principal Feasts, Festivals, Lesser Festivals, or Commemorations. In order to minimise problems caused by the ambivalence regarding the manner of commemoration of uncanonised persons, all such days are Lesser Festivals or Commemorations only, whose observance is optional.
The following table lists the Holy Days in the calendar of Common Worship, the calendar most generally followed in the Church of England (though the calendar of the Book of Common Prayer is still authorised for use). This calendar was finalised in 2000, with some further names added in 2010. Individual dioceses and societies may suggest additional observances for local use, but these are not included here. The table includes the feast date, the name of the person or persons being commemorated, their title, the nature and location of their ministry or other relevant facts, and year of death, all in the form in which they are set out in the authorised Common Worship calendar. The level of the observance is indicated as follows:

boldface denotes Principal Feasts and Principal Holy Days
a dagger (†) denotes Festivals
an asterisk (*) denotes Lesser Festivals
italics denote unclassified observances
entries with none of the above are Commemorations.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calendar_of_saints_(Church_of_England)</link></item><item><title>Saints Cosmas and Damian</title><description>Cosmas and Damian (Arabic: قُزما ودميان, romanized: Qozma wa Dimyān; Greek: Κοσμᾶς καὶ Δαμιανός; Latin: Cosmas et Damianus; c. 3rd century – c. 287 or c. 303 AD) were two Arab physicians and early Christian martyrs. They practised their profession in the seaport of Aegeae, then in the Roman province of Cilicia.
Cosmas and Damian were third century Arabian-born twin brothers who embraced Christianity and practised medicine and surgery without a fee. This led them to being named anargyroi (from the Greek Ἀνάργυροι, 'the silverless' or 'unmercenaries'); by this, they attracted many to the Christian faith. They reputedly cured blindness, fever, paralysis and reportedly expelled a serpent. They were arrested by Lysias, governor of Cilicia (modern day Çukurova, Turkey) during the Diocletian persecution because of their faith and fame as healers. Emperor Diocletian, who favoured the worship of the Olympian gods, issued a series of edicts that condemned the Christians with the goal of eliminating Christianity from the Roman empire.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saints_Cosmas_and_Damian</link></item></channel></rss>