<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>All Saints' Church, Wittenberg</title><description>All Saints' Church, commonly referred to as Schlosskirche (Castle Church) to distinguish it from the Stadtkirche (Town Church) of St. Mary's, sometimes known as the Reformation Memorial Church, is a Lutheran church in Wittenberg, Saxony-Anhalt, Germany. It is the site where, according to Philip Melanchthon, the Ninety-five Theses were posted by Martin Luther in 1517, launching the beginning of the Protestant Reformation.
Beginning in 1883, the church was restored as a memorial site and re-inaugurated on 31 October 1892, 375 years after Luther's posting. Because of its religious significance and testimony to the lasting global effects of the Reformation, the church was inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 1996 along with other sites in Wittenberg and Eisleben associated with Martin Luther and Philip Melanchthon.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_Saints%27_Church,_Wittenberg</link></item><item><title>List of Eastern Orthodox saint titles</title><description>The saints of the Eastern Orthodox Church (and of the Eastern Catholic Churches of the Byzantine Rite) have various customary saint titles with which they are commemorated on the liturgical calendar and in Divine Services.
Many of the titles can overlap with each other (e.g. apostle and disciple) or are at least not mutually exclusive. Some of them are, however, mutually exclusive (e.g. prophet and righteous). Some titles are only given to one saint, very often the Virgin Mary, and some titles are also no longer given to saints (e.g. apostle).
It is not rare that certain titles, such as Venerable, Prophet or Hieromartyr, are placed in front of a saint's name instead of the standard Saint (e.g. Venerable Bede, Prophet Jonah or Hieromartyr Maximus Sandovic).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Eastern_Orthodox_saint_titles</link></item></channel></rss>