<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>Saint Mark (disambiguation)</title><description>Pope Mark (Latin: Marcus) was the bishop of Rome from 18 January to his death on 7 October 336.

Little is known of Mark's early life. According to the Liber Pontificalis, he was a Roman, and his father's name was Priscus. Mark succeeded Sylvester I as pope on 18 January 336.
Some evidence suggests that the early lists of bishops and martyrs known as the Depositio episcoporum and Depositio martyrum were begun during his pontificate. According to the Liber Pontificalis, Pope Mark issued a constitution investing the bishop of Ostia with a pallium and confirming his power to consecrate newly elected popes. Likewise according to the Liber Pontificalis, Pope Mark is credited with the foundation of the Basilica of San Marco, a basilica in Rome, and a cemetery church over the Catacomb of Balbina, just outside the city on lands obtained as a donation from Emperor Constantine.
Mark died of natural causes on 7 October and was buried in the catacomb of Balbina. In 1048, his remains were removed to the town of Velletri, and in 1145 were relocated to the Basilica of San Marco in Rome, where they are kept in an urn under the altar. His feast day is celebrated on 7 October. He is particularly venerated at the Abbadia San Salvatore at Monte Amiata.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pope_Mark</link></item><item><title>Saints in Anglicanism</title><description>Saints in Anglicanism are people recognised as having lived a holy life and as being an exemplar and model for other Christians (as opposed to the protestant teaching that saint is simply another term for a believer in Christ, literally "consecrated ones," from the Greek hagios).  Beginning in the 10th century, the Catholic Church began to centralise and formalise the process of recognising saints through canonisation.
Saints who had been canonised when the Church of England was in communion with Rome generally continued to be recognised as saints after the English Reformation in the 16th century.
Since the split with Rome, the Church of England sometimes uses the word hero or heroine to recognise those holy people whom the church synod or an individual church praises as having had special benevolence. It considers such muted terms a reversion to a more simple and cautious doctrine which emphasises empowerment (subsidiarity) to all members and components of the church.
The provinces of the Anglican Communion therefore commemorate many of the saints in the General Roman Calendar, often on the same days.
In some cases, Anglican Calendars have kept pre-1954 celebratory days that the Roman Catholic Church has since moved or abolished in the General Roman Calendar of 1969.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saints_in_Anglicanism</link></item></channel></rss>