<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>Saint Mark (disambiguation)</title><description>Mark Edward Pope (born September 11, 1972) is an American collegiate basketball coach and former player who is head men's basketball coach at the University of Kentucky, his alma mater. 
As a player, Pope played power forward and small forward. He was Pac-10 Freshman of the Year with the Washington Huskies and then transferred to Kentucky, where he served as a team captain of its 1996 NCAA national championship team. After college, Pope spent almost a decade playing professionally in the U.S. and internationally.
Pope has held various coaching roles at the collegiate level. Prior to taking the helm at his alma mater, he was the head coach at Utah Valley from 2015 to 2019 and BYU from 2019 to 2024.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Pope</link></item><item><title>List of Eastern Orthodox saints</title><description>This is a partial list of canonised saints in the Eastern Orthodox Church.
In Orthodoxy, a saint is defined as anyone who is in heaven, whether recognised here on earth, or not. By this definition, Adam and Eve, Moses, the various prophets, and archangels are all given the title of Saint. Sainthood in the Orthodox Church does not necessarily reflect a moral model, but communion with God; there are many examples of people who lived in great sin and became saints by humility and repentance: Saints Mary of Egypt, Moses the Ethiopian, and Dismas, the repentant thief who was crucified with Jesus Christ. Therefore, a more complete Orthodox definition of what a saint is, has to do with the way that saints, through their humility and their love of mankind, saved inside them the entire Church, and loved all people.
Orthodox belief states that God reveals saints through answered prayers and other miracles. Saints are usually recognised by their local community, often by people who directly knew them. As their popularity grows they are often then recognised by the entire Church through the Holy Spirit. The word canonisation means that a Christian has been found worthy to have his name placed in the canon (official list) of saints of the Church. The formal process of recognition involves deliberation by a synod of bishops. Evidence of a virtuous life and prior local veneration of the saint are required for canonization.
Because the Church shows no true distinction between the living and the dead, as the saints are considered to be alive in heaven, saints are referred to as if they are still alive, and are venerated, not worshipped. They are believed to be able to intercede for the living for salvation or other requests and help mankind either through direct communion with God or by personal intervention.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Eastern_Orthodox_saints</link></item><item><title>New Orleans Saints</title><description>The New Orleans Saints are a professional American football team based in New Orleans. The Saints compete in the National Football League (NFL) as a member of the National Football Conference (NFC) South division. Since 1975, the team plays its home games at Caesars Superdome after using Tulane Stadium during its first eight seasons. Founded by John W. Mecom Jr., David Dixon, and the city of New Orleans on November 1, 1966, the Saints joined the NFL as an expansion team in 1967.
The Saints were among the NFL's least successful franchises in their first several decades, where they went 20 consecutive seasons without a winning record or qualifying for the playoffs. They earned their first winning record and postseason berth in 1987, while their first playoff win would not occur until 2000, the team's 34th season. The team's fortunes improved in the 21st century, especially during the late 2000s and 2010s, which saw them become more consistent postseason contenders. Their greatest success to date came in the 2009 season, when they won Super Bowl XLIV in their only Super Bowl appearance. The win later drew controversy due to a bounty scandal. The Saints are one of two NFL franchises, along with the New York Jets, to win their sole Super Bowl appearance.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Orleans_Saints</link></item><item><title>Calendar of saints (Anglican Church of Canada)</title><description>Prior to the revision of the Anglican Church of Canada's (ACC) Book of Common Prayer (BCP) in 1962, the national church followed the liturgical calendar of the 1918 Canadian Book of Common Prayer. Throughout most of the twentieth century, the situation in Canada resembled that which pertained in much of the Anglican Communion: There was uncertainty as to whether post-Reformation figures (with the exception of the martyred Charles I) could or should be commemorated. In the words of the calendar's introduction, "New names have been added from the ancient calendars, and also from the history of the Anglican Communion, without thereby enrolling or commending such persons as saints of the Church."  The 1962 revision added twenty-six post-Reformation individuals, as well as commemorations of the first General Synod and of "The Founders, Benefactors, and Missionaries of the Church in Canada."  Of the calendar days, twenty-eight were highlighted as "red-letter days" — that is, days of required observation.
With the publication of the Book of Alternative Services (BAS) in 1985, a revised and expanded calendar was introduced. This was supplemented, in 1994, with the publication of For All The Saints; a book of propers, short biographies and descriptions of the commemorations, and readings by or about the individuals or events commemorated (there were also some very minor changes to the 1985 calendar).  As the BAS has largely supplanted the BCP for most Canadian Anglicans, so too has its calendar.  Nonetheless, the BCP calendar is still in use and individuals and parishes can legitimately choose to observe it.
The chief difference between the 1962 and 1985 calendars is the elimination of observations for several European figures, in order to include individuals of interest to the Canadian Church, and to the worldwide Anglican Communion. Similar to the Calendar of saints of the Church of England, the Patriarchs of Old are omitted in both the Book of Common Prayer and the newer Book of Alternative Services, for the Anglican Church of Canada.
In the ACC, the calendar is officially referred to as the Canadian Calendar of Holy Persons.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calendar_of_saints_(Anglican_Church_of_Canada)</link></item><item><title>Saints in Anglicanism</title><description>Saints in Anglicanism are people recognised as having lived a holy life and as being an exemplar and model for other Christians (as opposed to the Protestant teaching that saint is simply another term for a believer in Christ, literally "consecrated ones", from the Greek hagios).  Beginning in the 10th century, the Catholic Church began to centralise and formalise the process of recognising saints through canonisation.
Saints who had been canonised when the Church of England was in communion with Rome generally continued to be recognised as saints after the English Reformation in the 16th century.
Since the split with Rome, the Church of England sometimes uses the word hero or heroine to recognise those holy people whom the church synod or an individual church praises as having had special benevolence. It considers such muted terms a reversion to a more simple and cautious doctrine which emphasises empowerment (subsidiarity) to all members and components of the church.
The provinces of the Anglican Communion therefore commemorate many of the saints in the General Roman Calendar, often on the same days.
In some cases, Anglican Calendars have kept pre-1954 celebratory days that the Roman Catholic Church has since moved or abolished in the General Roman Calendar of 1969.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saints_in_Anglicanism</link></item></channel></rss>