<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>Feast of Saint James</title><description>The Feast of Saint James, also known as Saint James' Day, is a commemoration of the apostle James the Great celebrated on July 25 of the liturgical calendars of the Catholic Church and the Church of England. The Eastern Orthodox liturgical calendar commemorates James on April 30.
July 25 is also the National Day of Galicia of which James is its patron saint (Galician: Festas do Apóstolo).

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feast_of_Saint_James</link></item><item><title>Saint Silvan</title><description>Saint Silvan was a Christian martyr possibly from the fourth century and buried in St Blaise's Church in Dubrovnik since the mid of the 19th century. Saint Silvan, of whom not much is known, is commemorated on 30 July.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Silvan</link></item><item><title>List of saints</title><description>This sortable list of Christian saints includes—where known—a surname, location, and personal attribute (or those attributes included as part of the historical name).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_saints</link></item><item><title>Saint Crispin's Day</title><description>Saint Crispin's Day, or the Feast of Saint Crispin, falls on 25 October and is the feast day of the Christian saints Crispin and Crispinian, twins who were martyred c. 286. They are both the patron saints of cobblers, leather workers, tanners, saddlers and glove, lace and shoemakers (among other professions).
In modern times, the feast day is best known with reference to the St Crispin's Day Speech in Shakespeare's play Henry V. A scene in the play recounts the Battle of Agincourt, which took place on Saint Crispin's Day in 1415, with the titular character giving a speech before the battle referencing the feast day. 
When the Battle of Balaclava was fought on 25 October 1854, the coincidence was noticed by contemporaries, who used Shakespeare's words to comment on the battle. A similar effect occurred with reference to the Battle of Leyte Gulf, fought on St. Crispin's Day in 1944.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Crispin%27s_Day</link></item><item><title>Saints in Anglicanism</title><description>Saints in Christianity are a people recognised as having lived a holy life and as being an exemplar and model for other Christians.  Beginning in the 10th century, the Catholic Church began to centralise and formalise the process of recognising saints through canonisation.
Saints who had been canonised when the Church of England was in communion with Rome generally continued to be recognised as saints after the English Reformation in the 16th century.
Since the split with Rome, the Church of England sometimes uses the word hero or heroine to recognise those holy people whom the church synod or an individual church praises as having had special benevolence.  It considers such muted terms a reversion to a more simple and cautious doctrine which emphasises empowerment (subsidiarity) to all members and components of the church.
The provinces of the Anglican Communion therefore commemorate many of the saints in the General Roman Calendar, often on the same days.
In some cases, Anglican Calendars have kept pre-1954 celebratory days that the Roman Catholic Church has since moved or abolished.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saints_in_Anglicanism</link></item></channel></rss>