<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>All Saints' Church, Wittenberg</title><description>All Saints' Church, commonly referred to as Schlosskirche (Castle Church) to distinguish it from the Stadtkirche (Town Church) of St. Mary's, sometimes known as the Reformation Memorial Church, is a Lutheran church in Wittenberg, Saxony-Anhalt, Germany. It is the site where, according to Philip Melanchthon, the Ninety-five Theses were posted by Martin Luther in 1517, launching the beginning of the Protestant Reformation.
Beginning in 1883, the church was restored as a memorial site and re-inaugurated on 31 October 1892, 375 years after Luther's posting. Because of its religious significance and testimony to the lasting global effects of the Reformation, the church was inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 1996 along with other sites in Wittenberg and Eisleben associated with Martin Luther and Philip Melanchthon.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_Saints%27_Church,_Wittenberg</link></item><item><title>List of Catholic saints</title><description>This is an incomplete list of humans and angels whom the Catholic Church has canonized as saints. According to Catholic theology, all saints enjoy the beatific vision. Many of the saints listed here are found in the General Roman Calendar, while others may also be found in the Roman Martyrology; still others are particular to local places or religious institutes and their recognition does not extend to the larger worldwide church.
Candidates go through the following four steps on the way to being declared saints:

People also accepted as saints in the Eastern Orthodox Church and other churches are listed in Category:Christian saints by century and/or Category:Christian saints by nationality.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Catholic_saints</link></item><item><title>New Orleans Saints</title><description>The New Orleans Saints are a professional American football team based in New Orleans. The Saints compete in the National Football League (NFL) as a member of the National Football Conference (NFC) South division. Since 1975, the team plays its home games at Caesars Superdome after using Tulane Stadium during its first eight seasons. Founded by John W. Mecom Jr., David Dixon, and the city of New Orleans on November 1, 1966, the Saints joined the NFL as an expansion team in 1967.
The Saints were among the NFL's least successful franchises in their first several decades, where they went 20 consecutive seasons without a winning record or qualifying for the playoffs. They earned their first winning record and postseason berth in 1987, while their first playoff win would not occur until 2000, the team's 34th season. The team's fortunes improved in the 21st century, especially during the late 2000s and 2010s, which saw them become more consistent postseason contenders. Their greatest success to date came in the 2009 season, when they won Super Bowl XLIV in their only Super Bowl appearance. The win later drew controversy due to a bounty scandal. The Saints, along with the New York Jets, are one of two NFL franchises to win their sole Super Bowl appearance.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Orleans_Saints</link></item></channel></rss>