<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>List of Eastern Orthodox saints</title><description>This is a partial list of canonised Saints in the Eastern Orthodox Church. Some of the Saints below are also venerated in other Christian denominations, including in Catholicism, Oriental Orthodoxy, Anglicanism, Lutheranism and others.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Eastern_Orthodox_saints</link></item><item><title>List of saints of Ireland</title><description>This is a list of the saints of Ireland, which attempts to give an overview of saints from Ireland or venerated in Ireland. The vast majority of these saints lived during the 4th–10th centuries, the period of early Christian Ireland, when Celtic Christianity produced many missionaries to Great Britain and the European continent. The exact number of Irish saints is not known but the Martyrology of Donegal lists 1000 saints, male and female. For this reason, Ireland in a 19th-century adage is described as "the land of saints and scholars".
Christianity was introduced into Ireland toward the end of the 4th century. The details of the introduction are obscure, though the strict ascetic nature of monasticism in Ireland is said to be derived from the practices of the Desert Fathers. Although there were some Christians in Ireland before Patrick, who was a native of Roman Britain, he played a significant role in its full Christianisation.
Some of the best-known saints are Saint Patrick, Colmcill, Brigid of Kildare and the Twelve Apostles of Ireland.
After 1000, the process of recognizing saints was formalized, after which fewer people were named saints. Those canonized in the modern era include Oliver Plunkett (d. 1681, canonized 1975 by Pope Paul VI)  and Charles of Mount Argus (d. 1893, canonized in 2007 by Pope Benedict XVI).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_saints_of_Ireland</link></item><item><title>Saint Fiacre</title><description>Fiacre  (Irish: Fiachra, Latin: Fiacrius) is the name of three different Irish saints, the most famous of which is Fiacre of Breuil (c. AD 600 – 18 August 670), the priest, abbot, hermit, and gardener of the seventh century who was famous for his sanctity and skill in curing infirmities. He emigrated from his native Ireland to France, where he constructed for himself a hermitage together with a vegetable and herb garden, oratory, and hospice for travellers. He is the patron saint of gardeners.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Fiacre</link></item></channel></rss>