<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>Feast of Saint James</title><description>The Feast of Saint James, also known as Saint James' Day, is a commemoration of the apostle James the Great celebrated on July 25 of the liturgical calendars of the Catholic Church and the Church of England. The Eastern Orthodox liturgical calendar commemorates James on April 30.
July 25 is also the National Day of Galicia of which James is its patron saint (Galician: Festas do Apóstolo).</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feast_of_Saint_James</link></item><item><title>Saints in Anglicanism</title><description>Saints in Anglicanism are people recognised as having lived a holy life and as being an exemplar and model for other Christians (as opposed to the protestant teaching that saint is simply another term for a believer in Christ, literally "consecrated ones," from the Greek hagios).  Beginning in the 10th century, the Catholic Church began to centralise and formalise the process of recognising saints through canonisation.
Saints who had been canonised when the Church of England was in communion with Rome generally continued to be recognised as saints after the English Reformation in the 16th century.
Since the split with Rome, the Church of England sometimes uses the word hero or heroine to recognise those holy people whom the church synod or an individual church praises as having had special benevolence.  It considers such muted terms a reversion to a more simple and cautious doctrine which emphasises empowerment (subsidiarity) to all members and components of the church.
The provinces of the Anglican Communion therefore commemorate many of the saints in the General Roman Calendar, often on the same days.
In some cases, Anglican Calendars have kept pre-1954 celebratory days that the Roman Catholic Church has since moved or abolished.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saints_in_Anglicanism</link></item><item><title>Saint Cera</title><description>Saint Ciera of Ireland (alternately Chera, Chier, Cier, Ciara, Cyra, Céire, Keira, Keara, Kiara, Kiera, Ceara, Ciar) was an abbess in the 7th century who died in 679. Her history is commingled with another Cera (alternately Cier, Ciar, Ciara) who lived in the 6th century.  However, some authors maintain that monastic mistakes account for references to Cera in the 6th century or that a single Cera had an exceptionally long life span.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Cera</link></item></channel></rss>