<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>List of Eastern Orthodox saints</title><description>This is a partial list of canonised saints in the Eastern Orthodox Church.
In Orthodoxy, a saint is defined as anyone who is in heaven, whether recognised here on earth, or not. By this definition, Adam and Eve, Moses, the various prophets, and archangels are all given the title of "Saint". Sainthood in the Orthodox Church does not necessarily reflect a moral model, but communion with God: there are many examples of people who lived in great sin and became saints by humility and repentance, such as Saints Mary of Egypt, Moses the Ethiopian, and Dismas, the repentant thief who was crucified with Jesus Christ. Therefore, a more complete Orthodox definition of what a saint is, has to do with the way that saints, through their humility and their love of mankind, saved inside them the entire Church, and loved all people.
Orthodox belief states that God reveals saints through answered prayers and other miracles. Saints are usually recognised by their local community, often by people who directly knew them. As their popularity grows they are often then recognised by the entire Church through the Holy Spirit. The word canonisation means that a Christian has been found worthy to have his name placed in the canon (official list) of saints of the Church. The formal process of recognition involves deliberation by a synod of bishops. The Orthodox Church does not require the manifestation of miracles, as it does in Roman Catholicism; what is required is evidence of a virtuous life and prior local veneration of the saint.
Because the Church shows no true distinction between the living and the dead, as the saints are considered to be alive in heaven, saints are referred to as if they are still alive, and are venerated, not worshipped. They are believed to be able to intercede for the living for salvation or other requests and help mankind either through direct communion with God or by personal intervention.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Eastern_Orthodox_saints</link></item><item><title>Saint Gordius</title><description>Saint Gordius (also known as Gordinus; died 320) was a Christian soldier in Cappadocia who was dismissed from the Roman army, lived as a hermit for a while, then returned and made an open declaration of his faith, for which he was martyred in the city of Caesarea Maritima. He is commemorated on 3 January in the Eastern Orthodox Church and Roman Catholic Church.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Gordius</link></item><item><title>Saint Giles</title><description>Saint Giles (, Latin: Aegidius, French: Gilles, Italian: Egidio, Spanish: Gil; c. 650 - c. 710), also known as Giles the Hermit, was a hermit or monk active in the lower Rhône most likely in the 7th century. Revered as a saint, his cult became widely diffused but his hagiography is mostly legendary. A town that bears his name grew up around the monastery he purportedly founded, which became a pilgrimage centre and a stop on the Way of Saint James. 

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Giles</link></item></channel></rss>