<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>2010–11 Paris Saint-Germain FC season</title><description>The 2010–11 season was French football club Paris Saint-Germain's 38th professional season, their 38th season in Ligue 1 and their 37th consecutive season in French top-flight. PSG was coached by Antoine Kombouaré. The club was presided by Robin Leproux. PSG was present in the Ligue 1, the Coupe de France, the Coupe de la Ligue and the UEFA Europa League. PSG's average home gate was 29,317, the fourth highest in Ligue 1.
After a season marked by the violence between the fans and poor results from the team, Paris Saint-Germain started the season with the prospect of regaining success and stability. The club management presented the key measures of the anti-violence which intended to pacify the Parc des Princes. By the name "Tous PSG", many celebrities, such as former player Nicolas Anelka, attended and committed to the call of the club on the occasion of its 40 years. Paris Saint-Germain maintained the services of key players such as Claude Makélélé, Guillaume Hoarau, Stéphane Sessègnon and Mevlüt Erdinç, as well as adding Mathieu Bodmer and Nenê to their player pool. Robin Leproux had pretty high ambitions and declared that PSG was on the course to become more competitive. He expected the capital club to finish between the first four in the league and to pull something off in the Europa League:

We announced late last season that we wanted to make the team more competitive. It was planned to recruit a player of great value. The arrival of Mathieu Bodmer was the first strong sign, and that of Nenê is another. We continue to work to recruit quickly and have a full team for Le Championnat and other competitions, including in Europe.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010%E2%80%9311_Paris_Saint-Germain_FC_season</link></item><item><title>List of Eastern Orthodox saints</title><description>This is a partial list of canonised saints in the Eastern Orthodox Church.
In Orthodoxy, a saint is defined as anyone who is in heaven, whether recognised here on earth, or not. By this definition, Adam and Eve, Moses, the various prophets, and archangels are all given the title of Saint. Sainthood in the Orthodox Church does not necessarily reflect a moral model, but communion with God; there are many examples of people who lived in great sin and became saints by humility and repentance: Saints Mary of Egypt, Moses the Ethiopian, and Dismas, the repentant thief who was crucified with Jesus Christ. Therefore, a more complete Orthodox definition of what a saint is, has to do with the way that saints, through their humility and their love of mankind, saved inside them the entire Church, and loved all people.
Orthodox belief states that God reveals saints through answered prayers and other miracles. Saints are usually recognised by their local community, often by people who directly knew them. As their popularity grows they are often then recognised by the entire Church through the Holy Spirit. The word canonisation means that a Christian has been found worthy to have his name placed in the canon (official list) of saints of the Church. The formal process of recognition involves deliberation by a synod of bishops. Evidence of a virtuous life and prior local veneration of the saint are required for canonization.
Because the Church shows no true distinction between the living and the dead, as the saints are considered to be alive in heaven, saints are referred to as if they are still alive, and are venerated, not worshipped. They are believed to be able to intercede for the living for salvation or other requests and help mankind either through direct communion with God or by personal intervention.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Eastern_Orthodox_saints</link></item><item><title>Calendar of saints</title><description>The calendar of saints is the traditional Christian method of organizing a liturgical year by associating each day with one or more saints and referring to the day as the feast day or feast of said saint. The word "feast" in this context does not mean "a large meal, typically a celebratory one", but instead "an annual religious celebration, a day dedicated to a particular saint".
The system rose from the early Christian custom of commemorating each martyr annually on the date of their death, their birth into heaven, a date therefore referred to in Latin as the martyr's dies natalis ('day of birth'). In the Eastern Orthodox Church, a calendar of saints is called a Menologion. "Menologion" may also mean a set of icons on which saints are depicted in the order of the dates of their feasts, often made in two panels.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calendar_of_saints</link></item></channel></rss>