<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Saints Celebrated Today</title><link>http://example.com/saints</link><description>RSS feed of saints commemorated today from various religions.</description><item><title>All Saints' Day</title><description>All Saints' Day, also known as All Hallows' Day, the Feast of All Saints, the Feast of All Hallows, the Solemnity of All Saints, and Hallowmas, is a Christian holy day celebrated in honour of all the saints of the Church, whether they are known or unknown.
From the 4th century, feasts commemorating all Christian martyrs were held in various places, on various dates near Easter and Pentecost. In the 9th century, some churches in the British Isles began holding the commemoration of all saints on November 1st, and in the 9th century this was extended to the whole Catholic Church by Pope Gregory IV.
In Western Christianity, it is celebrated on November 1st by the Roman Catholic Church as well as by many Protestant Churches, such as the Evangelical Lutheran, Anglican, and Methodist traditions. With respect to its festal ranking, All Saints' Day is a solemnity in Catholicism and a festival in Evangelical Lutheranism.  The Eastern Orthodox Church and associated Eastern Catholic and Eastern Lutheran churches celebrate it on the first Sunday after Pentecost. The Syro-Malabar Church and the Chaldean Catholic Church, both of which are in communion with Rome, as well as the Church of the East, celebrate All Saints' Day on the first Friday after Easter Sunday. In the Coptic Orthodox tradition, All Saints' Day is on Nayrouz, celebrated on September 11th. The day is the start of the Coptic new year, and of its first month, Thout.
In the Western Christian practice, the liturgical celebration begins with its first vespers on the evening of October 31st, All Hallows' Eve (All Saints' Eve or Hallowe'en), and ends at the compline of November 1st. It is thus the day before All Souls' Day, which commemorates the faithful departed. In many traditions, All Saints' Day is part of the season of Allhallowtide, which includes the three days from October 31st to November 3rd inclusive, as well as the International Day of Prayer for the Persecuted Church (held on the first Sunday of November), and in some Christian denominations, such as Anglicanism, extends to Remembrance Sunday. In places where All Saints' Day is observed as a public holiday, cemetery and grave rituals such as offerings of flowers, candles and prayers or blessings for the graves of loved ones often take place on All Saints' Day (along with other days of Allsaintstide, especially on All Hallows Eve and All Souls Day). The use of candles by Christians symbolized the light of Christ and the use of lamps at the tombs of Christian martyrs dates back to the early Christian period. In Austria and Germany, godparents gift their godchildren Allerheiligenstriezel (All Saint's Braid) on All Saint's Day, while the practice of souling remains popular in Portugal. It is a national holiday in many Christian countries.
The Christian celebration of All Saints' Day and All Souls' Day stems from a belief that there is a powerful spiritual bond between those in heaven (the "Church triumphant"), the living (the "Church militant"), and the "Church penitent" which includes the faithful departed. In Catholic theology, the day commemorates all those who have attained the beatific vision in Heaven. The Lutheran branch of Christianity, on All Hallows' Day, remembers "those blessed fellow-believers who died in the Lord and are now at rest even as we wait with them for the Last Day and the resurrection of the body to eternal life with Christ." In Methodist theology, All Saints' Day revolves around "giving God solemn thanks for the lives and deaths of his saints", including those who are "famous or obscure". As such, individuals throughout the Church Universal are honoured, such as Paul the Apostle, Augustine of Hippo and other saints, varying according to the hagiographic traditions of the Church in question. In some traditions, the day is also used to celebrate individuals who have personally led one to faith in Jesus, such as one's grandmother or friend.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_Saints%27_Day</link></item><item><title>List of Catholic saints</title><description>This is an incomplete list of humans and angels whom the Catholic Church has canonized as saints. According to Catholic theology, all saints enjoy the beatific vision. Many of the saints listed here are found in the General Roman Calendar, while others may also be found in the Roman Martyrology; still others are particular to local places or religious institutes and their recognition does not extend to the larger worldwide church.
Candidates go through the following four steps on the way to being declared saints:

People also accepted as saints in the Eastern Orthodox Church and other churches are listed in Category:Christian saints by century and/or Category:Christian saints by nationality.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Catholic_saints</link></item><item><title>Saint Gordianus</title><description>Gordianus (died 362) was a Roman martyr who was killed during the reign of Julian the Apostate, and is commemorated on 10 May.
In his funeral inscription, Gordianus's youth is contrasted with his mature faith. Later Acts make him a pagan and a judge. He was charged with forcing Januarius to make a sacrifice to the Emperor, but instead was persuaded and then converted to Christianity with many within his household. Being accused before his successor, or as some say before the prefect of the city, Apronianus, he was tortured and finally beheaded. His body was carried off by the Christians, and laid in a crypt on the Latin Way beside the body of Epimachus of Alexandria, who had been recently interred there. The two saints gave their name to the cemetery, and have ever since been jointly venerated by the Catholic Church. According to David Farmer, these Acts are historically "worthless".
Some time later the remains of Gordianus were moved to the Cyriaca cemetery and there they lay until the 1670s, when a monk named Ambrose of the Order of St Augustin removed them and gave them to Christopher Anderson, a Jesuit priest. The remains were transferred to the Jesuit College of St. Omer; when the College moved to Stonyhurst, the remains travelled to England where they have remained since, interred below the altar of the Sodality Chapel.  His bones were temporarily removed in 2006 whilst the chapel underwent restoration, but they have since been returned.
The Princely Abbey of Kempten in Bavaria was established in 752, and dedicated to the Virgin Mary and Gordianus and Epimachus. Some of the relics of the two saints were brought there.
There is a church dedicated to Gordianus in Saint-Paul-d'Oueil in France.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Gordianus</link></item><item><title>New Orleans Saints</title><description>The New Orleans Saints are a professional American football team based in New Orleans. The Saints compete in the National Football League (NFL) as a member of the National Football Conference (NFC) South division. Since 1975, the team plays its home games at Caesars Superdome after using Tulane Stadium during its first eight seasons. Founded by John W. Mecom Jr., David Dixon, and the city of New Orleans on November 1, 1966, the Saints joined the NFL as an expansion team in 1967.
The Saints were among the NFL's least successful franchises in their first several decades, where they went 20 consecutive seasons without a winning record or qualifying for the playoffs. They earned their first winning record and postseason berth in 1987, while their first playoff win would not occur until 2000, the team's 34th season. The team's fortunes improved in the 21st century, especially during the late 2000s and 2010s, which saw them become more consistent postseason contenders. Their greatest success to date came in the 2009 season, when they won Super Bowl XLIV over the favored Indianapolis Colts, the team's first and only Super Bowl appearance so far. The Saints, along with the New York Jets, are one of two NFL franchises to win their sole Super Bowl appearance.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Orleans_Saints</link></item></channel></rss>