<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>2025 Copa América of Beach Soccer</title><description>The 2025 Copa América of Beach Soccer (known natively in Spanish as the Copa América de Futbol Playa) is the fifth edition of the Copa América of Beach Soccer, the international beach soccer competition organised by CONMEBOL for the men's national teams of South America. It is being held at Cavancha Beach in Iquique, Chile between 22 February and 2 March 2025.
For the second time, the tournament acts as the South American qualification for the FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup following CONMEBOL's decision to determine its representatives in the World Cup via the Copa America instead of its specific qualifying tournament that ran until 2021. The top three teams will qualify for the 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup held in Seychelles. The defending champions are Brazil.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_Copa_Am%C3%A9rica_of_Beach_Soccer</link></item><item><title>2025 CONCACAF Beach Soccer Championship</title><description>The 2025 CONCACAF Beach Soccer Championship will be the eleventh edition of the CONCACAF Beach Soccer Championship, the premier beach soccer tournament contested by CONCACAF teams. The tournament will take place at the Malcolm Park Beach Soccer Facility in Nassau, Bahamas. 
The two finalists will qualify to the 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup. The United States are the defending champions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_CONCACAF_Beach_Soccer_Championship</link></item><item><title>Major League Soccer on television</title><description>Major League Soccer has been broadcast live in the United States nationally since the league's inception in 1996 and in Canada since 2007. As of the 2023 season, Apple Inc. is the primary global rights holder and streams every regular season and playoff match on MLS Season Pass – a service in the Apple TV app. Some matches are also broadcast on television via Fox Sports in the United States, and Bell Media (via TSN and RDS) in Canada.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Major_League_Soccer_on_television</link></item><item><title>Major League Soccer</title><description>Major League Soccer (MLS) is a professional soccer league in North America and the highest level of the United States soccer league system. It comprises 30 teams, with 27 in the United States and 3 in Canada, and is sanctioned by the United States Soccer Federation. MLS is one of the major professional sports leagues in the United States and Canada. The league is headquartered in Midtown Manhattan.
The predecessor of MLS was the North American Soccer League (NASL), which existed from 1968 until 1984. MLS was founded in 1993 as part of the United States' successful bid to host the 1994 FIFA World Cup. The inaugural season took place in 1996 with ten teams. MLS experienced financial and operational struggles in its first few years, losing millions of dollars and folding two teams in 2002. Since then, developments such as the proliferation of soccer-specific stadiums around the league, the implementation of the Designated Player Rule allowing teams to sign star players such as David Beckham and Lionel Messi, and national TV contracts have made MLS profitable. 
In 2022, with an average attendance of over 21,000 per game, MLS had the fourth-highest average attendance of the major professional sports leagues in the United States and Canada, behind the National Football League (NFL) with over 69,000 fans per game, Major League Baseball (MLB) with over 26,000 fans per game, and the Canadian Football League (CFL) with over 21,700 fans per game. Two years later, MLS was ranked second in the most attended soccer leagues in the world, only trailing the Premier League.
The MLS regular season typically starts in late February or early March and runs through mid-October, with each team playing 34 games; the team with the best record is awarded the Supporters' Shield. Eighteen teams compete in the postseason MLS Cup playoffs in late October and November, culminating in the league's championship game, MLS Cup. Instead of operating as an association of independently owned clubs, MLS is a single entity in which each team is owned by the league and individually operated by the league's investors. The league has a fixed membership like most sports leagues in the United States and Canada and Mexico's Liga MX which makes it one of the few soccer leagues that does not use a promotion and relegation process. 
The LA Galaxy have the most MLS Cups, with six. They are tied with D.C. United for most Supporters' Shields, with four each.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Major_League_Soccer</link></item><item><title>Sophia Wilson (soccer)</title><description>Sophia Olivia Wilson (née Smith; born August 10, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a forward for Portland Thorns FC of the National Women's Soccer League (NWSL) and the United States national team.
Wilson played college soccer for the Stanford Cardinal, which she helped lead to the 2019 national championship. She was picked first overall by the Thorns in the 2020 NWSL College Draft. In 2021, she led the Thorns in scoring on their way to winning the NWSL Shield. In 2022, she led the Thorns to the NWSL Championship and was named the NWSL Most Valuable Player and Championship MVP. She received the NWSL Golden Boot as the league's top scorer in 2023.
Wilson played for the under-17 and under-20 teams before making her senior debut for the United States in 2020. She was named the U.S. Soccer Female Player of the Year in 2022. She scored three goals at the 2024 Paris Olympics, where the United States women's national team (USWNT) won gold.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sophia_Wilson_(soccer)</link></item></channel></rss>