<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Sophia Smith (soccer, born 2000)</title><description>Sophia Olivia Smith (born August 10, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a forward for National Women's Soccer League club Portland Thorns FC and the United States national team. She played college soccer at Stanford University, helping the Cardinal win the national championship in 2019. Smith was the first overall pick in the 2020 NWSL College Draft.
In 2022, Smith was named NWSL Most Valuable Player (MVP) and U.S. Soccer Female Player of the Year. She earned MVP honors at the 2022 NWSL Championship after helping the Thorns win the title. In 2023, she won the NWSL Golden Boot for most goals in the season. In 2024, Smith won a gold medal at the Paris 2024 Olympics with U.S. National Team.
At the international level, Smith won the gold medal with the United States at the 2024 Paris Olympics.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sophia_Smith_(soccer,_born_2000)</link></item><item><title>Quinn (soccer)</title><description>Quinn (formerly Rebecca Quinn; born 11 August 1995) is a Canadian professional soccer player who plays as a midfielder for National Women's Soccer League club Seattle Reign FC and the Canada national team. Quinn previously played professionally for Paris FC in France's top league Division 1 Féminine (D1F), Vittsjö GIK in the Swedish Damallsvenskan, as well as Washington Spirit in the NWSL. They were the first Canadian to play women's collegiate soccer at Duke University. Quinn previously represented Canada on the under-17, under-20, under-23 national teams.
In 2021, at the 2020 Tokyo Olympics, Quinn became the first out transgender, non-binary athlete to compete at the Olympics, the first to medal, and the first to earn a gold medal. In 2023, Quinn became the first openly transgender and non-binary footballer at the FIFA World Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quinn_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>United States men's national under-17 soccer team</title><description>The United States U-17 men's national soccer team is controlled by the United States Soccer Federation. The highest level of competition in which the team may compete is in the FIFA U-17 World Cup, which is held every two years.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_under-17_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team results</title><description>The United States women's national soccer team was founded in 1985.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_women%27s_national_soccer_team_results</link></item><item><title>OneSoccer</title><description>OneSoccer is a Canadian category-B exempt English language television channel and English and French language subscription over-the-top video streaming service. The service broadcasts programming related to soccer including live and pre-taped games, recap shows, and more. It is the main rightsholder of the Canadian Soccer Association, including holding the rights to the Canadian Premier League, Canadian Championship, and national team matches. It is rightsholder for various CONCACAF competitions, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup and CONCACAF Champions Cup. In 2024, ownership of OneSoccer was transferred from Mediapro Canada to Timeless Inc.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OneSoccer</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>Soccer on ESPN/ABC</title><description>Soccer on ESPN and ABC is a number of programs that currently airs soccer matches in the United States. These matches are from European competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_ESPN/ABC</link></item></channel></rss>