<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. Inter Miami CF won the 2024 Supporters' Shield; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and is scheduled to end on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs are scheduled to begin in October and conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS will only send 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allows most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS will be part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.
The United States will be the host country for the 2025 FIFA Club World Cup. MLS clubs can qualify as a host nation club; however, the criteria for selection has not been announced. MLS clubs have also been able to qualify through the 2021–2024 editions of the CONCACAF Champions Cup/CONCACAF Champions League. Seattle Sounders FC have qualified as the 2022 CONCACAF Champions League winners.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Soccer on Fox Sports</title><description>Fox currently airs soccer matches in the United States. These matches are from the FIFA World Cup, the FIFA Women's World Cup, the UEFA European Championship, the Gold Cup,  and Copa América. With the network currently also airing select MLS, and Liga MX matches. Fox formerly aired the UEFA Champions League and UEFA Europa League, the Premier League, the Bundesliga, the Serie A, and the FA Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_Fox_Sports</link></item><item><title>2024 National Women's Soccer League season</title><description>The 2024 National Women's Soccer League season is the twelfth season of the National Women's Soccer League, the top division of women's soccer in the United States. Including the NWSL's two professional predecessors, Women's Professional Soccer (2009–2011) and the Women's United Soccer Association (2001–2003), it is the 18th overall season of FIFA and USSF-sanctioned top division women's soccer in the United States. The league has 14 teams following the addition of expansion teams Bay FC and Utah Royals—the latter being the revival of a team that had played in the league from 2018 to 2020.
The season began with the 2024 NWSL Challenge Cup, a supercup match between the reigning playoff champion (NJ/NY Gotham FC) and NWSL Shield winner San Diego Wave FC, on March 15, 2024. The regular season began the following day and will run until November 3; it will pause for a month between July 8 and August 18 for the 2024 Summer Olympics. Each team will play 26 matches, an increase of four from the 2023 season. The playoffs will comprise the top eight teams and run from November 9 to November 23. The 2024 season is the first under a new broadcast agreement with CBS Sports, ESPN, Amazon Prime Video and Scripps Sports; a total of 118 matches will be televised or streamed.
In addition to league play, 2024 marks the debut of the NWSL x Liga MX Femenil Summer Cup, an international competition between clubs from the NWSL and Liga MX Femenil of Mexico. It is scheduled to be played from July to October.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_National_Women%27s_Soccer_League_season</link></item><item><title>Chris Richards (soccer)</title><description>Christopher Jeffrey Richards (born March 28, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a center-back or defensive midfielder for Premier League club Crystal Palace and the United States national team.
A youth player for FC Dallas in his home country, Richards began his professional career with Bundesliga club Bayern Munich, initially playing for the club's reserve team. After loan spells at 1899 Hoffenheim, he was signed by Crystal Palace in 2022.
A former youth player for his country, Richards received his first senior call-up for the United States in 2020, winning the CONCACAF Nations League in 2023 after scoring in the final.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Richards_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>Washington Freedom (soccer)</title><description>Washington Freedom was an American professional soccer club based in the Washington, D.C., suburb of Germantown, Maryland, that participated in Women's Professional Soccer.  The Freedom was founded in 2001 as a member of the defunct Women's United Soccer Association.  Beginning in 2004, the Freedom played its home games at the Maryland SoccerPlex. In 2011, the team relocated to Boca Raton, Florida, and became magicJack.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Washington_Freedom_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team results</title><description>The United States women's national soccer team was founded in 1985.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_women%27s_national_soccer_team_results</link></item><item><title>Match fixing in association football</title><description>The issue of match fixing in association football has been described, in 2013, by Chris Eaton, the former Head of Security of FIFA (the sport's world governing body), as a "crisis", while UEFA's president Michel Platini has said that if it continues, "football is dead". Zhang Jilong, president of the Asian Football Confederation, has stated that it is a "pandemic". The issue also affects a number of other sports across the world.
In May 2011, world governing body FIFA announced an anti-match fixing plan, and in September 2012 FIFA President Sepp Blatter warned that match-fixing endangered "the integrity of the game". In September 2014, the Council of Europe also announced they would tackle the problem.
A number of clubs in countries across the world have been subject to match fixing, including Australia, China, and Spain. The South African national team has also been investigated.
In the 18 months prior to February 2013, Europol investigated 680 matches in 30 countries. In November 2013, 11 men were charged in Estonia with fixing 17 matches.
The problem is often attributed to criminal gangs based in Asia, who generate "hundreds of billions of euros per year".
Players who have publicly rejected bribes have been praised, such as in a case in Belize.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Match_fixing_in_association_football</link></item></channel></rss>