<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Sophia Smith (soccer, born 2000)</title><description>Sophia Olivia Smith (born August 10, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a forward for National Women's Soccer League club Portland Thorns FC and the United States national team. She played college soccer at Stanford University, helping the Cardinal win the national championship in 2019. Smith was the first overall pick in the 2020 NWSL College Draft.
In 2022, Smith was named NWSL Most Valuable Player (MVP) and U.S. Soccer Female Player of the Year. She earned MVP honors at the 2022 NWSL Championship after helping the Thorns win the title. In 2023, she won the NWSL Golden Boot for most goals in the season. In 2024, Smith won a gold medal at the Paris 2024 Olympics with U.S. National Team.
At the international level, Smith won the gold medal with the United States at the 2024 Paris Olympics.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sophia_Smith_(soccer,_born_2000)</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team results</title><description>The United States women's national soccer team was founded in 1985.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_women%27s_national_soccer_team_results</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>Soccer on ESPN/ABC</title><description>Soccer on ESPN and ABC is a number of programs that currently airs soccer matches in the United States. These matches are from European competitions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_ESPN/ABC</link></item><item><title>List of United States women's international soccer players</title><description>The United States women's national soccer team (USWNT) represents the United States in international women's soccer. The team is fielded by the United States Soccer Federation (USSF), the governing body of soccer in the United States, and competes as a member of the Confederation of North, Central American and Caribbean Association Football (CONCACAF). The United States competed in their first international match on August 18, 1985, a 1–0 loss in the Mundialito against Italy. In total, 263 players have appeared for the national team since its inception.
The United States have competed in numerous friendly and competitive competitions, and all players who have played in a match, either as a member of the starting eleven or as a substitute, are listed below. Each player's details include her playing position while with the team, the number of caps earned and goals scored in all international matches, and details of the first and most recent matches played in. The players in the list are ordered alphabetically using their most common name. All statistics are correct up to and including the match played on June 5, 2024, against South Korea.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_women%27s_international_soccer_players</link></item><item><title>Quinn (soccer)</title><description>Quinn (formerly Rebecca Quinn; born 11 August 1995) is a Canadian professional soccer player who plays as a midfielder for National Women's Soccer League club Seattle Reign FC and the Canada national team. Quinn previously played professionally for Paris FC in France's top league Division 1 Féminine (D1F), Vittsjö GIK in the Swedish Damallsvenskan, as well as Washington Spirit in the NWSL. They were the first Canadian to play women's collegiate soccer at Duke University. Quinn previously represented Canada on the under-17, under-20, under-23 national teams.
In 2021, at the 2020 Tokyo Olympics, Quinn became the first out transgender, non-binary athlete to compete at the Olympics, the first to medal, and the first to earn a gold medal. In 2023, Quinn became the first openly transgender and non-binary footballer at the FIFA World Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quinn_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>United States men's national under-23 soccer team</title><description>The United States U-23 men's national soccer team, also known as the United States men's Olympic soccer team, is a youth soccer team operated under the auspices of U.S. Soccer. Its primary role is qualification into and competition at the quadrennial Olympic Football Tournament, with the next one to be held during the 2028 Summer Olympics in Los Angeles, which the team has already qualified for as hosts.
Its most recent major tournament was the 2024 edition at the Paris Olympics, in which the team made it to the quarter-finals before being eliminated by Morocco.
In accordance with FIFA regulations, the roster can be augmented with three "overage" players during Olympic competition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_under-23_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>2021 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2021 Major League Soccer season was the 26th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada. The 2021 season included the addition of Austin FC as an expansion club, which took the league to 27 teams.
Due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, the season was originally scheduled to begin on April 3, as opposed to the normal late February or early March start. This was later pushed back to April 16, the latest ever start to an MLS season, due to negotiations with the MLS Players Association for a new collective bargaining agreement. The regular season concluded on November 7. The 2021 MLS Cup Playoffs began on November 20, and concluded with MLS Cup 2021 on December 11.
At the beginning of the season, COVID-19 cross-border restrictions imposed by the Canadian government has also made the Canadian teams to play their home matches in the United States from the start of the season, while also sharing stadiums with other American MLS teams. On July 14, MLS announced that a select Toronto FC and CF Montréal matches would be played in Canada while working with the Canadian government on how the matches were to be held. Nearly a week later, the MLS announced that the Canadian teams would play home matches in Canada in August 2021.
The Columbus Crew were the defending champions, having defeated Seattle Sounders FC in MLS Cup 2020 but was eliminated from playoffs during the regular season, while the Philadelphia Union were the defending Supporters' Shield winners. The New England Revolution won their first Supporters' Shield, in the process breaking the record for most regular season points collected. New York City FC won their first ever MLS Cup, beating Portland Timbers in the decider.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2021_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item></channel></rss>