<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. Inter Miami CF won the 2024 Supporters' Shield; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and are scheduled to conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS are part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.
The United States will be the host country for the 2025 FIFA Club World Cup. MLS clubs could qualify as a host nation club, with Inter Miami CF qualifying as the 2024 MLS Supporters' Shield champions. MLS clubs were also able to qualify through the 2021–2024 editions of the CONCACAF Champions Cup/CONCACAF Champions League. Seattle Sounders FC have qualified as the 2022 CONCACAF Champions League winners.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>2024 Beach Soccer Africa Cup of Nations</title><description>The 2024 Africa Beach Soccer Cup of Nations was the sixth edition of the Africa Beach Soccer Cup of Nations (BSAFCON), the premier beach soccer championship in Africa contested by Confederation of African Football (CAF) member association men's national teams. And the 12th edition of the beach soccer championships on the continent, including the FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup CAF qualifiers championships organized by Beach Soccer Worldwide before its rebranding in 2015.
The tournament was held in Hurghada, Egypt, with all matches taking place from 19 to 26 October 2024. It also serves as the qualification pathway for African teams to the 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup in Seychelles, with the winner and runner-up qualifying alongside the automatically qualified host team, Seychelles.
Senegal were the defending champions, and successfully defending the title.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Beach_Soccer_Africa_Cup_of_Nations</link></item><item><title>List of United States men's national soccer team head coaches</title><description>The role of the United States men's national soccer team coach was first established in 1916 with the appointment of Thomas Cahill. Forty-one men have occupied this position.
The following tables include various statistics for head coaches of the United States men's national soccer team (featuring matches, wins, losses, ties, goals for, goals against, and goal differential along with goals for average and goals-against average) from the team's inception in 1916 through the October 12, 2024, match against Panama.
The result percentage is based on the formula used by U.S. Soccer in their U.S. Soccer Media Guide, found on page 78.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team_head_coaches</link></item><item><title>2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup qualification (UEFA)</title><description>The 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup will be the 13th edition of the FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup, the premier international beach soccer championship contested by men's national teams of the member associations of FIFA. Overall, this will be the 23rd edition of a world cup in beach soccer since the establishment of the Beach Soccer World Championships which ran from 1995 to 2004 but was not governed by FIFA; the World Cup took place annually until 2009 when it then became a biennial event.
It will take place in Victoria, capital of Seychelles, between 1 and 11 May 2025. This will be the first time that Seychelles has hosted a FIFA tournament, and the first Beach Soccer World Cup to be played in Africa.
Brazil are the defending champions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_FIFA_Beach_Soccer_World_Cup</link></item><item><title>Soccer in the United States</title><description>The United States Soccer Federation (USSF) governs most levels of soccer in the United States, including the national teams, professional leagues, and amateur leagues, being the highest soccer authority in the country. The National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) governs most colleges; secondary schools are governed by state-level associations, with the National Federation of State High School Associations (NFHS) setting the rules at that level. The match regulations are generally the same between the three governing bodies although there are many subtle differences.
As of May 2015, over 24.4 million people play soccer in the United States. In 2017, Gallup reported that soccer was the third-most watched team sport in the U.S., behind only basketball and American football. The popularity of the sport in the U.S. has been growing since the late 1960s and received a significant boost when the United States hosted the 1994 FIFA World Cup and 1999 FIFA Women's World Cup. It is the fourth most popular sport in the United States behind American football, baseball, and basketball.
The highest-level of  men's professional soccer in the U.S. is Major League Soccer (MLS). The league's predecessor was the major professional North American Soccer League (NASL), which existed from 1968 until 1984. MLS began to play in 1996 with 10 teams and has grown to 29 teams (26 in the United States and 3 in Canada), with further expansion planned to at least 30 teams. MLS is currently the largest first-division professional soccer league in the world. The MLS season runs from February to November, with the regular-season winner awarded the Supporters' Shield and the post-season winner awarded the MLS Cup. With an average attendance of over 20,000 per game, MLS has the third-highest average attendance of any sports league in the U.S. after the National Football League (NFL) and Major League Baseball (MLB), and is the seventh-highest attended professional soccer league worldwide. MLS uses franchised clubs similar to other major U.S. sports leagues, rather than the promotion and relegation model used for club soccer in other countries such as the United Kingdom.
The first women's professional soccer league in the U.S. formed after the success of the 1999 Women's World Cup. The Women's United Soccer Association (WUSA) ran from 2001 to 2003 and featured many of the World Cup stars, including Mia Hamm, Michelle Akers and Brandi Chastain. Its successor Women's Professional Soccer (WPS) ran from 2009 to 2012. Currently, the National Women's Soccer League (NWSL) is the top professional league in the country; it was formed in 2012 with play starting in 2013. The NWSL season runs from spring to early fall (typically April – October).
U.S. soccer fans follow the U.S. national teams in international competition. The 2015 FIFA Women's World Cup Final drew a record 26.7 million viewers, greater than final games of the 2014 World Series or the 2015 NBA Finals, and the 2010 Men's World Cup final drew 26.5 million viewers. The women's national team has won four Women's World Cup titles and five gold medals at the Summer Olympics and the men's national team played in every World Cup from 1990 to 2014 and returned to the World Cup in 2022.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_in_the_United_States</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Mexico–United States soccer rivalry</title><description>The Mexico–United States soccer rivalry is a sports rivalry between the national association football teams of the two countries, widely considered the two major powers of CONCACAF. It began with the first match played in 1934. The teams have met 78 times, with Mexico leading the overall series 37-17–24 (W–D–L). 
It is considered as one of the greatest rivalries in international soccer for its incidents involving fans, team brawls, and competitiveness, which is exemplified by political issues surrounding Mexico–U.S. relations. Matches between the two nations often attract much media attention, public interest, and comment in both countries. The U.S.-Mexico matches are widely attended; several matches at the Estadio Azteca in Mexico have drawn over 100,000 fans, and several matches at the Rose Bowl in the United States have drawn over 90,000 fans.
The most prominent matchups take place in quadrennial FIFA World Cup qualification matches and major North American tournaments such as the CONCACAF Gold Cup and CONCACAF Nations League. The rivalry also plays out with occasional friendly exhibition games, which media outlets often consider "anything but friendly".

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexico%E2%80%93United_States_soccer_rivalry</link></item><item><title>Quinn (soccer)</title><description>Quinn (formerly Rebecca Quinn; born 11 August 1995) is a Canadian professional soccer player who plays as a midfielder for National Women's Soccer League club Seattle Reign FC and the Canada national team. Quinn previously played professionally for Paris FC in France's top league Division 1 Féminine (D1F), Vittsjö GIK in the Swedish Damallsvenskan, as well as Washington Spirit in the NWSL. They were the first Canadian to play women's collegiate soccer at Duke University. Quinn previously represented Canada on the under-17, under-20, under-23 national teams.
In 2021, at the 2020 Tokyo Olympics, Quinn became the first out transgender, non-binary athlete to compete at the Olympics, the first to medal, and the first to earn a gold medal. In 2023, Quinn became the first openly transgender and non-binary footballer at the FIFA World Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quinn_(soccer)</link></item></channel></rss>