<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>United States men's national under-20 soccer team</title><description>The United States U-20 men's national soccer team is controlled by the United States Soccer Federation. The highest level of competition in which the team competes is the FIFA U-20 World Cup, which is held every two years.
The United States' best finish came in the 1989 FIFA World Youth Championship, when the U.S. beat Iraq in the quarterfinal before losing to Nigeria in overtime in the semifinal and Brazil in the third-place match. Steve Snow tied for second in the tournament with three goals.
The U.S. reached the quarterfinals in 1993 but lost to Brazil. After missing out in 1995, the U.S. began a run of six consecutive qualifications in 1997, reaching the second round in five consecutive tournaments. Of those tournaments, the best U.S. performance came in 2003, when the U.S. reached the quarterfinal and led Argentina 1–0 in the final minutes before falling 2–1 in extra time. The U.S. also reached the quarterfinal of the 2007 Cup before losing 2–1 in extra time to Austria.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_under-20_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.

The first United States national soccer team was constituted in 1885, when it played Canada in the first international match held outside the United Kingdom. Canada defeated the U.S. 1–0 in Newark, New Jersey. A second match in Newark the following year resulted in the U.S. defeating Canada 1–0, although neither match was officially recognized. The U.S. earned both silver and bronze medals in men's tournament at the 1904 St. Louis Summer Olympics through Christian Brothers College and St. Rose Parish, though the tournament is declared official only by the IOC; FIFA does not endorse tournaments held before 1908. The U.S. played its first official international match under the auspices of U.S. Soccer on August 20, 1916, against Sweden in Stockholm, where the U.S. won 3–2.

The U.S. fielded a team in the 1930 World Cup in Uruguay, the first edition of the World Cup. The U.S. began group play by beating Belgium 3–0, and then earned a 3–0 victory over Paraguay, with FIFA crediting Bert Patenaude with two of the goals. In November 2006, FIFA announced that it had accepted evidence that Patenaude scored all three goals against Paraguay, and was thus the first person to score a hat trick in a World Cup. In the semifinals, the U.S. lost to Argentina 6–1 and were eliminated. There was no third place game; however, using the overall tournament records in 1986, FIFA credited the Americans with a third-place finish ahead of fellow semifinalist Yugoslavia. This remains the U.S. team's best World Cup result, and is the highest finish of any team from outside of South America and Europe.
The U.S. qualified for the 1934 World Cup by defeating Mexico 4–2 in Italy a few days before the tournament opened. In a straight knock-out format, the team first played host Italy and lost 7–1, eliminating the U.S. from the tournament. At the 1936 Olympic Games in Berlin, the U.S. lost 1–0 to Italy in the first round and were eliminated. Italy went on to win both tournaments.
The 1950 World Cup in Brazil was the next World Cup appearance for the United States, as it withdrew in 1938 and the tournament was not held again until 1950 due to World War II. The U.S. lost its first match 3–1 against Spain, but then won 1–0 against England at Independência Stadium in Belo Horizonte. Striker Joe Gaetjens was the lone goalscorer in the match, which was called "The Miracle on Grass" and considered one of the greatest upsets in the history of the World Cup. The U.S. were eliminated from the tournament in their third game, a 5–2 defeat to Chile.

The national team spent the mid-to-late 20th century in near complete irrelevance in both the international game and the domestic sporting scene. CONCACAF had only one World Cup berth until 1982. Playing only two matches from 1981 to 1983, U.S. Soccer targeted the 1984 Summer Olympics in Los Angeles and the 1986 World Cup to rebuild the national team and its fan base. The International Olympic Committee declared that teams from outside Europe and South America could field full senior teams, including professionals. The U.S. finished with a 1–1–1 record in the group stage of the tournament but did not qualify for the second round, losing to Egypt on a tiebreaker.
To provide a more stable national team program and renew interest in the North American Soccer League, U.S. Soccer entered the national team into the NASL league schedule for the 1983 season as Team America. This team lacked the continuity and regularity of training that conventional clubs enjoy, and many players were unwilling to play for the national team instead of their own clubs when conflicts arose. Team America finished the season at the bottom of the league, with U.S. Soccer canceling the experiment and withdrawing the national team from the NASL after one season. By the end of 1984, the NASL had folded, leaving the U.S. without a single professional-level outdoor soccer league.
The 1986 World Cup was hosted by Mexico after Colombia withdrew from contention due to economic concerns and the United States lost their subsequent bid to host. In the last game of CONCACAF qualifying for the 1986 World Cup, the U.S. needed only a tie against Costa Rica to reach the final qualification group against Honduras and Canada. U.S. Soccer scheduled the game to be played in Torrance, California, an area with many Costa Rican expatriates, and marketed the game almost exclusively to the Costa Rican community. Costa Rica won the match 1–0, and kept the U.S. from reaching its fourth World Cup finals.

On July 4, 1988, FIFA named the U.S. as the host of the 1994 World Cup under significant international criticism given the perceived weakness of the national team and the lack of a professional outdoor league. The U.S. qualified for the 1990 World Cup with a 1–0 win against Trinidad and Tobago in the last match of the 1989 CONCACAF Championship. Mexico had been disqualified from the CONCACAF Championship for using ineligible players in a youth tournament, which allowed a chance for the U.S. to qualify for their first World Cup in 40 years.
The team was coached by Bob Gansler, Wisconsin-Milwaukee and U20 national team coach, in preparation for the 1990 World Cup in Italy. Two of the team's more experienced players, Rick Davis and Hugo Perez, were unavailable for selection while recovering from injuries. Rather than fill out his team with veteran professionals from U.S. indoor soccer leagues, Gansler and his assistant Stejem Mark chose to select many younger players with better conditioning for the outdoor game, including several collegiate players such as Virginia goalkeeper Tony Meola. The U.S. entered the tournament as major underdogs and lost all three of its group games to Czechoslovakia, Italy, and Austria. Defenders Jimmy Banks and Desmond Armstrong became the first African Americans to appear in a World Cup match for the United States.
During the 1993 U.S. Cup, a tournament designed to prepare for the upcoming World Cup, the U.S. beat England 2–0. After qualifying automatically as the host of the 1994 World Cup under Bora Milutinović, the U.S. opened the tournament schedule with a 1–1 tie against Switzerland in the Pontiac Silverdome in the suburbs of Detroit, the first World Cup game played indoors. In its second game, the U.S. faced Colombia, then ranked fourth in the world, at the Rose Bowl. Aided by an own goal from Andrés Escobar, the U.S. won 2–1; Escobar was later murdered in his home country, possibly in retaliation for this mistake. Despite a 1–0 loss to Romania in its final group game, the U.S. made it past the initial round for the first time since 1930. In the round of 16, the U.S. lost 1–0 to the eventual champion Brazil. U.S. Soccer later fired Milutinović in 1995 because he was reportedly not interested in administrative duties in addition to coaching.
The U.S. were invited to play in the 1995 Copa América, where they finished first in their group after defeating Chile and Argentina in an upset victory. In the quarterfinals, the U.S. defeated Mexico on penalties, and then lost to Brazil 1–0 in the semifinals. The United States finished fourth after losing to Colombia in the third-place match.
In the 1998 World Cup in France, the team lost all three group matches, 2–0 to Germany, 2–1 to Iran, and 1–0 to Yugoslavia, finishing last in the field of 32. The tournament was marred by disputes between the players and head coach Steve Sampson, who resigned shortly after the tournament.

Under former D.C. United head coach Bruce Arena, the U.S. qualified for the 2002 World Cup and reached the quarterfinals, their best finish in a World Cup since 1930. The team earned four points in the group stage, beginning with a 3–2 win over Portugal, followed by a 1–1 tie with co-host and eventual semifinalist South Korea. The third and final match was a 3–1 loss to Poland; the team still advanced to the round of 16 when South Korea defeated Portugal. The U.S. met continental rivals Mexico for the first time in a World Cup, and won the game 2–0, with goals from Brian McBride and Landon Donovan. In the quarterfinals, the USMNT met Germany and lost 1–0 after being controversially denied a penalty when Torsten Frings handled the ball to prevent a Gregg Berhalter goal. Donovan won the Best Young Player for the tournament.
In the 2006 World Cup, after finishing top of the CONCACAF qualification tournament, the U.S. was drawn into Group E along with the Czech Republic, Italy, and Ghana. The United States opened the tournament with a 3–0 loss to the Czech Republic. The team then tied 1–1 against eventual winners Italy, and then were knocked out of the tournament when they were beaten 2–1 by Ghana in its final group match, with Clint Dempsey scoring the U.S.'s only goal in the tournament (the goal against Italy had been an own goal by Italian defender Cristian Zaccardo). Following the tournament, Arena's contract was not renewed; his assistant, former Chicago Fire and MetroStars head coach Bob Bradley, became interim head coach in December 2006 and was selected for the full-time role in May 2007.
After winning the 2007 Gold Cup against Mexico, the USMNT qualified for the 2009 Confederations Cup. The U.S. shocked the soccer world by defeating top-ranked Spain, who were on a 35-game undefeated streak, 2–0. With the win, the United States advanced to its first-ever final in a men's FIFA tournament. The team lost 3–2 to Brazil after leading 2–0 at half-time. Hosting the 2009 Gold Cup, the United States was beaten by Mexico 5–0 in the final; this defeat broke the U.S. team's 58-match home unbeaten streak against CONCACAF opponents, and was the first home loss to Mexico since 1999 and their first home loss in a competitive match since 1998.
In the fourth round of the 2010 World Cup qualification, Jozy Altidore became the youngest U.S. player to score a hat-trick, in a 3–0 victory over Trinidad and Tobago. On October 10, 2009, the U.S. secured qualification to the 2010 World Cup with a 3–2 win over Honduras. Four days later, the U.S. finished in first place in the final round of qualification with a 2–2 tie against Costa Rica.

In the 2010 World Cup, the USMNT was drawn into Group C against England, Slovenia and Algeria. After drawing against England 1–1 and Slovenia 2–2, the U.S. defeated Algeria 1–0 with a stoppage-time goal from Landon Donovan, taking first place in a World Cup group for the first time since 1930. In the round of 16, the U.S. was eliminated by Ghana, 2–1.
After losing to Mexico 4–2 in the final of the 2011 Gold Cup, Bob Bradley was relieved of his duties and former Germany manager Jürgen Klinsmann was hired as head coach. The U.S. won 1–0 in Genoa, Italy on February 29, 2012, the team's first-ever win over Italy. In July 2013, the United States became North American champions for the fifth time after winning the Gold Cup with a 1–0 victory over Panama in the final, with Landon Donovan winning the tournament's golden ball award. A 4–3 victory over Bosnia and Herzegovina in an international friendly match in Sarajevo represented the 12th consecutive win for the USMNT, the longest active winning streak for any team in the world at that time. The winning streak ended September 6, when the U.S. lost to Costa Rica 3–1 in San José in the final round of qualification. The U.S. eventually clinched a spot in the 2014 World Cup.
The Americans were drawn into Group G, along with Ghana, Germany, and Portugal. The U.S. won 2–1 in their rematch with Ghana. They tied their second group game against Portugal 2–2. In the final game of the group stage, the U.S. fell to Germany 1–0, but moved on to the knockout stage on goal difference. This was the first time that the team made two consecutive trips to the knockout stage of the FIFA World Cup. In the round of 16, the U.S. lost 2–1 to Belgium in extra time, despite goalkeeper Tim Howard making a World Cup record 15 saves during the match.

In the 2015 Gold Cup, the U.S. were eliminated by Jamaica 2–1 in the semifinals, before losing to Panama on penalties in the third place match. It marked the first time the team failed to make the tournament final since 2003. In the 2015 CONCACAF Cup playoff to determine the region's entry to the 2017 Confederations Cup, the U.S. were defeated 3–2 by Mexico at the Rose Bowl. The results led to criticism of Klinsmann's coaching style, particularly the lack of a cohesive identity.
In June 2016, the U.S. hosted the Copa América Centenario, a special edition of the Copa América to commemorate the centenary of the tournament and its first to be played outside of South America. In their third Copa América appearance, the U.S. topped Group A on goal difference against Colombia, and then beat Ecuador 2–1 in the quarterfinals. The team lost 4–0 to Argentina 4–0 in the semifinals and 1–0 to Colombia again in the third place match. The U.S. finished fourth overall, tying their best finish ever in 1995.
Following consecutive losses to Mexico and Costa Rica in the opening games of the final round of qualification for the 2018 World Cup, Klinsmann was removed as national team coach and technical director and replaced by previous U.S. head coach Bruce Arena. World Cup qualification resumed on March 24, 2017, where Arena and his team achieved a record 6–0 win over Honduras. The U.S. got their third ever result in World Cup qualification at the Estadio Azteca when they drew 1–1 against Mexico. In July 2017, the U.S. won their sixth Gold Cup with a 2–1 win over Jamaica in the final. Following a 2–1 defeat to Trinidad and Tobago on October 10, 2017, the U.S. failed to qualify for the 2018 World Cup, missing the tournament for the first time since 1986. Many pundits and analysts called this the worst result and worst performance in the history of the national team.
Following Arena's resignation on October 13, 2017, assistant coach Dave Sarachan was named interim head coach during the search for a permanent replacement. The search for a permanent head coach was delayed by the USSF presidential election in February 2018 and the hiring of Earnie Stewart as general manager in June 2018. Gregg Berhalter, coach of the Columbus Crew and a former USMNT defender, was announced as the team's new head coach on December 2, 2018.
Under Berhalter the team lost in the 2019 Gold Cup final 1–0 against Mexico and were unable to defend their title.

An influx of new young talent playing for top European clubs, widely described as America's golden generation, entered the national team in the late 2010s and early 2020s. These players included Christian Pulisic, Weston McKennie, Tyler Adams, Timothy Weah, Sergiño Dest, and Gio Reyna. This new group won the inaugural CONCACAF Nations League in 2021 with a 3–2 victory against Mexico in the final. A different roster won the Gold Cup against Mexico later that summer, contributing to a record for wins in a calendar year, with 17 wins, three ties, and two losses in 2021.
The United States qualified for the 2022 World Cup by finishing third in the final qualifying round. Grouped with England, Iran, and Wales in Group B, the team advanced to the knockout stage as runners-up with five points and without losing a game. There, they faced the Netherlands and were defeated 3–1. Midfielder Kellyn Acosta became the first Asian American player to appear for the U.S. at a World Cup.
After Berhalter's contract expired in December 2022, the U.S. searched for a new head coach. Under interim manager B.J. Callaghan in June 2023, the United States successfully defended their Nations League trophy by winning the 2022–23 CONCACAF Nations League. The team conceded no goals in the finals tournament, winning 3–0 against Mexico and 2–0 against Canada in the final match. Callaghan remained the team's manager for the 2023 Gold Cup the following month, which was played with a different roster. The U.S. were eliminated in the semifinals by Panama after losing a penalty shootout.
The United States automatically qualified for the 2026 World Cup as co-host in February 2023, and secured a spot at the U.S.-hosted 2024 Copa América by defeating Trinidad and Tobago 4–2 over two legs in November 2023. Gregg Berhalter was reappointed as coach of the United States on June 16, 2023. In March 2024, the United States won their third CONCACAF Nations League title by defeating Mexico 2–0 in the final. The Nations League title qualified the United States for the Copa América, where they were eliminated in the group stage. The 1–0 loss in the final group stage match against Uruguay included several controversial decisions from referee Kevin Ortega, including an offside review for Uruguay's goal and handling of yellow cards. Following the team's elimination, Berhalter was fired as head coach on July 10, 2024.

Since their first unofficial game against Canada, the most common U.S. uniform has been white tops with blue shorts. A variant with a diagonal stripe or "sash" across the shirt similar to Peru's jersey was first adopted in 1950 and used in various uniforms in the 2000. A color scheme based on the U.S. flag—usually a shirt with red and white stripes with blue shorts—has been occasionally used (most prominently in the 1994 World Cup and 2012–13 qualifiers as well the 1983 Team America franchise of the North American Soccer League).
German brand Adidas provided the uniform for the United States from 1984 to 1994. Since 1995, American company Nike has been the uniform supplier. The final Adidas jersey was a denim-inspired blue shirt with white stars paired with red shorts.

The United States and Mexico have been the most successful teams in CONCACAF and are major rivals. They first met in 1934 during a World Cup qualifier in Rome that the U.S. won; Mexico won the following 24 meetings and were perennial qualifiers for the World Cup. Since 1980, the U.S. has had more wins against Mexico, particularly in home matches and major tournaments.
The two teams met in the knockout stage of the 2002 World Cup in the round of 16, with the United States winning 2–0. On August 15, 2012, the United States defeated Mexico at Estadio Azteca in the first victory for the U.S. against Mexico on Mexican soil in 75 years. On October 10, 2015, Mexico defeated the U.S. 3–2 in the CONCACAF Cup to qualify for the 2017 Confederations Cup. Thirteen months later, on November 11, 2016, El Tri defeated the U.S. for their second consecutive victory on American soil, in qualification for the 2018 World Cup. In 2021, the United States defeated Mexico three times in a calendar year for the first time, with the U.S. winning the CONCACAF Nations League final, the Gold Cup final, and in 2022 World Cup qualifying.
Ever since their first meeting in 1934, the two teams have met 77 times, with Mexico leading 36W–17T–24L, outscoring the U.S. 145–92. However, because of recent growth of soccer in the U.S., since the beginning of the 21st century, the U.S. leads the series 19W–8T–9L. Either the United States or Mexico has won every edition of the Gold Cup except one (the 2000 Gold Cup was won by Canada).

The U.S. has a secondary rivalry with Canada. The United States has historically been the stronger side, having qualified for 11 World Cups while Canada has qualified for two. 
On October 15, 2019, Canada defeated the United States for the first time in 34 years, at BMO Field in Toronto. In 2022 World Cup qualifying, Canada tied 1–1 with the U.S. in Nashville, Tennessee, and defeated the U.S. 2–0 in Hamilton, Ontario. On June 18, 2023, the United States defeated Canada 2–0 in the 2022–23 CONCACAF Nations League final in Las Vegas. The U.S. defeated Canada yet again in a 2023 Gold Cup quarterfinal matchup, this time 3–2 on penalties. The United States currently leads the series with 18 wins, 11 draws, and 11 losses.

In the 2010s, the United States began to develop a rivalry with Costa Rica. The impetus for the rivalry was a 2014 World Cup qualifying match played on March 22, 2013, at Dick's Sporting Goods Park in Commerce City, Colorado under blizzard conditions. Costa Rica filed a protest with FIFA due to field conditions after the United States won the game 1–0, but were denied recourse. The game was dubbed "Snow Clasico" for the conditions. The United States have never won an away match in Costa Rica, losing 10 meetings and drawing twice.

There have been two main supporter groups backing U.S. Soccer teams, Sam's Army and The American Outlaws. Sam's Army started shortly after the 1994 World Cup and were active through 2014. Sam's Army members wore red to matches and sung or chanted throughout the match, and often brought huge U.S. flags and other banners to the game.
The American Outlaws began in Lincoln, Nebraska, in 2007 as a local supporters' group. The group's membership attempted to address a lack of consistency from game to game in supporter organization and social events on match days. To achieve this goal, the American Outlaws became a nationwide, non-profit supporters' group. Some American Outlaws members wear U.S. flag bandanas over their faces and commonly wear soccer supporter scarves. Some branches of the American Outlaws have their own scarves specific to their branch.
The U.S. men's national team has a major following on social media platforms. Interest in young American players and the attention they bring has led to an increase in foreign investment in U.S. players, soccer development programs, and sports clubs.

The United States does not have a dedicated national stadium like other national teams; instead, the team has played their home matches at various venues across the country. As of 2017, the team has played in 123 stadiums in 30 states and the District of Columbia. Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium, located in the national capital of Washington, D.C., has hosted 24 matches, the most of any stadium. The state of California has hosted 117 matches, the most of any state, and greater Los Angeles has hosted 79 matches at several venues in and around the city of LA. The Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum hosted 20 matches from 1965 to 2000. The Rose Bowl, a 92,000-seat venue in Pasadena, has hosted 17 national team matches, as well as the 1994 World Cup final, the 1999 Women's World Cup final, and the 1984 Olympics gold medal match.

TNT Sports has the English language rights for U.S. Soccer broadcasts from 2022 to 2030. All matches are streaming live on Max with matches also on TNT and TBS. In  June 2021, CBS Sports acquired partial rights to select U.S. Soccer matches, including World Cup qualifiers and the Nations League finals, to be broadcast on CBS Sports Network and the Paramount+ streaming service. Telemundo has the Spanish language rights to all U.S. Soccer broadcasts from 2023 to 2030. These agreements do not apply to World Cup away qualifiers, whose rights are distributed by the host country.

The following is a list of match results in the last 12 months, as well as any future matches that have been scheduled.
  Win
  Draw
  Loss
  Fixture

 
 

 

 

The following table shows the United States all-time international record, correct as of July 1, 2024.

Coaching staff

Technical staff

Coach Gregg Berhalter named a 26-man squad for the 2024 Copa América.
Caps and goals are updated as of July 1, 2024, after the match against Uruguay.

The following players have been called up for the team within the last twelve months.

PRE = Preliminary squad
INJ = Injured
WD = Player withdrew from the squad due to non-injury issue.

As of July 1, 2024.
Players in bold are still active with the national team.

The United States has competed at the FIFA World Cup, the CONCACAF Gold Cup, the CONCACAF Nations League, and the Summer Olympics. The team has also played in the now-defunct FIFA Confederations Cup, the Copa América, as well as several minor tournaments.
The best result for the United States in a World Cup tournament came in 1930 when it reached the semifinals. The team included six naturalized internationals, five of them from Scotland and one from England. In the modern era, the team’s best result came in the 2002 World Cup, when it reached the quarterfinals. Its worst World Cup tournament results in were group-stage eliminations in 1990, 1998, and 2006; the team failed to qualify altogether for the final tournament in 2018. The United States reached the round of 16 in 1994, 2010, 2014, and 2022.
In the Confederations Cup, the United States finished in third place in both 1992 and 1999, and were runner-up in 2009. The team appeared in its first intercontinental tournament final at the 2009 Confederations Cup, where it lost to Brazil 3–2 after leading 2–0 at halftime.
The U.S. men's soccer team first played in the Summer Olympics in 1924. From that tournament to 1980, only amateur and state-sponsored Eastern European players were allowed on Olympic teams. The Olympics became a full international tournament in 1984 after the IOC allowed full national teams from outside FIFA's strongest confederations of UEFA and CONMEBOL. Since 1992 the men's Olympic event has been age-restricted, to those 23 years and younger, with the exception (since 1996) of up to three overage players; participation has been by the United States men's national under-23 soccer team.
In regional competitions, the United States has won the CONCACAF Gold Cup seven times, with its most recent title in 2021. The team won the inaugural CONCACAF Nations League in 2021. Its best finish at the Copa América was fourth place at the 1995 and 2016 editions, while it competed as the host nation in 2024, failing to advance past the group stage.  

CONCACAF Championship 1963–1989, CONCACAF Gold Cup 1991–present

Major competitions

FIFA World Cup
Third place (1):  1930
Summer Olympics
Silver medal (1):  1904
Bronze medal (1):  1904
FIFA Confederations Cup
Runners-up (1):  2009
Third place (2):  1992, 1999
Copa América
Fourth place (2): 1995, 2016
CONCACAF Championship / Gold Cup
Champions (7):  1991, 2002, 2005, 2007, 2013, 2017, 2021
Runners-up (6):  1989, 1993, 1998, 2009, 2011, 2019
Third place (2):  1996, 2003
Fair Play Award (6): 2003, 2009, 2017, 2019, 2021, 2023
CONCACAF Nations League
Champions (3):  2019–20, 2022–23, 2023–24
Other competitions

CONCACAF Cup
Runners-up (1):  2015
CONCACAF Olympic Qualifying Tournament
Runners-up (2):  1972, 1980
Third Place (1):  1964
U.S. Cup
Champions (3):  1992, 1995, 2000
Runners-up (1):  1999
Third place (2):  1993, 1996
Marlboro Cup
Champions (2):  1989, 1989
Runners-up (3):  1987, 1988, 1989
Third place (1):  1990
North American Nations Cup
Runners-up (2):  1949, 1991
Third place (2):  1947, 1990

Fútbol de Primera Player of the Year
List of United States men's international soccer players born outside the United States
U.S. National Soccer Team Players Association
U.S. Soccer Player of the Year
United States men's national under-17 soccer team
United States men's national under-20 soccer team
United States men's national under-23 soccer team
United States women's national soccer team

Official website 
U.S. Soccer Schedule at USSF
U.S. Soccer Results at USSF
U.S. Matches at FIFA
U.S. National Soccer Team Players Association
U.S. soccer team at Association of Football Statisticians
United States at FootballDatabase.eu
USA Men's National Team: All-time Results, 1885–1989 Archived August 2, 2018, at the Wayback Machine
USA Men's National Team: All-time Results, 1990–present Archived August 11, 2011, at the Wayback Machine
USA Men's National Team: Current Value of Players on Team</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. FC Cincinnati are the reigning Supporters' Shield holders; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and is scheduled to end on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprises all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup Playoffs are scheduled to begin in October and conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS will only send 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allows most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS will be part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.

Note: All teams use Adidas as universal kit manufacturer. As part of Apple's broadcast contract, all MLS kits will include Apple TV+ as a sleeve sponsor.

The regular season consists of 34 matches for each team, split evenly between home and away games. The opening match was played on February 21, the earliest in league history; the regular season will end with Decision Day on October 19, which will comprise simultaneous intra-conference matches. Matches will be paused from July 25 to August 23 for the 2024 Leagues Cup, a knockout tournament that includes teams from MLS and Liga MX. The league did not pause matches for the 2024 Copa América, which was played in the United States from June to July. Most regular season matches will be played on Saturdays and Wednesdays at 7:30 p.m. local time.
The 29 teams are divided into two conferences: the Eastern and Western. The 15 teams in the East will play a round-robin format with intra-conference teams and six matches against six opponents from the West. The 14 teams in the West will play a round-robin with intra-conference teams, an additional one or two intra-conference matches, and six to seven matches against opponents from the East. The top nine teams in each conference will advance to the 2024 MLS Cup Playoffs, which begin with a wild card round for the eighth and ninth placed teams and is followed by a best-of-three series that was introduced in 2023. The remaining matches are single-elimination and culminate with the MLS Cup final on December 7.
Several new rules were scheduled to be introduced for the 2024 season following trials in MLS Next Pro, including in-stadium announcements of video assistant referee decisions, a time limit for substitutions, and mandatory off-field checks for injured players. These initiatives were postponed by MLS due to an ongoing labor dispute with the Professional Soccer Referees Association, who organized a lockout of their referees. Replacement referees from outside the union, including former officials and those from lower level leagues other than USL, were called in to officiate MLS matches. The referees' union and MLS reached an agreement in time for the regular referees to return to the field for Matchday 7, on March 30.
The 2024 MLS All-Star Game will be played between the MLS All-Stars and the Liga MX All-Stars on July 24.

The leading team in this table will win the Supporters' Shield.

The United States will be the host country for the 2025 FIFA Club World Cup. MLS clubs can qualify as a host nation club; however, the criteria for selection has not been announced. MLS clubs have also been able to qualify through the 2021–2024 editions of the CONCACAF Champions Cup/CONCACAF Champions League.
Seattle Sounders FC have qualified as the 2022 CONCACAF Champions League winners.

As of May 15, 2024

Regular season

As of July 17, 2024
Source:

Notes
(H) – Home team(A) – Away team

Bold denotes the Player of the Matchday.

2024 MLS referee lockout

Official website</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Sophia Smith (soccer, born 2000)</title><description>Sophia Olivia Smith (born August 10, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a forward for Portland Thorns FC of the National Women's Soccer League (NWSL) and the United States national team. She played college soccer at Stanford University, helping the Cardinal win the national championship in 2019. Smith was the first overall pick in the 2020 NWSL College Draft.
In 2022, Smith was named NWSL Most Valuable Player (MVP) and U.S. Soccer Female Player of the Year. She earned MVP honors at the 2022 NWSL Championship after helping the Thorns win the title. In 2023, she won the NWSL Golden Boot for most goals in the season.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sophia_Smith_(soccer,_born_2000)</link></item><item><title>Canada men's national soccer team</title><description>The Canada men's national soccer team (French: Équipe du Canada de soccer masculin) represents Canada in international soccer competitions since 1924. They are overseen by the Canadian Soccer Association, the governing body for soccer in Canada. They have been a member of FIFA since 1948 and of CONCACAF since 1961.
Canada participated in its second World Cup in 2022 after finishing first in CONCACAF qualifying. Canada competed in its first Copa América in 2024, finishing fourth.
Previously, their top achievements were to win the 1985 CONCACAF Championship to qualify for the 1986 FIFA World Cup and winning the 2000 CONCACAF Gold Cup to qualify for the 2001 FIFA Confederations Cup. Canada is the only national team aside from regional powerhouses Mexico and the United States to win a Gold Cup. Canada also won a gold medal in the 1904 Summer Olympics.
Canada will co-host, along with the United States and Mexico, the 2026 World Cup.

Soccer was being played in Canada with the Dominion Football Association (1877) and Western Football Association (1880) acting as precursors to the modern-day Canadian Soccer Association. In 1885, the WFA sent a team to New Jersey to take on a side put forth by the American Football Association, the then-unofficial governing body of the sport in the United States. In an unofficial friendly, Canada defeated the United States 1–0 in East Newark, New Jersey. The American team won 3–2 in a return match one year later. In 1888, a team represented the WFA in a tour of the British Isles, earning a record of nine wins, five draws, and nine losses. The squad comprised 16 Canadian-born players with the only exception being tour organizer David Forsyth, who had immigrated to Canada one year after his birth.

In 1904 Galt F.C. represented the WFA at the Olympic Games in St Louis, Missouri. As just one of three teams competing, Galt defeated two American clubs, Christian Brothers College (7–0) and St. Rose (4–0) to win the tournament. The Toronto Mail and Empire of November 18, 1904, reports that "Immediately after the game, the Galt aggregation, numbering about 50 persons, retired to the office of James W. Sullivan, chief of the Department of Physical Culture, where they received their prize. After a short talk by Mr. James E. Conlon of the Physical Culture Department, Mayor Mundy, of the City of Galt, presented each player on the winning team with a beautiful gold medal." The medals are clearly engraved with the name of the company in St. Louis that made them.
In 1905, a British team of touring amateurs nicknamed the "Pilgrims" toured Canada, with their match against Galt billed as the "championship of the world". The match was played in front of 3500 fans in Galt, now part of Cambridge, Ontario, and ended in a 3–3 draw. Earlier the Pilgrims had been beaten 2–1 by Berlin Rangers, in the city now known as Kitchener.

The Canadian national team toured Australia in 1924, playing a series of "test" friendlies against their hosts, including their first official match, a 3–2 friendly defeat to the Australian national team in Brisbane, Queensland on June 7, 1924. Canada also played Australia at the Jubilee Oval, Adelaide on Saturday July 12, 1924, and defeated them by 4 goals to 1. In 1925, Canada played their old rivals, the United States, in Montreal, winning 1–0 on Ed McLaine's goal. In a return match in November 1925 in Brooklyn, New York, Canada was defeated 1–6. One year later, Canada lost 2–6 to the Americans in the same city before playing four internationals in a 1927 tour of New Zealand.
The New Zealand tour included a total of 22 games, of which Canada won 19 with only 2 defeats. Most of the games were against local combined teams although Canada also played New Zealand in four occasions (scores: 2–2, 2–1, 0–1, 4–1).

Following the lead of British soccer associations, Canada withdrew from FIFA in 1928 over a dispute regarding broken time payments to amateur players. They rejoined the confederation in 1946 and took part in World Cup qualifying in the North American Football Confederation (NAFC) (a precursor to CONCACAF) for the first time in 1957, the first time they had played as a national team in 30 years. Under the guidance of head coach Don Petrie, Canada defeated the United States in Toronto 5–1 in their opening game, but lost two games in Mexico (failing to play a home game due to financial reasons) 0–2 and 0–3 before defeating the U.S. 3–2 in St. Louis. Mexico advanced as group winners, meaning that Canada missed out on the World Cup in 1958 in Sweden.
Canada withdrew from World Cup qualifying for 1962 and did not enter a team for 1966. They did compete in soccer however at the 1967 Pan American Games, their first time to do so in the sixth edition of the games, which they hosted in Winnipeg. Canada finished fourth place, helped somewhat by defending champion Brazil's absence.
A 0–0 draw away to Bermuda meant the Canadians, under coach Peter Dinsdale, could not advance out of the first round of qualifying for the 1970 World Cup. Dinsdale was replaced by Frank Pike. In their second participation in soccer at the Pan Am games, held in Cali, Canada finished second in their opening round group (to hosts Colombia). In the final group round however, they managed only one win (over Colombia) and finished next to last.
Canada again failed at the first hurdle in qualifying for the 1974 World Cup. Under German head coach Eckhard Krautzun, they finished second in a home and away qualifying group for the 1973 CONCACAF Championship (to Mexico). For the 1975 Pan Am Games, Canada, along with most of the larger Pan Am countries, sent their Olympic team, which was amateur (and senior aged), to compete. After narrowly qualifying out of the first round, the Canucks were soundly defeated by Costa Rica, Cuba, and Mexico, conceding a total of 14 goals while scoring none. At the Summer Olympics at home the following year, under head coach Colin Morris, the amateur Canadian side failed to get out of the first round, losing both of their games. This despite the brilliant play of Jimmy Douglas, who scored a goal against a Dynamo Kyiv-dominated Soviet Union side and another goal against North Korea, Canada's only two goals in the tournament.
In their North American qualifying group for the 1977 CONCACAF Championship, with both group winners and runners-up now advancing, Canada, again under head coach Krautzun, qualified as runners-up after defeating the Americans 3–0 in a neutral site one-match play-off, played in Port-au-Prince. In the championship, played in Monterrey and Mexico City, Mexico won all five of their matches with a plus 15 goals difference to win the tournament handily. Canada finished fourth.
Matters were different however at the next CONCACAF championship, in 1981, played in Tegucigalpa. Canada entered the tournament raising eyebrows by winning their qualifying group over Mexico and the United States, even achieving a 1–1 draw against Mexico at the Azteca Stadium with Gerry Gray scoring from a direct free kick in the 88th-minute. In the final round, the Canadians opened strongly with a 1–0 win over El Salvador, with Mike Stojanovic the goal-scorer, and a 1–1 draw with Haiti, with Stojanovic scoring again. They next lost to the hosts Honduras 1–2 and then drew Mexico 1–1 with Ian Bridge scoring the equalizer via a corner kick.  A win in their final game against Cuba would have put them through to Spain, but they were held to a 2–2 draw, allowing El Salvador to qualify as tournament runners-up.
1981 through 1985 saw Canada continue to develop under the guidance of English coach Tony Waiters. After a strong performance at the 1984 Summer Olympics, Waiters would see the Maple Leafs through to their first World Cup finals appearance in 1985. A 1–1 away draw to Guatemala was key in allowing them to eliminate Los Chapines in the first round group. The second round was also closely contested, in part as this Canadian squad was strong defensively but had limited ability to score goals. The Canucks managed to eke out a 1–0 away win over Honduras, thanks to a George Pakos winner, hold Costa Rica scoreless in San José, and then in their final game, one they needed to draw to qualify, beat Los Catrachos a second time, 2–1 in St. John's, Newfoundland, with Pakos and Igor Vrablic the goal scorers. The victory not only secured their first World Cup finals berth, but also the crown of CONCACAF champions for the first time, although Mexico did not compete, having already qualified automatically for the World Cup as hosts.
At the 1986 FIFA World Cup, Canada impressed defensively in their first game against France, only conceding a late Jean-Pierre Papin goal after Papin had missed several earlier chances.
However, Canada could not build on their stubborn performance against France, losing their next two matches to both Hungary and the Soviet Union 0–2, finishing the group in last place with zero points.
Four Canadian players (Chris Chueden, Hector Marinaro, David Norman and Vrablic) were involved in a match fixing betting scandal at the Merlion Cup tournament in Singapore two months after the World Cup. The four players were suspended by the Canadian Soccer Association for "bringing the game into disrepute". Norman was reinstated in 1992 after admitting his involvement in the scandal. Vrablic never played for Canada again.

Qualification for 1990 lasted all of two matches for Canada, a home-and-away series with Guatemala, played in October 1988. The Central Americans won the first game 1–0 in Guatemala City while Canada prevailed in Vancouver 3–2. Tied on goal difference, Los Chapines advanced on away goal rule.
1990 saw Canada take part in the first North American Nations Cup, hosting the three-team tournament. Mexico and Canada sent their full squads, but the United States sent a 'B' team. Canada won the tournament after a 1–0 win over the United States on May 6 and a 2–1 win over Mexico on May 13. All three Canadian goals were scored by John Catliff, the tournament's top scorer.
Canada came close to qualifying for the World Cup again in 1994 under the guidance of a defender on the 1986 team, Bob Lenarduzzi. They entered the tournament at the second round stage and advanced as group runners-up. Canada competed strongly in the final qualifying round, drawing their first match in Tegucigalpa after a controversial penalty allowed the Hondurans to draw even, winning their next two, over El Salvador and Honduras in Vancouver, losing convincingly at Azteca Stadium, and winning 2–1 in San Salvador. They went into their final group match against Mexico, in Toronto, needing a win to win the group and thus qualify directly for the World Cup. Canada went up 1–0 on a goal credited to Alex Bunbury off a free kick, but Mexico scored twice to win, 2–1. The loss meant Canada finished second and advanced to an intercontinental play-off series where they needed to win two rounds to qualify for the 1994 FIFA World Cup. The Reds went up against Oceania Football Confederation's champions Australia. Canada won the first leg 2–1 in Edmonton. Australia led the second leg 2–1 at the end of 90 minutes, sending the tie to extra time. There was no score in the extra 30 minutes, meaning the series was decided by a penalty shootout which Australia won 4–1 to eliminate Canada from contention. Australia went on to lose 2–1 on aggregate to Argentina, who advanced to the World Cup.
With the World Cup to be played in the United States, Canada had the opportunity to play a number of high-profile squads in tune-up matches. The highlight of this set of matches—played against Morocco, Brazil, Germany, Spain, and the Netherlands all within 13 days—was Canada holding eventual World Cup champions Brazil to a 1–1 draw at Commonwealth Stadium, on a 69th-minute equalizer by Eddy Berdusco, on Canada's only real scoring chance in the game.
With three countries set to qualify out of CONCACAF for the 1998 World Cup, and with Canada handily winning their second round group over El Salvador, Panama, and Cuba, expectations were high for a second qualification in 12 years in the spring of 1997. The aging Canadians, however, fared miserably, losing their opening game to Mexico 0–4 and the following one to the U.S. 0–3. In their next two matches, against El Salvador and Jamaica, they could only manage two 0–0 draws in Vancouver. A 1–0 win over Costa Rica in Edmonton in their next match thanks to a goal by Berdusco gave Canada some hope at the halfway point but losses to both Jamaica and El Salvador away ended any aspirations as they finished bottom of the group with 6 points from 10 games and a −15 goal difference. Having overseen two consecutive World Cup campaigns ending in the side failing to qualify, Lenarduzzi stepped down in 1997 and was replaced by interim head coach Bruce Twamley.

The Canadian Soccer Association turned to another German to lead the senior national team in 1998 with the signing of Holger Osieck. Success came quickly with Canada winning the CONCACAF Gold Cup in February 2000. After emerging from the first round on a coin-toss tiebreaker with invited side Republic of Korea, the Canucks scored a quarter-final upset win over Mexico. The win set the stage for an unprecedented run to the final, where Canada defeated Colombia 2–0 at Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum. Canada swept the awards ceremony, with goalkeeper Craig Forrest winning MVP honours, Carlo Corazzin securing the Golden Boot, and Richard Hastings named Rookie of the Tournament.
Expectations were again high following the winter's result, but the campaign sputtered. A positive 1–0 away result in Havana in June was followed by a listless 0–0 home draw against Cuba. For the semi-final round two out of four teams advanced. Canada was eliminated from World Cup contention after finishing third in the semi-final round. Canada managed just one goal in 6 games while conceding 8 to finish third in the standings, well adrift of advancing sides Trinidad and Tobago and Mexico.
Winning the Gold Cup earned Canada a place in the 2001 Confederations Cup, where the highlight was holding Brazil to a 0–0 draw. The Gold Cup victory also won them an invitation to compete in the Copa América 2001. When security concerns prompted the cancellation of the tournament, Canada disbanded their training camp. The tournament was then reinstated and held on schedule. The Canadian Soccer Association announced they would not be able to participate in the reinstated tournament.
Canada had another strong showing in the 2002 CONCACAF Gold Cup, losing to the United States in the semi-finals in penalties, and then defeating South Korea in the third-place game, 2–1. There was a Gold Cup held the following year so as to hold the event in years between the World Cup and the Olympics, and Canada was eliminated in the first round on goal difference. Head coach Osieck had seen the side progress. The coach resigned in September 2003 and former player Colin Miller was put in charge as an interim.
2004 marked the beginning of 2006 World Cup qualification and a new era under the guidance of former Canadian skipper Frank Yallop. Things began brightly, with the Canadians dispatching of Belize handily in the Premilinary Round, 8–0 on aggregate, in a home-and-home series. Matters turned, however, with Canada finishing bottom in a group featuring Costa Rica, Guatemala, and Honduras. They got only 5 points from 6 matches and a −4 goal difference. Hard times continued under Yallop as the Canucks again went out at the first barrier in the Gold Cup, losing to both the U.S. and Costa Rica, while defeating Cuba. The coach stayed on through 2005 into the following summer, overseeing a series a friendlies against European sides. He resigned on June 7, 2006, finishing with a win-lose record of 8–9–3.
Things turned around under interim coach Stephen Hart's guidance. Canada opened their 2007 CONCACAF Gold Cup campaign with a 2–1 win over Costa Rica. A 1–2 upset loss to upstarts Guadeloupe was followed by a 2–0 victory over Haiti, securing Canada first-place in their group. They next beat Guatemala 3–0 in their quarter-final match setting up a semi-final showdown with the host Americans. Substitute Iain Hume scored for Canada in the 76th minute to cut the United States' lead to 2–1. After the United States were reduced to ten men, Canada pressed for the equalizer but were denied when Atiba Hutchinson's stoppage-time goal was incorrectly flagged offside by linesman Ricardo Louisville and Canada was eliminated.
The team faced criticism for its poor handling of goalkeeper Greg Sutton, who suffered a concussion during a practice prior to the start of the Gold Cup. Without a doctor accompanying the team, Sutton instead saw a local physician who cleared him to practice, resulting in Sutton suffering post-concussion syndrome. Sutton was lost to his professional club Toronto FC for nearly a year.
Prior to the Gold Cup on May 18, 2007, the Canadian Soccer Association announced that former national team player Dale Mitchell would take over as head coach of the senior team after the 2007 FIFA U-20 World Cup. Mitchell had previously served as an assistant coach under Coach Frank Yallop.  Under Mitchell, Canada drew friendlies with Iceland and against Costa Rica, lost 0–2 to South Africa, had a 1–0 win over Martinique, and a 0–2 defeat to Estonia. Optimism grew, however, as Canada played well in a 2–3 loss to Brazil.
Despite defeating Saint Vincent and the Grenadines 7–1 on aggregate in a second-round series—they had had a bye in the first—Canada did not play at the level they had at the Gold Cup and were eliminated from qualifying for the 2010 World Cup. They conceded an equalizer shortly after scoring the opening goal in a 1–1 draw to Jamaica at BMO Field, conceded two second-half goals in quick succession in a 1–2 home loss to Honduras at Saputo Stadium, and then lost away to Mexico and Honduras. They finished last in the four-team group with just 2 points from 6 matches. On March 27, 2009, head coach Dale Mitchell was fired. The president of the Canadian Soccer Association, Dominic Maestracci, said that "the Canadian Soccer Association is committed to the future of our men's national team program. We have made this decision to move the program in a new direction." Technical director Stephen Hart was renamed as interim head coach. On December 9, 2009, Hart was named as head coach.

Stephen Hart's first competitive action as the full-time head coach was a poor showing at the 2011 CONCACAF Gold Cup, not managing to get out of the group stage. However, during the early stages qualifying for the 2014 World Cup, Canada topped their group in the second round but were eliminated in the third round of CONCACAF qualifying, finishing one point behind Honduras and Panama after losing 8–1 in Honduras on the final match day.
After a series of interim coaching changes following Stephen Hart's dismissal on October 12, 2012 Benito Floro replaced Colin Miller as Canada's coach on August 1, 2013. Being a coach with top-flight management experience in La Liga, he was expected to help Canada raise its competitiveness prior to 2018 FIFA World Cup qualification. In the midst of Floro's player identification and restructuring phase, the team experienced many difficulties including a 958-minute goal-scoring drought, which was finally broken by Atiba Hutchinson in a 1–1 draw with Bulgaria on May 23, 2014. Despite showing improvement with two draws in Europe, Canada continued to shed FIFA points having gone winless for nearly two years, and sank to their lowest ever FIFA ranking of 122 in August 2014. Canada ended a 16-match winless streak on September 10, 2014, defeating Jamaica 3–1 in Toronto.
Canada was drawn into the 2018 FIFA World Cup second round of qualifying against Dominica in June 2015. Canada entered the second round of 2018 World Cup qualifying against Dominica with a game at Windsor Park in Dominica which they won 2–0 with goals from Cyle Larin and a penalty converted by Russell Teibert. In the return leg at BMO Field in front of 9,749 fans they defeated Dominica 4–0 with two goals from Tosaint Ricketts and one each from Tesho Akindele and Cyle Larin.
The team did not score a single goal and finished last in their group in the 2015 CONCACAF Gold Cup after two 0–0 draws to El Salvador and Costa Rica, while also suffering a 1–0 loss against Jamaica.
Canada then advanced to the third round of 2018 World Cup qualifying against Belize, winning 4–1 on aggregate and advancing to the fourth round of 2018 World Cup qualifying. Canada was drawn into a group against Honduras, El Salvador and Mexico. They played their first pair of matches in the fourth round on November 13 and 17, 2015. The first match was played in Vancouver at BC Place against Honduras, resulting in a 1–0 win for Canada thanks to a deflected goal by Cyle Larin. The crowd of 20,108 set a new record for the Canadian men's team in the province of British Columbia.  In their next game on November 17, away at El Salvador, Canada drew with El Salvador 0-0 as Julian De Guzman broke Canada's record for most caps for the national team with his 85th cap, passing Paul Stalteri's record of 84 caps. With this result in Canada's last game of 2015, they ended off the year conceding just three goals in their final 12 games and in 14 games overall, they ended off with a record of 6 wins, 6 draws, and 2 losses.
On March 25, 2016, in a World Cup qualifier against Mexico at BC Place Stadium in Vancouver, 54,798 people were recorded in the stadium which set a new attendance record for a Canadian national team of any sport. Ultimately, however, Canada lost the game 3–0, but remained in second place in the group, keeping them in contention for World Cup qualification. On September 6, 2016, after not being able to qualify for the fifth round of the 2018 World Cup qualifying despite a 3–1 win over El Salvador, head coach Benito Floro was sacked on September 14, ending his reign as coach of the national team.

Canada announced Octavio Zambrano as the new coach of the national team on May 16, 2017, replacing Michael Findlay who was the interim coach after Floro's departure. He guided Canada to a quarterfinal finish at the 2017 CONCACAF Gold Cup, with the team getting out of the group stage for the first time since 2009. However, on January 8, 2018, Zambrano was let go and was replaced with John Herdman, who previously was the head coach of the Canadian women's national team.
Under Herdman, Canada qualified for the top division in the inaugural season of the CONCACAF Nations League following an undefeated qualifying campaign. Competing in CONCACAF Nations League A, Canada earned a 2–0 victory over the United States at BMO Field, Canada's first win against their American rivals since 1985. However, Canada would fall to a 4–1 defeat against the United States in the away leg and failed to qualify for the Nations League Finals.

Canada's national team was marked by the arrival of a golden generation of new young players, led by the first Canadian UEFA Champions League winner Alphonso Davies of Bayern Munich, the most expensive Canadian soccer player in history, Jonathan David who joined Lille for a €30-million fee in 2020 and the establishment of the Canadian Premier League, the first fully professional soccer league in the country. In the first round of World Cup qualifying, Canada finished with a 4–0–0 record to win Group B and progress to the second round. The second round was two leg home-and-away tie against Haiti which Canada won 4–0 on aggregate with a 1–0 win in the away leg and a 3–0 win in the home leg, the latter being played at SeatGeek Stadium in Chicago due to COVID-19 restrictions in Canada. The victory over Haiti led to Canada qualifying for the third and final round of World Cup qualifying for the first time since 1997.

Canada began the third round of World Cup qualifying unbeaten in its first eleven matches, finishing 2021 with its first win over Mexico in over 20 years to finish the year at the top of the table. It also ended the year 40th in the FIFA World Rankings, its highest-ever position to date, earning the team the honour of "Most Improved Side" after having started the year ranked 72nd.
On March 27, 2022, Canada defeated Jamaica 4–0 on Matchday 13 to qualify for the 2022 FIFA World Cup in Qatar. This ended a 36-year drought since the first and only time Canada played in the FIFA World Cup, in 1986. The speed of the team's ascent was such that it was subsequently revealed that neither the federation nor kit supplier Nike had anticipated them qualifying, and as a result they would be the only team in Qatar to not receive a special kit for the occasion. Defender Sam Adekugbe remarked "I think that just shows that no one really believed in us. I don't think Canada believed."

In Canada's first match of the tournament against Belgium on November 23, Davies failed to score an early penalty in an eventual 1–0 loss, despite Canada dictating most of the play, and failing to convert any of their 22 shots. Four days later, Davies scored Canada's first ever goal at the FIFA World Cup, in a game against Croatia. Croatia came back to win 4–1, eliminating Canada from the tournament after two matches. Canada were defeated 2–1 by Morocco in their final group match on December 1, finishing in last place in their group with zero points. Post-event assessments of Canada's performance were mixed, with many saying that opportunities had been missed, while also creating possibilities for the future 2026 FIFA World Cup that Canada would co-host.

Canada automatically qualified for the 2026 World Cup as co-host in February 2023. They also qualified to the 2023 CONCACAF Nations League Finals by winning Group C. A 2–0 victory over Panama on June 15, 2023 saw the national team reach its first event final in 23 years, where they lost to the United States 2–0. Following this, many of the team's established players opted not to attend the 2023 CONCACAF Gold Cup held later that same summer. After some difficulties in the group stage, Canada reached the quarter-final of the tournament, losing to the United States in a penalty shootout. The summer championships marked the end of Herdman's tenure with Canada Soccer, with his departure coming at the end of August to manage Toronto FC of Major League Soccer, amidst media discussion of conflicts with the federation over funding and playing opportunities.
Interim coach Mauro Biello was tasked with guiding the team through the quarter-finals of the 2023–24 CONCACAF Nations League A in November 2023, where victory in a two-legged aggregate match or away goals rule against Jamaica would both send them to the following spring's semi-finals and qualify them to participate in CONMEBOL's 2024 Copa América. After defeating Jamaica 2–1 in the away leg, Canada needed only a draw in the home match at BMO Field to advance. Leading halfway through, the team collapsed to lose 3–2 in the second half and 3–2 on away goals, as a result missing both the Nation's League semi-final and immediate qualification to the Copa América. The loss to Jamaica prompted considerable criticism of the team, Biello, and the federation, with The Athletic opining that Canada's "humiliating loss" should be considered its worst defeat since falling 8–1 to Honduras in World Cup qualification in 2012. As a result, the qualifying play-off for a final place in the Copa América was scheduled on March 23, 2024 against Trinidad and Tobago, which they later won 2–0.
In May 2024, Canada Soccer hired Jesse Marsch to serve as Herdman's permanent replacement as coach. Due to ongoing financial difficulties, the money to pay Marsch was found via donations from MLS clubs CF Montreal, Toronto FC, and Vancouver Whitecaps FC and other private parties. This drew media attention due to the unusual arrangement of the naming rights to the coaching position being given as part of the arrangement, called the "MLS Canada Men's National Team Head Coach". In advance of the Copa América, Marsch's first matches with the team were two friendlies against high-profile opponents, first a lopsided 4–0 loss to the Netherlands, and then a goalless draw with second-ranked France that was generally considered a major success. Canada began Group A play at the Copa against world number one-ranked Argentina, a 2–0 loss that nevertheless was generally considered a credible showing. They defeated Peru 1–0, with David scoring the team's first goal of the Marsch era to earn the country's first victory over a South American team since the 2000 Gold Cup final. A draw with Chile saw Canada finish second in the group and advance to the knockout stage, where they defeated Venezuela 4–3 on penalties after a 1–1 draw in regulation time to reach a semi-final rematch with Argentina. After another 2–0 loss to the Argentines, Canada played Uruguay in the third-place match. They led 2–1 for the final ten minutes of regulation, but allowed a tying goal in stoppage time, and lost 4–3 on penalties to finish fourth.

Canada has a rivalry with the United States. The United States-Canada rivalry stems from a generally friendly rivalry between the two nations. The two teams frequently face each other in the Gold Cup. The United States currently leads the series 18-10-11 (W-L-T). Historically, the United States has been the stronger side, having qualified for 11 World Cups while Canada qualified for two. Until recently, Canada was not seen as a competitive rival by a number of American fans as it had not beaten the United States in a 34-year stretch. That streak was snapped on October 15, 2019, when Canada defeated the United States 2–0 at BMO Field in Toronto. The following month, on November 15, the United States beat Canada 4–1 in Orlando. Since then, matches between the two have been very competitive. The United States defeated Canada 1–0 in a 2021 Gold Cup matchup in Kansas City. In 2022 World Cup qualifying, Canada earned a 1–1 draw in Nashville and defeated the United States 2–0 in Hamilton. 
On June 18, 2023 the United States defeated Canada 2-0 in the 2022-23 CONCACAF Nations League final, marking the first time the two nations faced each other in the final of a major CONCACAF tournament. Three weeks later, the U.S. eliminated Canada 3–2 on penalties in the 2023 CONCACAF Gold Cup quarter-final.

BMO Field is Canada's largest natural turf stadium, followed by Saputo Stadium, in Montreal. Canada played their 2018 FIFA World Cup qualifiers at BC Place in Vancouver. During 2022 FIFA World Cup qualifying, Canada used BMO Field in Toronto, Commonwealth Stadium in Edmonton, and Tim Hortons Field in Hamilton. Due to travel restrictions during the COVID-19 pandemic, Canada played their home games for the first and second rounds of 2022 World Cup qualifying in stadiums in the United States.

The following is a list of match results in the last twelve months, as well as any future matches that have been scheduled.
  Win
  Draw
  Loss
  Fixture

 

 
 

As of May 29, 2024

Caretaker managers are listed in italics.

The following 26 players were selected for the 2024 Copa América.  
Caps and goals as of July 13, 2024, after the match against  Uruguay.

The following players have also been called up within the last twelve months.

As of July 13, 2024, after the match against  Uruguay.
Players in bold are still active with the national team.

  Champions    Runners-up    Third place     Tournament played fully or partially on home soil  

*Denotes draws include knockout matches decided via penalty shoot-out.

*Denotes draws include knockout matches decided via penalty shoot-out.

After 1988, Olympic soccer was contested by the U–23 team.

Key
 
The following table shows Canada's all-time official international record per opponent:

As of July 13, 2024

Major competitions

CONCACAF Championship / Gold Cup
Champions (2): 1985, 2000
Third place (2): 2002, 2007
CONCACAF Nations League
Runners-up: 2022–23
Other competitions

North American Nations Cup
Winners: 1990
Summer Olympics
Winners: 1904
CONCACAF Olympic Qualifying Tournament
Runners-up: 1984
Canada Cup 
Runners-up: 1995

Canada Soccer Association
CONCACAF
National teams
Men's
Canada men's national under-23 soccer team
Canada men's national under-20 soccer team
Canada men's national under-17 soccer team
Canada men's national beach soccer team
Canada men's national futsal team
Women's
Canada women's national soccer team
Canada women's national under-20 soccer team
Canada women's national under-17 soccer team

Kloke, Joshua (October 4, 2022). The Voyageurs: The Canadian Men's Soccer Team's Quest to Reach the World Cup. Dundurn Press. ISBN 978-1459750456.

Official website 
FIFA profile
Canada Soccer records and results for 2024
RSSSF archive of most capped players and highest goalscorers
International results until 1999</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.

The first United States national soccer team was constituted in 1885, when it played Canada in the first international match held outside the United Kingdom. Canada defeated the U.S. 1–0 in Newark, New Jersey. A second match in Newark the following year resulted in the U.S. defeating Canada 1–0, although neither match was officially recognized. The U.S. earned both silver and bronze medals in men's tournament at the 1904 St. Louis Summer Olympics through Christian Brothers College and St. Rose Parish, though the tournament is declared official only by the IOC; FIFA does not endorse tournaments held before 1908. The U.S. played its first official international match under the auspices of U.S. Soccer on August 20, 1916, against Sweden in Stockholm, where the U.S. won 3–2.

The U.S. fielded a team in the 1930 World Cup in Uruguay, the first edition of the World Cup. The U.S. began group play by beating Belgium 3–0, and then earned a 3–0 victory over Paraguay, with FIFA crediting Bert Patenaude with two of the goals. In November 2006, FIFA announced that it had accepted evidence that Patenaude scored all three goals against Paraguay, and was thus the first person to score a hat trick in a World Cup. In the semifinals, the U.S. lost to Argentina 6–1 and were eliminated. There was no third place game; however, using the overall tournament records in 1986, FIFA credited the Americans with a third-place finish ahead of fellow semifinalist Yugoslavia. This remains the U.S. team's best World Cup result, and is the highest finish of any team from outside of South America and Europe.
The U.S. qualified for the 1934 World Cup by defeating Mexico 4–2 in Italy a few days before the tournament opened. In a straight knock-out format, the team first played host Italy and lost 7–1, eliminating the U.S. from the tournament. At the 1936 Olympic Games in Berlin, the U.S. lost 1–0 to Italy in the first round and were eliminated. Italy went on to win both tournaments.
The 1950 World Cup in Brazil was the next World Cup appearance for the United States, as it withdrew in 1938 and the tournament was not held again until 1950 due to World War II. The U.S. lost its first match 3–1 against Spain, but then won 1–0 against England at Independência Stadium in Belo Horizonte. Striker Joe Gaetjens was the lone goalscorer in the match, which was called "The Miracle on Grass" and considered one of the greatest upsets in the history of the World Cup. The U.S. were eliminated from the tournament in their third game, a 5–2 defeat to Chile.

The national team spent the mid-to-late 20th century in near complete irrelevance in both the international game and the domestic sporting scene. CONCACAF had only one World Cup berth until 1982. Playing only two matches from 1981 to 1983, U.S. Soccer targeted the 1984 Summer Olympics in Los Angeles and the 1986 World Cup to rebuild the national team and its fan base. The International Olympic Committee declared that teams from outside Europe and South America could field full senior teams, including professionals. The U.S. finished with a 1–1–1 record in the group stage of the tournament but did not qualify for the second round, losing to Egypt on a tiebreaker.
To provide a more stable national team program and renew interest in the North American Soccer League, U.S. Soccer entered the national team into the NASL league schedule for the 1983 season as Team America. This team lacked the continuity and regularity of training that conventional clubs enjoy, and many players were unwilling to play for the national team instead of their own clubs when conflicts arose. Team America finished the season at the bottom of the league, with U.S. Soccer canceling the experiment and withdrawing the national team from the NASL after one season. By the end of 1984, the NASL had folded, leaving the U.S. without a single professional-level outdoor soccer league.
The 1986 World Cup was hosted by Mexico after Colombia withdrew from contention due to economic concerns and the United States lost their subsequent bid to host. In the last game of CONCACAF qualifying for the 1986 World Cup, the U.S. needed only a tie against Costa Rica to reach the final qualification group against Honduras and Canada. U.S. Soccer scheduled the game to be played in Torrance, California, an area with many Costa Rican expatriates, and marketed the game almost exclusively to the Costa Rican community. Costa Rica won the match 1–0, and kept the U.S. from reaching its fourth World Cup finals.

On July 4, 1988, FIFA named the U.S. as the host of the 1994 World Cup under significant international criticism given the perceived weakness of the national team and the lack of a professional outdoor league. The U.S. qualified for the 1990 World Cup with a 1–0 win against Trinidad and Tobago in the last match of the 1989 CONCACAF Championship. Mexico had been disqualified from the CONCACAF Championship for using ineligible players in a youth tournament, which allowed a chance for the U.S. to qualify for their first World Cup in 40 years.
The team was coached by Bob Gansler, Wisconsin-Milwaukee and U20 national team coach, in preparation for the 1990 World Cup in Italy. Two of the team's more experienced players, Rick Davis and Hugo Perez, were unavailable for selection while recovering from injuries. Rather than fill out his team with veteran professionals from U.S. indoor soccer leagues, Gansler and his assistant Stejem Mark chose to select many younger players with better conditioning for the outdoor game, including several collegiate players such as Virginia goalkeeper Tony Meola. The U.S. entered the tournament as major underdogs and lost all three of its group games to Czechoslovakia, Italy, and Austria. Defenders Jimmy Banks and Desmond Armstrong became the first African Americans to appear in a World Cup match for the United States.
During the 1993 U.S. Cup, a tournament designed to prepare for the upcoming World Cup, the U.S. beat England 2–0. After qualifying automatically as the host of the 1994 World Cup under Bora Milutinović, the U.S. opened the tournament schedule with a 1–1 tie against Switzerland in the Pontiac Silverdome in the suburbs of Detroit, the first World Cup game played indoors. In its second game, the U.S. faced Colombia, then ranked fourth in the world, at the Rose Bowl. Aided by an own goal from Andrés Escobar, the U.S. won 2–1; Escobar was later murdered in his home country, possibly in retaliation for this mistake. Despite a 1–0 loss to Romania in its final group game, the U.S. made it past the initial round for the first time since 1930. In the round of 16, the U.S. lost 1–0 to the eventual champion Brazil. U.S. Soccer later fired Milutinović in 1995 because he was reportedly not interested in administrative duties in addition to coaching.
The U.S. were invited to play in the 1995 Copa América, where they finished first in their group after defeating Chile and Argentina in an upset victory. In the quarterfinals, the U.S. defeated Mexico on penalties, and then lost to Brazil 1–0 in the semifinals. The United States finished fourth after losing to Colombia in the third-place match.
In the 1998 World Cup in France, the team lost all three group matches, 2–0 to Germany, 2–1 to Iran, and 1–0 to Yugoslavia, finishing last in the field of 32. The tournament was marred by disputes between the players and head coach Steve Sampson, who resigned shortly after the tournament.

Under former D.C. United head coach Bruce Arena, the U.S. qualified for the 2002 World Cup and reached the quarterfinals, their best finish in a World Cup since 1930. The team earned four points in the group stage, beginning with a 3–2 win over Portugal, followed by a 1–1 tie with co-host and eventual semifinalist South Korea. The third and final match was a 3–1 loss to Poland; the team still advanced to the round of 16 when South Korea defeated Portugal. The U.S. met continental rivals Mexico for the first time in a World Cup, and won the game 2–0, with goals from Brian McBride and Landon Donovan. In the quarterfinals, the USMNT met Germany and lost 1–0 after being controversially denied a penalty when Torsten Frings handled the ball to prevent a Gregg Berhalter goal. Donovan won the Best Young Player for the tournament.
In the 2006 World Cup, after finishing top of the CONCACAF qualification tournament, the U.S. was drawn into Group E along with the Czech Republic, Italy, and Ghana. The United States opened the tournament with a 3–0 loss to the Czech Republic. The team then tied 1–1 against eventual winners Italy, and then were knocked out of the tournament when they were beaten 2–1 by Ghana in its final group match, with Clint Dempsey scoring the U.S.'s only goal in the tournament (the goal against Italy had been an own goal by Italian defender Cristian Zaccardo). Following the tournament, Arena's contract was not renewed; his assistant, former Chicago Fire and MetroStars head coach Bob Bradley, became interim head coach in December 2006 and was selected for the full-time role in May 2007.
After winning the 2007 Gold Cup against Mexico, the USMNT qualified for the 2009 Confederations Cup. The U.S. shocked the soccer world by defeating top-ranked Spain, who were on a 35-game undefeated streak, 2–0. With the win, the United States advanced to its first-ever final in a men's FIFA tournament. The team lost 3–2 to Brazil after leading 2–0 at half-time. Hosting the 2009 Gold Cup, the United States was beaten by Mexico 5–0 in the final; this defeat broke the U.S. team's 58-match home unbeaten streak against CONCACAF opponents, and was the first home loss to Mexico since 1999 and their first home loss in a competitive match since 1998.
In the fourth round of the 2010 World Cup qualification, Jozy Altidore became the youngest U.S. player to score a hat-trick, in a 3–0 victory over Trinidad and Tobago. On October 10, 2009, the U.S. secured qualification to the 2010 World Cup with a 3–2 win over Honduras. Four days later, the U.S. finished in first place in the final round of qualification with a 2–2 tie against Costa Rica.

In the 2010 World Cup, the USMNT was drawn into Group C against England, Slovenia and Algeria. After drawing against England 1–1 and Slovenia 2–2, the U.S. defeated Algeria 1–0 with a stoppage-time goal from Landon Donovan, taking first place in a World Cup group for the first time since 1930. In the round of 16, the U.S. was eliminated by Ghana, 2–1.
After losing to Mexico 4–2 in the final of the 2011 Gold Cup, Bob Bradley was relieved of his duties and former Germany manager Jürgen Klinsmann was hired as head coach. The U.S. won 1–0 in Genoa, Italy on February 29, 2012, the team's first-ever win over Italy. In July 2013, the United States became North American champions for the fifth time after winning the Gold Cup with a 1–0 victory over Panama in the final, with Landon Donovan winning the tournament's golden ball award. A 4–3 victory over Bosnia and Herzegovina in an international friendly match in Sarajevo represented the 12th consecutive win for the USMNT, the longest active winning streak for any team in the world at that time. The winning streak ended September 6, when the U.S. lost to Costa Rica 3–1 in San José in the final round of qualification. The U.S. eventually clinched a spot in the 2014 World Cup.
The Americans were drawn into Group G, along with Ghana, Germany, and Portugal. The U.S. won 2–1 in their rematch with Ghana. They tied their second group game against Portugal 2–2. In the final game of the group stage, the U.S. fell to Germany 1–0, but moved on to the knockout stage on goal difference. This was the first time that the team made two consecutive trips to the knockout stage of the FIFA World Cup. In the round of 16, the U.S. lost 2–1 to Belgium in extra time, despite goalkeeper Tim Howard making a World Cup record 15 saves during the match.

In the 2015 Gold Cup, the U.S. were eliminated by Jamaica 2–1 in the semifinals, before losing to Panama on penalties in the third place match. It marked the first time the team failed to make the tournament final since 2003. In the 2015 CONCACAF Cup playoff to determine the region's entry to the 2017 Confederations Cup, the U.S. were defeated 3–2 by Mexico at the Rose Bowl. The results led to criticism of Klinsmann's coaching style, particularly the lack of a cohesive identity.
In June 2016, the U.S. hosted the Copa América Centenario, a special edition of the Copa América to commemorate the centenary of the tournament and its first to be played outside of South America. In their third Copa América appearance, the U.S. topped Group A on goal difference against Colombia, and then beat Ecuador 2–1 in the quarterfinals. The team lost 4–0 to Argentina 4–0 in the semifinals and 1–0 to Colombia again in the third place match. The U.S. finished fourth overall, tying their best finish ever in 1995.
Following consecutive losses to Mexico and Costa Rica in the opening games of the final round of qualification for the 2018 World Cup, Klinsmann was removed as national team coach and technical director and replaced by previous U.S. head coach Bruce Arena. World Cup qualification resumed on March 24, 2017, where Arena and his team achieved a record 6–0 win over Honduras. The U.S. got their third ever result in World Cup qualification at the Estadio Azteca when they drew 1–1 against Mexico. In July 2017, the U.S. won their sixth Gold Cup with a 2–1 win over Jamaica in the final. Following a 2–1 defeat to Trinidad and Tobago on October 10, 2017, the U.S. failed to qualify for the 2018 World Cup, missing the tournament for the first time since 1986. Many pundits and analysts called this the worst result and worst performance in the history of the national team.
Following Arena's resignation on October 13, 2017, assistant coach Dave Sarachan was named interim head coach during the search for a permanent replacement. The search for a permanent head coach was delayed by the USSF presidential election in February 2018 and the hiring of Earnie Stewart as general manager in June 2018. Gregg Berhalter, coach of the Columbus Crew and a former USMNT defender, was announced as the team's new head coach on December 2, 2018.
Under Berhalter the team lost in the 2019 Gold Cup final 1–0 against Mexico and were unable to defend their title.

An influx of new young talent playing for top European clubs, widely described as America's golden generation, entered the national team in the late 2010s and early 2020s. These players included Christian Pulisic, Weston McKennie, Tyler Adams, Timothy Weah, Sergiño Dest, and Gio Reyna. This new group won the inaugural CONCACAF Nations League in 2021 with a 3–2 victory against Mexico in the final. A different roster won the Gold Cup against Mexico later that summer, contributing to a record for wins in a calendar year, with 17 wins, three ties, and two losses in 2021.
The United States qualified for the 2022 World Cup by finishing third in the final qualifying round. Grouped with England, Iran, and Wales in Group B, the team advanced to the knockout stage as runners-up with five points and without losing a game. There, they faced the Netherlands and were defeated 3–1. Midfielder Kellyn Acosta became the first Asian American player to appear for the U.S. at a World Cup.
After Berhalter's contract expired in December 2022, the U.S. searched for a new head coach. Under interim manager B.J. Callaghan in June 2023, the United States successfully defended their Nations League trophy by winning the 2022–23 CONCACAF Nations League. The team conceded no goals in the finals tournament, winning 3–0 against Mexico and 2–0 against Canada in the final match. Callaghan remained the team's manager for the 2023 Gold Cup the following month, which was played with a different roster. The U.S. were eliminated in the semifinals by Panama after losing a penalty shootout.
The United States automatically qualified for the 2026 World Cup as co-host in February 2023, and secured a spot at the U.S.-hosted 2024 Copa América by defeating Trinidad and Tobago 4–2 over two legs in November 2023. Gregg Berhalter was reappointed as coach of the United States on June 16, 2023. In March 2024, the United States won their third CONCACAF Nations League title by defeating Mexico 2–0 in the final. The Nations League title qualified the United States for the Copa América, where they were eliminated in the group stage. The 1–0 loss in the final group stage match against Uruguay included several controversial decisions from referee Kevin Ortega, including an offside review for Uruguay's goal and handling of yellow cards. Following the team's elimination, Berhalter was fired as head coach on July 10, 2024.

Since their first unofficial game against Canada, the most common U.S. uniform has been white tops with blue shorts. A variant with a diagonal stripe or "sash" across the shirt similar to Peru's jersey was first adopted in 1950 and used in various uniforms in the 2000. A color scheme based on the U.S. flag—usually a shirt with red and white stripes with blue shorts—has been occasionally used (most prominently in the 1994 World Cup and 2012–13 qualifiers as well the 1983 Team America franchise of the North American Soccer League).
German brand Adidas provided the uniform for the United States from 1984 to 1994. Since 1995, American company Nike has been the uniform supplier. The final Adidas jersey was a denim-inspired blue shirt with white stars paired with red shorts.

The United States and Mexico have been the most successful teams in CONCACAF and are major rivals. They first met in 1934 during a World Cup qualifier in Rome that the U.S. won; Mexico won the following 24 meetings and were perennial qualifiers for the World Cup. Since 1980, the U.S. has had more wins against Mexico, particularly in home matches and major tournaments.
The two teams met in the knockout stage of the 2002 World Cup in the round of 16, with the United States winning 2–0. On August 15, 2012, the United States defeated Mexico at Estadio Azteca in the first victory for the U.S. against Mexico on Mexican soil in 75 years. On October 10, 2015, Mexico defeated the U.S. 3–2 in the CONCACAF Cup to qualify for the 2017 Confederations Cup. Thirteen months later, on November 11, 2016, El Tri defeated the U.S. for their second consecutive victory on American soil, in qualification for the 2018 World Cup. In 2021, the United States defeated Mexico three times in a calendar year for the first time, with the U.S. winning the CONCACAF Nations League final, the Gold Cup final, and in 2022 World Cup qualifying.
Ever since their first meeting in 1934, the two teams have met 77 times, with Mexico leading 36W–17T–24L, outscoring the U.S. 145–92. However, because of recent growth of soccer in the U.S., since the beginning of the 21st century, the U.S. leads the series 19W–8T–9L. Either the United States or Mexico has won every edition of the Gold Cup except one (the 2000 Gold Cup was won by Canada).

The U.S. has a secondary rivalry with Canada. The United States has historically been the stronger side, having qualified for 11 World Cups while Canada has qualified for two. 
On October 15, 2019, Canada defeated the United States for the first time in 34 years, at BMO Field in Toronto. In 2022 World Cup qualifying, Canada tied 1–1 with the U.S. in Nashville, Tennessee, and defeated the U.S. 2–0 in Hamilton, Ontario. On June 18, 2023, the United States defeated Canada 2–0 in the 2022–23 CONCACAF Nations League final in Las Vegas. The U.S. defeated Canada yet again in a 2023 Gold Cup quarterfinal matchup, this time 3–2 on penalties. The United States currently leads the series with 18 wins, 11 draws, and 11 losses.

In the 2010s, the United States began to develop a rivalry with Costa Rica. The impetus for the rivalry was a 2014 World Cup qualifying match played on March 22, 2013, at Dick's Sporting Goods Park in Commerce City, Colorado under blizzard conditions. Costa Rica filed a protest with FIFA due to field conditions after the United States won the game 1–0, but were denied recourse. The game was dubbed "Snow Clasico" for the conditions. The United States have never won an away match in Costa Rica, losing 10 meetings and drawing twice.

There have been two main supporter groups backing U.S. Soccer teams, Sam's Army and The American Outlaws. Sam's Army started shortly after the 1994 World Cup and were active through 2014. Sam's Army members wore red to matches and sung or chanted throughout the match, and often brought huge U.S. flags and other banners to the game.
The American Outlaws began in Lincoln, Nebraska, in 2007 as a local supporters' group. The group's membership attempted to address a lack of consistency from game to game in supporter organization and social events on match days. To achieve this goal, the American Outlaws became a nationwide, non-profit supporters' group. Some American Outlaws members wear U.S. flag bandanas over their faces and commonly wear soccer supporter scarves. Some branches of the American Outlaws have their own scarves specific to their branch.
The U.S. men's national team has a major following on social media platforms. Interest in young American players and the attention they bring has led to an increase in foreign investment in U.S. players, soccer development programs, and sports clubs.

The United States does not have a dedicated national stadium like other national teams; instead, the team has played their home matches at various venues across the country. As of 2017, the team has played in 123 stadiums in 30 states and the District of Columbia. Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium, located in the national capital of Washington, D.C., has hosted 24 matches, the most of any stadium. The state of California has hosted 117 matches, the most of any state, and greater Los Angeles has hosted 79 matches at several venues in and around the city of LA. The Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum hosted 20 matches from 1965 to 2000. The Rose Bowl, a 92,000-seat venue in Pasadena, has hosted 17 national team matches, as well as the 1994 World Cup final, the 1999 Women's World Cup final, and the 1984 Olympics gold medal match.

TNT Sports has the English language rights for U.S. Soccer broadcasts from 2022 to 2030. All matches are streaming live on Max with matches also on TNT and TBS. In  June 2021, CBS Sports acquired partial rights to select U.S. Soccer matches, including World Cup qualifiers and the Nations League finals, to be broadcast on CBS Sports Network and the Paramount+ streaming service. Telemundo has the Spanish language rights to all U.S. Soccer broadcasts from 2023 to 2030. These agreements do not apply to World Cup away qualifiers, whose rights are distributed by the host country.

The following is a list of match results in the last 12 months, as well as any future matches that have been scheduled.
  Win
  Draw
  Loss
  Fixture

 
 

 

 

The following table shows the United States all-time international record, correct as of July 1, 2024.

Coaching staff

Technical staff

Coach Gregg Berhalter named a 26-man squad for the 2024 Copa América.
Caps and goals are updated as of July 1, 2024, after the match against Uruguay.

The following players have been called up for the team within the last twelve months.

PRE = Preliminary squad
INJ = Injured
WD = Player withdrew from the squad due to non-injury issue.

As of July 1, 2024.
Players in bold are still active with the national team.

The United States has competed at the FIFA World Cup, the CONCACAF Gold Cup, the CONCACAF Nations League, and the Summer Olympics. The team has also played in the now-defunct FIFA Confederations Cup, the Copa América, as well as several minor tournaments.
The best result for the United States in a World Cup tournament came in 1930 when it reached the semifinals. The team included six naturalized internationals, five of them from Scotland and one from England. In the modern era, the team’s best result came in the 2002 World Cup, when it reached the quarterfinals. Its worst World Cup tournament results in were group-stage eliminations in 1990, 1998, and 2006; the team failed to qualify altogether for the final tournament in 2018. The United States reached the round of 16 in 1994, 2010, 2014, and 2022.
In the Confederations Cup, the United States finished in third place in both 1992 and 1999, and were runner-up in 2009. The team appeared in its first intercontinental tournament final at the 2009 Confederations Cup, where it lost to Brazil 3–2 after leading 2–0 at halftime.
The U.S. men's soccer team first played in the Summer Olympics in 1924. From that tournament to 1980, only amateur and state-sponsored Eastern European players were allowed on Olympic teams. The Olympics became a full international tournament in 1984 after the IOC allowed full national teams from outside FIFA's strongest confederations of UEFA and CONMEBOL. Since 1992 the men's Olympic event has been age-restricted, to those 23 years and younger, with the exception (since 1996) of up to three overage players; participation has been by the United States men's national under-23 soccer team.
In regional competitions, the United States has won the CONCACAF Gold Cup seven times, with its most recent title in 2021. The team won the inaugural CONCACAF Nations League in 2021. Its best finish at the Copa América was fourth place at the 1995 and 2016 editions, while it competed as the host nation in 2024, failing to advance past the group stage.  

CONCACAF Championship 1963–1989, CONCACAF Gold Cup 1991–present

Major competitions

FIFA World Cup
Third place (1):  1930
Summer Olympics
Silver medal (1):  1904
Bronze medal (1):  1904
FIFA Confederations Cup
Runners-up (1):  2009
Third place (2):  1992, 1999
Copa América
Fourth place (2): 1995, 2016
CONCACAF Championship / Gold Cup
Champions (7):  1991, 2002, 2005, 2007, 2013, 2017, 2021
Runners-up (6):  1989, 1993, 1998, 2009, 2011, 2019
Third place (2):  1996, 2003
Fair Play Award (6): 2003, 2009, 2017, 2019, 2021, 2023
CONCACAF Nations League
Champions (3):  2019–20, 2022–23, 2023–24
Other competitions

CONCACAF Cup
Runners-up (1):  2015
CONCACAF Olympic Qualifying Tournament
Runners-up (2):  1972, 1980
Third Place (1):  1964
U.S. Cup
Champions (3):  1992, 1995, 2000
Runners-up (1):  1999
Third place (2):  1993, 1996
Marlboro Cup
Champions (2):  1989, 1989
Runners-up (3):  1987, 1988, 1989
Third place (1):  1990
North American Nations Cup
Runners-up (2):  1949, 1991
Third place (2):  1947, 1990

Fútbol de Primera Player of the Year
List of United States men's international soccer players born outside the United States
U.S. National Soccer Team Players Association
U.S. Soccer Player of the Year
United States men's national under-17 soccer team
United States men's national under-20 soccer team
United States men's national under-23 soccer team
United States women's national soccer team

Official website 
U.S. Soccer Schedule at USSF
U.S. Soccer Results at USSF
U.S. Matches at FIFA
U.S. National Soccer Team Players Association
U.S. soccer team at Association of Football Statisticians
United States at FootballDatabase.eu
USA Men's National Team: All-time Results, 1885–1989 Archived August 2, 2018, at the Wayback Machine
USA Men's National Team: All-time Results, 1990–present Archived August 11, 2011, at the Wayback Machine
USA Men's National Team: Current Value of Players on Team</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Soccer on Fox Sports</title><description>Fox currently airs soccer matches in the United States. These matches are from the FIFA World Cup, the FIFA Women's World Cup, the UEFA European Championship, the Gold Cup, Copa América, MLS, and Liga MX. Fox formerly aired the UEFA Champions League and UEFA Europa League, the Premier League, the Bundesliga, the Serie A, and the FA Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_Fox_Sports</link></item><item><title>List of United States men's national soccer team head coaches</title><description>The role of the United States men's national soccer team coach was first established in 1916 with the appointment of Thomas Cahill. Thirty-nine men have occupied this position.
The following tables include various statistics for head coaches of the United States men's national soccer team (featuring matches, wins, losses, ties, goals for, goals against, and goal differential along with goals for average and goals-against average) from the team's inception in 1916 through the July 1, 2024, match against Uruguay.
The result percentage is based on the formula used by U.S. Soccer in their U.S. Soccer Media Guide, found on page 78.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team_head_coaches</link></item><item><title>Miles Robinson (soccer)</title><description>Miles Gordon Robinson (born March 14, 1997) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a center-back for Major League Soccer club FC Cincinnati and the United States national team.
Born in Arlington, Massachusetts, Robinson began his career with FC Boston Bolts before playing college soccer with the Syracuse Orange. After two seasons with Syracuse, Robinson was drafted with the second overall pick in the 2017 MLS SuperDraft by expansion club Atlanta United. He initially did not feature for the side, and was loaned out to the Charleston Battery in 2017, followed by reserve affiliate Atlanta United 2 in 2018. From the 2019 season, Robinson began appearing as a regular starter for the club following the arrival of Frank de Boer as head coach.
Robinson made his senior debut for the United States in September 2019. In July 2021, he was selected as part of the 23-man squad for the CONCACAF Gold Cup. In the final against Mexico, Robinson scored the winner in extra-time to give the United States the championship.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miles_Robinson_(soccer)</link></item></channel></rss>