<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Sophia Smith (soccer, born 2000)</title><description>Sophia Olivia Smith (born August 10, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a forward for National Women's Soccer League club Portland Thorns FC and the United States national team. She played college soccer at Stanford University, helping the Cardinal win the national championship in 2019. Smith was the first overall pick in the 2020 NWSL College Draft.
In 2022, Smith was named NWSL Most Valuable Player (MVP) and U.S. Soccer Female Player of the Year. She earned MVP honors at the 2022 NWSL Championship after helping the Thorns win the title. In 2023, she won the NWSL Golden Boot for most goals in the season. In 2024, Smith won a gold medal at the Paris 2024 Olympics with U.S. National Team.
At the international level, Smith won the gold medal with the United States at the 2024 Paris Olympics.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sophia_Smith_(soccer,_born_2000)</link></item><item><title>OneSoccer</title><description>OneSoccer is a Canadian category-B exempt English language television channel and English and French language subscription over-the-top video streaming service. The service broadcasts programming related to soccer including live and pre-taped games, recap shows, and more. It is the main rightsholder of the Canadian Soccer Association, including holding the rights to the Canadian Premier League, Canadian Championship, and national team matches. It is rightsholder for various CONCACAF competitions, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup and CONCACAF Champions Cup. In 2024, ownership of OneSoccer was transferred from Mediapro Canada to Timeless Inc.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OneSoccer</link></item><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>List of United States men's national soccer team head coaches</title><description>The role of the United States men's national soccer team coach was first established in 1916 with the appointment of Thomas Cahill. Thirty-nine men have occupied this position.
The following tables include various statistics for head coaches of the United States men's national soccer team (featuring matches, wins, losses, ties, goals for, goals against, and goal differential along with goals for average and goals-against average) from the team's inception in 1916 through the July 1, 2024, match against Uruguay.
The result percentage is based on the formula used by U.S. Soccer in their U.S. Soccer Media Guide, found on page 78.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team_head_coaches</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>National Women's Soccer League</title><description>The National Women's Soccer League (NWSL) is a professional women's soccer league at the top of the United States league system (alongside the USL Super League). Headquartered in New York City, it is owned by the teams and, until 2020, was under a management contract with the United States Soccer Federation.
The NWSL was established in 2012 as the successor to Women's Professional Soccer (WPS; 2007–2012), which was itself the successor to Women's United Soccer Association (2001–2003). The league began play in 2013 with eight teams, four of which were former members of WPS (Boston Breakers, Chicago Red Stars, Sky Blue FC, and Western New York Flash). As of 2024, there are 14 teams across the United States.
Through the 2023 season, six teams (one now defunct) have been crowned NWSL Champions, awarded to the playoff winner, and five teams (one defunct) have claimed the NWSL Shield, awarded to the team in first place at the end of the regular season. The current (2023) NWSL champions are NJ/NY Gotham FC, and the current shield winners (2023) are San Diego Wave FC.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Women%27s_Soccer_League</link></item><item><title>Association football</title><description>Association football, more commonly known as football or soccer, is a team sport played between two teams of 11 players each, who primarily use their feet to propel a ball around a rectangular field called a pitch. The objective of the game is to score more goals than the opposing team by moving the ball beyond the goal line into a rectangular-framed goal defended by the opposing team. Traditionally, the game has been played over two 45-minute halves, for a total match time of 90 minutes. With an estimated 250 million players active in over 200 countries and territories, it is the world's most popular sport.
The game of association football is played in accordance with the Laws of the Game, a set of rules that has been in effect since 1863 and maintained by the IFAB since 1886. The game is played with a football that is 68–70 cm (27–28 in) in circumference. The two teams compete to score goals by getting the ball into the other team's goal (between the posts, under the bar, and fully across the goal line). When the ball is in play, the players mainly use their feet, but may also use any other part of their body, such as their head, chest and thighs, except for their hands or arms, to control, strike, or pass the ball. Only the goalkeepers may use their hands and arms, and only then within the penalty area. The team that has scored more goals at the end of the game is the winner. There are situations where a goal can be disallowed, such as an offside call or a foul in the build-up to the goal. Depending on the format of the competition, an equal number of goals scored may result in a draw being declared, or the game goes into extra time or a penalty shoot-out.
Internationally, association football is governed by FIFA. Under FIFA, there are six continental confederations: AFC, CAF, CONCACAF, CONMEBOL, OFC, and UEFA. Of these confederations, CONMEBOL is the oldest one, being founded in 1916. National associations (e.g. The FA or JFA) are responsible for managing the game in their own countries both professionally and at an amateur level, and coordinating competitions in accordance with the Laws of the Game. The most senior and prestigious international competitions are the FIFA World Cup and the FIFA Women's World Cup. The men's World Cup is the most-viewed sporting event in the world, surpassing the Olympic Games. The two most prestigious competitions in European club football are the UEFA Champions League and the UEFA Women's Champions League, which attract an extensive television audience throughout the world. Since 2009, the final of the men's tournament has been the most-watched annual sporting event in the world.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Association_football</link></item></channel></rss>