<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Congressional Soccer Match</title><description>The Congressional Soccer Match (CSM) is an annual event held in Washington, D.C., that features Members of Congress, Hill staffers, corporations, and community members to participate in a soccer tournament.
The event has historically consisted of an Embassy Tournament, the Congressional Soccer Match, and a Congressional Staff vs. Lobbyist Match.[1]
In 2025, the format was updated to feature two 20-minute 7v7 matches decided by aggregate score for both the Congressional Soccer Match and the Congressional Staff vs. Lobbyist Match. New additions to the festivities included a skills challenge involving participants from the Embassy community, local youth, and congressional staffers.
The event is hosted by the United States Soccer Foundation. As one of the Foundation’s annual charity events, all proceeds from the event support the Foundation’s life-changing programs that help children in underserved communities embrace active and healthy lifestyles while nurturing their personal growth through trained coach-mentors.
As of 2025, the defending champions are the Democrats.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Congressional_Soccer_Match</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>The Soccer Tournament 2024</title><description>The Soccer Tournament 2024, also referred to as TST 2024, was the second annual edition of The Soccer Tournament. The tournament was held from 5–10 June 2024 in Cary, North Carolina. There were two tournaments, one each for men and women, with both having a $1 million prize for the winners.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Soccer_Tournament_2024</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT), officially recognized as USA by FIFA, represents the United States in men's international soccer. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA since 1914 and was a founding member of CONCACAF since 1961. It was also affiliated with NAFC, which was a predecessor confederation of CONCACAF and the former governing soccer body in North America from 1946 to 1961.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarter-finals at the 2002 World Cup.
The United States are the second most successful national team in its confederation, winning 10 CONCACAF continental titles (7 CONCACAF Gold Cup titles and 3 CONCACAF Nations League titles). The United States finished fourth place in two Copa América editions (1995 and 2016).
Globally, the United States finished runners-up in the 2009 FIFA Confederations Cup, beating top-ranked and European champions Spain in the semi-final and defeated by Brazil in the final.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>List of United States men's national soccer team head coaches</title><description>The role of the United States men's national soccer team coach was first established in 1916 with the appointment of Thomas Cahill. Forty-one men have occupied this position.
The following tables include various statistics for head coaches of the United States men's national soccer team (featuring matches, wins, losses, ties, goals for, goals against, and goal differential along with goals for average and goals-against average) from the team's inception in 1916 through the October 12, 2024, match against Panama.
The result percentage is based on the formula used by U.S. Soccer in their U.S. Soccer Media Guide, found on page 78.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team_head_coaches</link></item><item><title>Quinn Sullivan (soccer)</title><description>Quinn Krippendorff Sullivan (born March 27, 2004) is an American professional soccer player who plays as an attacking midfielder or winger for Major League Soccer club Philadelphia Union and the United States national team.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quinn_Sullivan_(soccer)</link></item></channel></rss>