<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>2025 ACC women's soccer tournament</title><description>The 2025 Atlantic Coast Conference women's soccer tournament was the post season women's soccer tournament for the Atlantic Coast Conference, held from November 2 through November 9, 2025. The five-match tournament took place at campus sites for the quarterfinals and First Horizon Stadium in Cary, North Carolina for the semifinals and final. The higher seed hosted the campus site matches. The six-team single-elimination tournament consisted of three rounds based on seeding from regular season conference play. The Florida State Seminoles were the five-time defending champions. The Seminoles were unable to defend their title, as they lost in a penalty shoot-out in the First Round. The final was contested by the first seed Stanford and second seed Notre Dame, who were also the first and second ranked teams in the United Soccer Coaches Poll at the time of the match. The teams played to a 2–2 draw, and Stanford prevailed 5–4 in the ensuing penalty shoot-out. This was Stanford's first ACC tournament title, after they joined the conference last year. It was also the first title for head coach Paul Ratcliffe. As tournament champions, Stanford earned the ACC's automatic berth into the 2025 NCAA Division I women's soccer tournament.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_ACC_women%27s_soccer_tournament</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>2025 Big 12 Conference women's soccer tournament</title><description>The 2025 Big 12 Conference women's soccer tournament will be the postseason women's soccer tournament for the Big 12 Conference held from November 3 to November 8, 2025.  The conference announced the 7-match tournament would be held at Garvey-Rosenthal Soccer Stadium in Fort Worth, Texas with the Championship game at Betty Lou Mays Soccer Field in Waco, Texas.
The 8-team single-elimination tournament will consist of all eight teams playing in a bracket style tournament.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_Big_12_Conference_women%27s_soccer_tournament</link></item><item><title>Patrick Agyemang (soccer, born 2000)</title><description>Patrick K. Agyemang  (, AW-jee-mawn, born November 7, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a forward for EFL Championship club Derby County and the United States national team.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patrick_Agyemang_(soccer,_born_2000)</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT), officially recognized as USA by FIFA, represents the United States in men's international soccer. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA since 1914 and was a founding member of CONCACAF since 1961. It was also affiliated with NAFC, which was a predecessor confederation of CONCACAF and the former governing soccer body in North America from 1946 to 1961.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarter-finals at the 2002 World Cup. The U.S. will host 2026 alongside Mexico and Canada.
The United States are the second most successful national team in its confederation, winning 10 CONCACAF continental titles (seven CONCACAF Gold Cups and three CONCACAF Nations League titles). The United States finished fourth place in two Copa América editions (1995 and 2016). Globally, the United States finished runners-up in the 2009 FIFA Confederations Cup, beating top-ranked European champions Spain in the semi-final and losing to Brazil in the final.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>2024 Atlantic 10 men's soccer tournament</title><description>The Atlantic 10 Conference men's soccer tournament is the conference championship tournament in men's soccer for the Atlantic 10 Conference (A-10). The tournament has been held every year since 1987. It is a single-elimination tournament, and seeding is based on regular season records. The winner, declared conference champion, receives the conference's automatic bid to the NCAA men's soccer tournament.
Rhode Island is the most winning team of the tournament, with 8 conference titles.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atlantic_10_men%27s_soccer_tournament</link></item></channel></rss>