<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>List of United States men's national soccer team head coaches</title><description>The role of the United States men's national soccer team coach was first established in 1916 with the appointment of Thomas Cahill. Thirty-nine men have occupied this position.
The following tables include various statistics for head coaches of the United States men's national soccer team (featuring matches, wins, losses, ties, goals for, goals against, and goal differential along with goals for average and goals-against average) from the team's inception in 1916 through the July 1, 2024 match against  Uruguay.
The result percentage is based on the formula used by U.S. Soccer in their U.S. Soccer Media Guide, found on page 78.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team_head_coaches</link></item><item><title>Canada men's national soccer team</title><description>The Canada men's national soccer team (French: Équipe du Canada de soccer masculin) represents Canada in international soccer competitions since 1924. They are overseen by the Canadian Soccer Association, the governing body for soccer in Canada. They have been a member of FIFA since 1948 and of CONCACAF since 1961.
Canada participated in its second World Cup in 2022 after finishing first in CONCACAF qualifying. Canada is competing in its first Copa América in 2024, reaching the Semi-Finals.
Previously, their top achievements were to win the 1985 CONCACAF Championship to qualify for the 1986 FIFA World Cup and winning the 2000 CONCACAF Gold Cup to qualify for the 2001 FIFA Confederations Cup. Canada is the only national team aside from regional powerhouses Mexico and the United States to win a Gold Cup. Canada also won a gold medal in the 1904 Summer Olympics.
Canada will co-host, along with the United States and Mexico, the 2026 World Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. FC Cincinnati are the reigning Supporters' Shield holders; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and is scheduled to end on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprises all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup Playoffs are scheduled to begin in October and conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS will only send 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allows most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS will be part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result ever by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups (seven consecutive appearances between 1990 and 2014), a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>Miles Robinson (soccer)</title><description>Miles Gordon Robinson (born March 14, 1997) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a center-back for Major League Soccer club FC Cincinnati and the United States national team.
Born in Arlington, Massachusetts, Robinson began his career with FC Boston Bolts before playing college soccer with the Syracuse Orange. After two seasons with Syracuse, Robinson was drafted with the second overall pick in the 2017 MLS SuperDraft by expansion club Atlanta United. He initially did not feature for the side, and was loaned out to the Charleston Battery in 2017, followed by reserve affiliate Atlanta United 2 in 2018. From the 2019 season, Robinson began appearing as a regular starter for the club following the arrival of Frank de Boer as head coach.
Robinson made his senior debut for the United States in September 2019. In July 2021, he was selected as part of the 23-man squad for the CONCACAF Gold Cup. In the final against Mexico, Robinson scored the winner in extra-time to give the United States the championship.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miles_Robinson_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>Matt Turner (soccer)</title><description>Matthew Charles Turner (born June 24, 1994) is an American professional soccer  player who plays as a goalkeeper for Premier League club Nottingham Forest and the United States national team.
Not playing soccer until 14 years old, Turner played for Fairfield University and went undrafted in the 2016 MLS SuperDraft, though signed with Major League Soccer club New England Revolution after a successful preseason trial. After 2 seasons he became the club's primary goalkeeper, later winning the MLS Goalkeeper of the Year award in 2021. In 2022 he joined Premier League club Arsenal, where he won the FA Community Shield in 2023. In the following 2023-24 season he signed for Nottingham Forest for £10 million ($12.75m).
Turner made his debut for the United States in January 2021 at age 27, quickly becoming the team's starting goalkeeper. With the U.S., he won the 2021 CONCACAF Gold Cup and 2023 CONCACAF Nations League, winning the best goalkeeper award for both competitions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matt_Turner_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>List of men's footballers with 1,000 or more official appearances</title><description>In association football, at least 48 players have played at least 1,000 official matches at all age levels. Regarding youth football, only matches with national teams are counted, as such data for club levels cannot be found for the majority of the players. Regarding B teams and reserve teams, appearances for such teams are only included if made in the primary football pyramid and not in reserve divisions. War-time results are also excluded if they were later regarded as unofficial by the relevant Football Association(s); if they were included, Billy Meredith would be the first ever player to have played in 1,000 official matches and Stanley Matthews would also make the list.
English goalkeeper Peter Shilton holds the record for the most appearances, making over 1,400 appearances between the 1960s and 1990s, including a national record of 125 appearances for England, and in 1996 became the first footballer to make 1,000 league appearances. In March 2022, Robert Carmona from Uruguay was recognized as the oldest active footballer by Guinness World Records and was reported as having played around 2,200 official matches, a total that would place him at the top of the list by far; however, due to a lack of details about the distribution of these matches per year and team, or even which teams he played for, he cannot currently be added to the list.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_men%27s_footballers_with_1,000_or_more_official_appearances</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result ever by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups (seven consecutive appearances between 1990 and 2014), a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item></channel></rss>