<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. Inter Miami CF won the 2024 Supporters' Shield; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and are scheduled to conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS are part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.
The United States will be the host country for the 2025 FIFA Club World Cup. MLS clubs could qualify as a host nation club, with Inter Miami CF qualifying as the 2024 MLS Supporters' Shield champions. MLS clubs were also able to qualify through the 2021–2024 editions of the CONCACAF Champions Cup/CONCACAF Champions League. Seattle Sounders FC have qualified as the 2022 CONCACAF Champions League winners.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team results</title><description>The United States women's national soccer team was founded in 1985.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_women%27s_national_soccer_team_results</link></item><item><title>National Women's Soccer League</title><description>The National Women's Soccer League (NWSL) is a professional women's soccer league at the top of the United States league system (alongside the USL Super League). Headquartered in New York City, it is owned by the teams and, until 2020, was under a management contract with the United States Soccer Federation.
The NWSL was established in 2012 as the successor to Women's Professional Soccer (WPS; 2007–2012), which was itself the successor to Women's United Soccer Association (2001–2003). The league began play in 2013 with eight teams, four of which were former members of WPS (Boston Breakers, Chicago Red Stars, Sky Blue FC, and Western New York Flash). As of 2024, there are 14 teams across the United States.
Through the 2024 season, seven teams (one now defunct) have been crowned NWSL Champions, awarded to the playoff winner, and six teams (one defunct) have claimed the NWSL Shield, awarded to the team in first place at the end of the regular season. The current (2024) NWSL champions and shield winners are the Orlando Pride.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Women%27s_Soccer_League</link></item><item><title>Soccer on Fox Sports</title><description>Fox currently airs soccer matches in the United States. These matches are from the FIFA World Cup, the FIFA Women's World Cup, the UEFA European Championship, the Gold Cup,  and Copa América. With the network currently also airing select MLS, and Liga MX matches. Fox formerly aired the UEFA Champions League and UEFA Europa League, the Premier League, the Bundesliga, the Serie A, and the FA Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_Fox_Sports</link></item></channel></rss>