<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>2026 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2026 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 31st season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada. It is also the 48th overall season of a national first-division men's soccer league in the United States overseen by the United States Soccer Federation. The league has 30 clubs that are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences, each with 15 teams.
The regular season is scheduled to run from February 21 to November 7, with 34 matches for each team, primarily against opponents in the same conference. A six-week break from May 25 to July 16 is planned for the 2026 FIFA World Cup, which is being hosted in the United States, Canada, and Mexico. The playoffs are scheduled to be played during an uninterrupted period in November and December that culminates in MLS Cup 2026, the league's postseason championship, on December 18. The 2026 season is the final full season played under the spring–autumn format, as MLS plans to transition to a summer–spring format beginning with the 2027–28 season. A shortened season with 14 matches is scheduled to be played in early 2027.
All MLS matches during the regular season and playoffs are planned to be broadcast on Apple TV, an online streaming service operated by Apple Inc. It replaces MLS Season Pass, which was a standalone streaming service by Apple, used from 2023 to 2025.
Inter Miami CF enters the season as reigning MLS Cup champions, while the Philadelphia Union enter as holders of the Supporters' Shield.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2026_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Sidemen Charity Match</title><description>The Sidemen Charity Match is a recurring charity football match organised by British YouTube group the Sidemen. Founded in 2016, the event features two teams of influencers contesting a friendly match whilst raising money for various British charities.
The event has been held on six occasions since 2016: one at St Mary's Stadium, three at the Valley, one at London Stadium, and one at Wembley Stadium. All matches have been livestreamed via YouTube, promoting various charitable causes. In each edition, the seven members of the Sidemen—KSI, W2S, Miniminter, Zerkaa, Vikkstar123, TBJZL and Behzinga—and various affiliated YouTubers compete as Sidemen Football Club, whilst various other influencers compete as the YouTube Allstars. A seventh match between the two teams will be held on 18 April 2026, returning to Wembley, with some of the Sidemen playing on the Allstars for the first time.
The fourth charity match, held in 2022, is recognised by Guinness World Records for the highest live viewership on a YouTube charity sports match, peaking at over 2.5 million viewers. As of 2025, the events have raised over £8.5 million for various British charities.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sidemen_Charity_Match</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning a league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team, simply known as USMNT and officially recognized as USA by FIFA, represents the United States in men's international soccer, which is governed by the United States Soccer Federation founded in 1913. It has been an affiliate member of FIFA since 1914 and a founding affiliate member of CONCACAF since 1961. Regionally, it is an affiliate member of NAFU in the North American Zone. From 1946 to 1961, it was a member of NAFC, the former governing soccer body in North America and a predecessor confederation of CONCACAF, and also a member of PFC, the former unified confederation of the Americas.
The United States has qualified for the FIFA World Cup twelve times, it is one of four CONCACAF teams to have advanced to the knockout stage, finishing in third place in 1930, reaching the quarter-finals in 2002 and also reaching the round of 16 in four editions. Their third place in Uruguay 1930 is the best result by a CONCACAF team in the competition and is the only non-European or South American team to achieve a World Cup podium finish. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. In 2026, the United States will host the World Cup for the second time. It has qualified for the FIFA Confederations Cup four times, finishing as runners-up in 2009, defeating top ranked European champions Spain 2–0 in the semifinal and losing to Brazil in the final, and also finishing in third place twice.
The United States has participated twenty times in CONCACAF's premier continental competition, it is the second most successful team in its confederation, winning 10 CONCACAF continental titles (seven CONCACAF Gold Cup titles and three CONCACAF Nations League titles). It has participated five times in the Copa América, finishing fourth place twice (1995 and 2016).
Regionally, the team finished as runners-up in the NAFC Championship in 1949, and also finished as runners-up in the North American Nations Cup as hosts in 1991.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Sunday Night Soccer</title><description>Sunday Night Soccer is a primetime Major League Soccer (MLS) broadcast series that debuted during the 2025 MLS season. Airing exclusively on Sunday evenings on Apple TV+, it features marquee matchups between top MLS clubs, aiming to enhance the league's visibility and provide fans with high-quality soccer entertainment. The series is accompanied by dedicated studio programming, including pre-game shows MLS Countdown and MLS La Previa, and post-game analysis shows MLS Wrap Up and MLS El Resumen.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sunday_Night_Soccer</link></item><item><title>2023 COSAFA Beach Soccer Championship</title><description>The 2023 COSAFA Beach Soccer Championship was the fourth edition of the annual tournament organized by COSAFA. The tournament was held in Durban, South Africa.
Senegal are defending champions. Morocco beat Mozambique 4-3 via penalties in the final after the final match ended in a 4-4 draw.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2023_COSAFA_Beach_Soccer_Championship</link></item></channel></rss>