<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>2021 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup</title><description>The 2021 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup was the 11th edition of the FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup. Overall, this was the 21st edition of a world cup in beach soccer since the establishment of the Beach Soccer World Championships which ran from 1995 to 2004 but was not governed by FIFA. This was the sixth tournament to take place biennially; the World Cup took place annually until 2009. The tournament took place in Moscow, capital of Russia, between 19 and 29 August 2021.
The tournament was first intimated in November 2017 at the FIFA Beach Soccer Workshop when it was announced that the World Cup would continue to be held every two years between 2018 and 2024. The bidding process was opened by FIFA in May 2019 and concluded with the selection of Russia as the hosts in October 2019.
Portugal were the defending champions, but they were eliminated in the group stage. They became the first time defending champions in the tournament's history to be eliminated in the group stage.
The hosts Russia, played as the RFU, won their third World Cup, beating Japan in the final.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2021_FIFA_Beach_Soccer_World_Cup</link></item><item><title>Soccer on NBC Sports</title><description>Soccer on NBC Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on NBC and NBCSN. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions. On August 10, 2011, NBC Sports announced a new three-year broadcasting contract with Major League Soccer to produce games for the 2012 season on NBC and the NBC Sports Network. This included the broadcast of two regular season games, two playoff games, and two national team matches on NBC and 38 regular season games, three playoff games, and two national team matches on NBC Sports Network. On October 28, 2012, NBC Sports also announced a three-year, $250 million deal to televise Premier League soccer in English (primarily on NBCSN) and Spanish (on Telemundo and mun2) beginning with the 2013–14 season, replacing ESPN and Fox Soccer as the league's U.S. broadcasters.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_NBC_Sports</link></item><item><title>List of FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup finals</title><description>The 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup is the ongoing 13th edition of the FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup, the premier international beach soccer championship contested by men's national teams of the member associations of FIFA. Overall, this is the 23rd edition of a world cup in beach soccer since the establishment of the Beach Soccer World Championships which ran from 1995 to 2004 but was not governed by FIFA; the World Cup took place annually until 2009 when it then became a biennial event.
It is currently taking place in Victoria, capital of Seychelles, on Mahé island, between 1 and 11 May 2025. This is the first time that Seychelles hosts a FIFA tournament, and the first Beach Soccer World Cup to be played in Africa.
Brazil are the defending champions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_FIFA_Beach_Soccer_World_Cup</link></item><item><title>Sidemen Charity Match</title><description>The Sidemen Charity Match is a recurring charity football match organised by British YouTube group the Sidemen. Founded in 2016, the event features two teams of influencers contesting a friendly match whilst raising money for various British charities.
The event has been held on six occasions since 2016: one at St Mary's Stadium, three at the Valley, one at London Stadium, and one at Wembley Stadium. All matches have been livestreamed via YouTube, promoting various charitable causes. In each edition, the seven members of the Sidemen—KSI, W2S, Miniminter, Zerkaa, Vikkstar123, TBJZL and Behzinga—and various affiliated YouTubers compete as Sidemen Football Club, whilst various other influencers compete as the YouTube Allstars.
The fourth charity match, held in 2022, is recognised by Guinness World Records for the highest live viewership on a YouTube charity sports match, peaking at over 2.5 million viewers. As of 2025, the events have raised over £8.5 million for various British charities.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sidemen_Charity_Match</link></item></channel></rss>