<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. Inter Miami CF won the 2024 Supporters' Shield; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and is scheduled to end on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs are scheduled to begin in October and conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS are part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.
The United States will be the host country for the 2025 FIFA Club World Cup. MLS clubs can qualify as a host nation club; however, the criteria for selection has not been announced. MLS clubs have also been able to qualify through the 2021–2024 editions of the CONCACAF Champions Cup/CONCACAF Champions League. Seattle Sounders FC have qualified as the 2022 CONCACAF Champions League winners.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>2024 Beach Soccer Africa Cup of Nations</title><description>The 2024 Africa Beach Soccer Cup of Nations is the 6th edition of the Africa Beach Soccer Cup of Nations (BSAFCON), the premier beach soccer championship in Africa contested by men's national teams who are members of the Confederation of African Football (CAF). The championship was originally organised by Beach Soccer Worldwide (BSWW) under the title of FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup CAF qualifier (also informally known as the CAF Beach Soccer Championship). In 2015, CAF became its organisers and began using the BSAFCON title to which the competition was officially renamed the next year. Therefore, this will be the 12th edition of the event overall.
The tournament will take place in Hurghada, Egypt staging all matches between 19 and 26 October 2024. The tournament also acted as the qualification route for African teams to the 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup in Seychelles; with the winners and runners-up qualifying joining automatically qualified host Seychelles.
Senegal are the defending champions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Beach_Soccer_Africa_Cup_of_Nations</link></item><item><title>2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup qualification (UEFA)</title><description>The 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup qualifiers for UEFA is a beach soccer tournament contested by European men's national teams who are members of UEFA that determines the four nations from Europe that qualify to the 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup in Seychelles.
The event, organised by Beach Soccer Worldwide (BSWW), takes place in Cádiz, Spain from 4–13 October 2024.
The tournament is a multi-stage competition, consisting of a first group stage, single knockout round, second group stage, and placement matches.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_FIFA_Beach_Soccer_World_Cup_qualification_(UEFA)</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>Association football</title><description>Association football, more commonly known as football or soccer, is a team sport played between two teams of 11 players each, who primarily use their feet to propel a ball around a rectangular field called a pitch. The objective of the game is to score more goals than the opposing team by moving the ball beyond the goal line into a rectangular-framed goal defended by the opposing team. Traditionally, the game has been played over two 45-minute halves, for a total match time of 90 minutes. With an estimated 250 million players active in over 200 countries and territories, it is the world's most popular sport.
The game of association football is played in accordance with the Laws of the Game, a set of rules that has been in effect since 1863 and maintained by the IFAB since 1886. The game is played with a football that is 68–70 cm (27–28 in) in circumference. The two teams compete to score goals by getting the ball into the other team's goal (between the posts, under the bar, and fully across the goal line). When the ball is in play, the players mainly use their feet, but may also use any other part of their body, such as their head, chest and thighs, except for their hands or arms, to control, strike, or pass the ball. Only the goalkeepers may use their hands and arms, and only then within the penalty area. The team that has scored more goals at the end of the game is the winner. There are situations where a goal can be disallowed, such as an offside call or a foul in the build-up to the goal. Depending on the format of the competition, an equal number of goals scored may result in a draw being declared, or the game goes into extra time or a penalty shoot-out.
Internationally, association football is governed by FIFA. Under FIFA, there are six continental confederations: AFC, CAF, CONCACAF, CONMEBOL, OFC, and UEFA. Of these confederations, CONMEBOL is the oldest one, being founded in 1916. National associations (e.g. The FA or JFA) are responsible for managing the game in their own countries both professionally and at an amateur level, and coordinating competitions in accordance with the Laws of the Game. The most senior and prestigious international competitions are the FIFA World Cup and the FIFA Women's World Cup. The men's World Cup is the most-viewed sporting event in the world, surpassing the Olympic Games. The two most prestigious competitions in European club football are the UEFA Champions League and the UEFA Women's Champions League, which attract an extensive television audience throughout the world. Since 2009, the final of the men's tournament has been the most-watched annual sporting event in the world.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Association_football</link></item><item><title>Canada men's national soccer team</title><description>The Canada men's national soccer team (French: Équipe du Canada de soccer masculin) represents Canada in international soccer competitions since 1924. They are overseen by the Canadian Soccer Association, the governing body for soccer in Canada. They have been a member of FIFA since 1948 and of CONCACAF since 1961.
Canada participated in its second World Cup in 2022 after finishing first in CONCACAF qualifying. Canada competed in its first Copa América in 2024, finishing fourth.
Previously, their top achievements were to win the 1985 CONCACAF Championship to qualify for the 1986 FIFA World Cup and winning the 2000 CONCACAF Gold Cup to qualify for the 2001 FIFA Confederations Cup. Canada is the only national team aside from regional powerhouses Mexico and the United States to win a Gold Cup. Canada also won a gold medal in the 1904 Summer Olympics.
Canada will co-host, along with the United States and Mexico, the 2026 World Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item></channel></rss>