<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>Congressional Soccer Match</title><description>The Congressional Soccer Match (CSM) is an annual event held in Washington, D.C., that features Members of Congress, Hill staffers, corporations, and community members to participate in a soccer tournament.
The event has historically consisted of an Embassy Tournament, the Congressional Soccer Match, and a Congressional Staff vs. Lobbyist Match.
In 2025, the format was updated to feature two 20-minute 7v7 matches decided by aggregate score for both the Congressional Soccer Match and the Congressional Staff vs. Lobbyist Match. New additions to the festivities included a skills challenge involving participants from the Embassy community, local youth, and congressional staffers.
The event is hosted by the United States Soccer Foundation. As one of the Foundation’s annual charity events, all proceeds from the event support the Foundation’s life-changing programs that help children in underserved communities embrace active and healthy lifestyles while nurturing their personal growth through trained coach-mentors.
As of 2025, the defending champions are the Democrats.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Congressional_Soccer_Match</link></item><item><title>Brian White (soccer)</title><description>Brian Michael White (born February 3, 1996) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a striker for Major League Soccer club Vancouver Whitecaps FC and the United States national team.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_White_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>National Women's Soccer League attendance</title><description>The National Women's Soccer League (NWSL) is the top-tier professional women's soccer league in the United States. It has the highest average attendance of any professional women's sports league in the United States, surpassing the Women's National Basketball Association and Professional Women's Hockey League. During the 2024 season, the NWSL reached a total attendance of over 2 million spectators for the first time in the league's history. The single-match attendance record of 40,091 spectators was set by the Washington Spirit and Bay FC on August 23, 2025, at Oracle Park in San Francisco.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Women%27s_Soccer_League_attendance</link></item></channel></rss>