<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Soccer on Fox Sports</title><description>Fox currently airs soccer matches in the United States. These matches are from the FIFA World Cup, the FIFA Women's World Cup, the UEFA European Championship, the Gold Cup, Copa América, MLS, and Liga MX. Fox formerly aired the UEFA Champions League and UEFA Europa League, the Premier League, the Bundesliga, the Serie A, and the FA Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_Fox_Sports</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. FC Cincinnati are the reigning Supporters' Shield holders; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and is scheduled to end on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprises all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup Playoffs are scheduled to begin in October and conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS will only send 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allows most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS will be part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.

Note: All teams use Adidas as universal kit manufacturer. As part of Apple's broadcast contract, all MLS kits will include Apple TV+ as a sleeve sponsor.

The regular season consists of 34 matches for each team, split evenly between home and away games. The opening match was played on February 21, the earliest in league history; the regular season will end with Decision Day on October 19, which will comprise simultaneous intra-conference matches. Matches will be paused from July 25 to August 23 for the 2024 Leagues Cup, a knockout tournament that includes teams from MLS and Liga MX. The league did not pause matches for the 2024 Copa América, which was played in the United States from June to July. Most regular season matches will be played on Saturdays and Wednesdays at 7:30 p.m. local time.
The 29 teams are divided into two conferences: the Eastern and Western. The 15 teams in the East will play a round-robin format with intra-conference teams and six matches against six opponents from the West. The 14 teams in the West will play a round-robin with intra-conference teams, an additional one or two intra-conference matches, and six to seven matches against opponents from the East. The top nine teams in each conference will advance to the 2024 MLS Cup Playoffs, which begin with a wild card round for the eighth and ninth placed teams and is followed by a best-of-three series that was introduced in 2023. The remaining matches are single-elimination and culminate with the MLS Cup final on December 7.
Several new rules were scheduled to be introduced for the 2024 season following trials in MLS Next Pro, including in-stadium announcements of video assistant referee decisions, a time limit for substitutions, and mandatory off-field checks for injured players. These initiatives were postponed by MLS due to an ongoing labor dispute with the Professional Soccer Referees Association, who organized a lockout of their referees. Replacement referees from outside the union, including former officials and those from lower level leagues other than USL, were called in to officiate MLS matches. The referees' union and MLS reached an agreement in time for the regular referees to return to the field for Matchday 7, on March 30.
The 2024 MLS All-Star Game will be played between the MLS All-Stars and the Liga MX All-Stars on July 24.

The leading team in this table will win the Supporters' Shield.

The United States will be the host country for the 2025 FIFA Club World Cup. MLS clubs can qualify as a host nation club; however, the criteria for selection has not been announced. MLS clubs have also been able to qualify through the 2021–2024 editions of the CONCACAF Champions Cup/CONCACAF Champions League.
Seattle Sounders FC have qualified as the 2022 CONCACAF Champions League winners.

As of May 15, 2024

Regular season

As of July 20, 2024
Source:

Notes
(H) – Home team(A) – Away team

Bold denotes the Player of the Matchday.

2024 MLS referee lockout

Official website</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>List of United States men's national soccer team head coaches</title><description>The role of the United States men's national soccer team coach was first established in 1916 with the appointment of Thomas Cahill. Thirty-nine men have occupied this position.
The following tables include various statistics for head coaches of the United States men's national soccer team (featuring matches, wins, losses, ties, goals for, goals against, and goal differential along with goals for average and goals-against average) from the team's inception in 1916 through the July 1, 2024, match against Uruguay.
The result percentage is based on the formula used by U.S. Soccer in their U.S. Soccer Media Guide, found on page 78.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team_head_coaches</link></item><item><title>Soccer-specific stadium</title><description>Soccer-specific stadium is a term used mainly in the United States and Canada to refer to a sports stadium either purpose-built or fundamentally redesigned for soccer and whose primary function is to host soccer matches, as opposed to a multi-purpose stadium which is for a variety of sports. A soccer-specific stadium may host other sporting events (such as lacrosse, American football and rugby) and concerts, but the design and purpose of a soccer-specific stadium is primarily for soccer. Some facilities (for example SeatGeek Stadium, Toyota Stadium and Historic Crew Stadium) have a permanent stage at one end of the stadium used for staging concerts.
A soccer-specific stadium typically has amenities, dimensions and scale suitable for soccer in North America, including a scoreboard, video screen, luxury suites and possibly a roof. The field dimensions are within the range found optimal by FIFA: 110–120 yards (100–110 m) long by 70–80 yards (64–75 m) wide. These soccer field dimensions are wider than the regulation American football field width of 53+1⁄3 yards (48.8 m), or the 65-yard (59 m) width of a Canadian football field. The playing surface typically consists of grass as opposed to artificial turf, as the latter is generally disfavored for soccer matches since players are more susceptible to injuries. However, some soccer specific stadiums, such as Portland's Providence Park and Creighton University's Morrison Stadium, do have artificial turf.
The seating capacity is generally between 18,000 and 30,000 for a Major League Soccer franchise, or smaller for college or minor league soccer teams. This is in comparison to the much larger American football stadiums that mostly range between 60,000 and 80,000 in which the original North American Soccer League teams played and most MLS teams occupied during the league's inception. As opposed to gridiron-style football stadiums, where the front row of seats is elevated several feet above the field of play to allow spectators to see over the heads of substitute players and coaches on the sidelines, soccer-specific venues typically have the front row closer to the level of the pitch.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer-specific_stadium</link></item><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>Sophia Smith (soccer, born 2000)</title><description>Sophia Olivia Smith (born August 10, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a forward for National Women's Soccer League club Portland Thorns FC and the United States national team. She played college soccer at Stanford University, helping the Cardinal win the national championship in 2019. Smith was the first overall pick in the 2020 NWSL College Draft.
In 2022, Smith was named NWSL Most Valuable Player (MVP) and U.S. Soccer Female Player of the Year. She earned MVP honors at the 2022 NWSL Championship after helping the Thorns win the title. In 2023, she won the NWSL Golden Boot for most goals in the season.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sophia_Smith_(soccer,_born_2000)</link></item><item><title>2024 National Women's Soccer League season</title><description>The 2024 National Women's Soccer League season is the twelfth season of the National Women's Soccer League, the top division of women's soccer in the United States. Including the NWSL's two professional predecessors, Women's Professional Soccer (2009–2011) and the Women's United Soccer Association (2001–2003), it is the 18th overall season of FIFA and USSF-sanctioned top division women's soccer in the United States. The league has 14 teams following the addition of expansion teams Bay FC and Utah Royals—the latter being the revival of a team that had played in the league from 2018 to 2020.
The season began with the 2024 NWSL Challenge Cup, a supercup match between the reigning playoff champion (NJ/NY Gotham FC) and NWSL Shield winner San Diego Wave FC, on March 15, 2024. The regular season began the following day and will run until November 3; it will pause for a month between July 8 and August 18 for the 2024 Summer Olympics. Each team will play 26 matches, an increase of four from the 2023 season. The playoffs will comprise the top eight teams and run from November 9 to November 23. The 2024 season is the first under a new broadcast agreement with CBS Sports, ESPN, Amazon Prime Video and Scripps Sports; a total of 118 matches will be televised or streamed.
In addition to league play, 2024 marks the debut of the NWSL x Liga MX Femenil Summer Cup, an international competition between clubs from the NWSL and Liga MX Femenil of Mexico. It is scheduled to be played from July to October.

Note: All teams use Nike as their kit manufacturer as part of a league-wide sponsorship agreement renewed in November 2021.

The initial determining factor for a team's position in the standings is most points earned, with three points earned for a win, one point for a draw, and zero points for a loss. If two or more teams tie in total points total when determining rank, playoff qualification, and seeding, the NWSL uses the following tiebreaker criteria, going down the list until all teams are ranked.

Greater goal difference across the entire regular season (against all teams, not just tied teams).
Most total wins across the entire regular season (against all teams, not just tied teams).
Most goals scored across the entire regular season (against all teams, not just tied teams).
Head-to-head results (total points) between the tied teams.
Head-to-head most goals scored between the tied teams.
Fewest disciplinary points accumulated across the entire regular season (against all teams, not just tied teams).
Coin flip (if two teams are tied) or drawing of lots (if three or more teams are tied).

Considering each week to end when the NWSL releases their weekly standing tweet 

Legend: Gold = first place; green = playoff position; Red = last place.

Ranked from highest to lowest average attendance.

Updated through July 10

Updated through June 30

As of July 10, 2024.

In a change of format, the Challenge Cup will be played as a one-off super cup, contested by the winners of the previous season's NWSL Championship, NJ/NY Gotham FC, and NWSL Shield, San Diego Wave FC.

It is scheduled to be played from July to October.

As of July 12, 2024

Official website</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_National_Women%27s_Soccer_League_season</link></item><item><title>United States men's national under-23 soccer team</title><description>The United States U-23 men's national soccer team, also known as the United States men's Olympic soccer team, is a youth soccer team operated under the auspices of U.S. Soccer. Its primary role is qualification into and competition at the quadrennial Olympic Football Tournament, the next of which is to be held during the 2024 Summer Olympics in Paris, France. The team's most recent major tournament was the 2020 edition at the Tokyo Olympics, in which the United States team did not qualify. Their most recent qualification was the tournament at the 2008 Summer Olympics, where the team was eliminated in the group stage.
In accordance with FIFA regulations, the roster can be augmented with three "overage" players during Olympic competition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_under-23_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item></channel></rss>