<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>United States men's national under-23 soccer team</title><description>The United States U-23 men's national soccer team, also known as the United States men's Olympic soccer team, is a youth soccer team operated under the auspices of U.S. Soccer. Its primary role is qualification into and competition at the quadrennial Olympic Football Tournament, with the next one to be held during the 2028 Summer Olympics in Los Angeles, which the team has already qualified for as hosts.
Its most recent major tournament was the 2024 edition at the Paris Olympics, in which the team made it to the quarter-finals before being eliminated by Morocco.
In accordance with FIFA regulations, the roster can be augmented with three "overage" players during Olympic competition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_under-23_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>OneSoccer</title><description>OneSoccer is a Canadian category-B exempt English language television channel and English and French language subscription over-the-top video streaming service. The service broadcasts programming related to soccer including live and pre-taped games, recap shows, and more. It is the main rightsholder of the Canadian Soccer Association, including holding the rights to the Canadian Premier League, Canadian Championship, and national team matches. It is rightsholder for various CONCACAF competitions, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup and CONCACAF Champions Cup. In 2024, ownership of OneSoccer was transferred from Mediapro Canada to Timeless Inc.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OneSoccer</link></item><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>Sophia Smith (soccer, born 2000)</title><description>Sophia Olivia Smith (born August 10, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a forward for National Women's Soccer League club Portland Thorns FC and the United States national team. She played college soccer at Stanford University, helping the Cardinal win the national championship in 2019. Smith was the first overall pick in the 2020 NWSL College Draft.
In 2022, Smith was named NWSL Most Valuable Player (MVP) and U.S. Soccer Female Player of the Year. She earned MVP honors at the 2022 NWSL Championship after helping the Thorns win the title. In 2023, she won the NWSL Golden Boot for most goals in the season. In 2024, Smith won a gold medal at the Paris 2024 Olympics with U.S. National Team.
At the international level, Smith won the gold medal with the United States at the 2024 Paris Olympics.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sophia_Smith_(soccer,_born_2000)</link></item><item><title>Quinn (soccer)</title><description>Quinn (formerly Rebecca Quinn; born 11 August 1995) is a Canadian professional soccer player who plays as a midfielder for National Women's Soccer League club Seattle Reign FC and the Canada national team. Quinn previously played professionally for Paris FC in France's top league Division 1 Féminine (D1F), Vittsjö GIK in the Swedish Damallsvenskan, as well as Washington Spirit in the NWSL. They were the first Canadian to play women's collegiate soccer at Duke University. Quinn previously represented Canada on the under-17, under-20, under-23 national teams.
In 2021, at the 2020 Tokyo Olympics, Quinn became the first out transgender, non-binary athlete to compete at the Olympics, the first to medal, and the first to earn a gold medal. In 2023, Quinn became the first openly transgender and non-binary footballer at the FIFA World Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quinn_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>List of United States men's national soccer team head coaches</title><description>The role of the United States men's national soccer team coach was first established in 1916 with the appointment of Thomas Cahill. Thirty-nine men have occupied this position.
The following tables include various statistics for head coaches of the United States men's national soccer team (featuring matches, wins, losses, ties, goals for, goals against, and goal differential along with goals for average and goals-against average) from the team's inception in 1916 through the July 1, 2024, match against Uruguay.
The result percentage is based on the formula used by U.S. Soccer in their U.S. Soccer Media Guide, found on page 78.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team_head_coaches</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>2024 National Women's Soccer League season</title><description>The 2024 National Women's Soccer League season is the twelfth season of the National Women's Soccer League, the top division of women's soccer in the United States. Including the NWSL's two professional predecessors, Women's Professional Soccer (2009–2011) and the Women's United Soccer Association (2001–2003), it is the 18th overall season of FIFA and USSF-sanctioned top division women's soccer in the United States. The league has 14 teams following the addition of expansion teams Bay FC and Utah Royals—the latter being the revival of a team that had played in the league from 2018 to 2020.
The season began with the 2024 NWSL Challenge Cup, a supercup match between the reigning playoff champion (NJ/NY Gotham FC) and NWSL Shield winner San Diego Wave FC, on March 15, 2024. The regular season began the following day and will run until November 3; it will pause for a month between July 8 and August 18 for the 2024 Summer Olympics. Each team will play 26 matches, an increase of four from the 2023 season. The playoffs will comprise the top eight teams and run from November 9 to November 23. The 2024 season is the first under a new broadcast agreement with CBS Sports, ESPN, Amazon Prime Video and Scripps Sports; a total of 118 matches will be televised or streamed.
In addition to league play, 2024 marks the debut of the NWSL x Liga MX Femenil Summer Cup, an international competition between clubs from the NWSL and Liga MX Femenil of Mexico. It is scheduled to be played from July to October.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_National_Women%27s_Soccer_League_season</link></item></channel></rss>