<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Marshall Islands national soccer team</title><description>The Marshall Islands national soccer team represents the Pacific island nation of the Marshall Islands in senior men's international soccer and is controlled by the Marshall Islands Soccer Federation. It is not a member of FIFA or OFC.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marshall_Islands_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Major League Soccer</title><description>Major League Soccer (MLS) is a professional soccer league in North America and the highest level of the United States soccer league system. It comprises 30 teams, with 27 in the United States and 3 in Canada, and is sanctioned by the United States Soccer Federation. MLS is one of the major professional sports leagues in the United States and Canada. The league is headquartered in Midtown Manhattan.
The predecessor of MLS was the North American Soccer League (NASL), which existed from 1968 until 1984. MLS was founded in 1993 as part of the United States' successful bid to host the 1994 FIFA World Cup. The inaugural season took place in 1996 with ten teams. MLS experienced financial and operational struggles in its first few years, losing millions of dollars and folding two teams in 2002. Since then, developments such as the proliferation of soccer-specific stadiums around the league, the implementation of the Designated Player Rule allowing teams to sign star players such as David Beckham and Lionel Messi, and national TV contracts have made MLS profitable. 
In 2022, with an average attendance of over 21,000 per game, MLS had the fourth-highest average attendance of the major professional sports leagues in the United States and Canada, behind the National Football League (NFL) with over 69,000 fans per game, Major League Baseball (MLB) with over 26,000 fans per game, and the Canadian Football League (CFL) with over 21,700 fans per game. Two years later, MLS was ranked the second most attended soccer league in the world in total attendance, only trailing the Premier League.
The MLS regular season typically starts in late February or early March and runs through mid-October, with each team playing 34 games; the team with the best record is awarded the Supporters' Shield. Eighteen teams compete in the postseason MLS Cup playoffs in late October and November, culminating in the league's championship game, MLS Cup. Instead of operating as an association of independently owned clubs, MLS is a single entity in which each team is owned by the league and individually operated by the league's investors. The league has a fixed membership like most sports leagues in the United States and Canada and Mexico's Liga MX which makes it one of the few soccer leagues that does not use a promotion and relegation process. 
The LA Galaxy have the most MLS Cups, with six. They are tied with D.C. United for most Supporters' Shields, with four each.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Major_League_Soccer</link></item><item><title>Record attendances in United States club soccer</title><description>Competitive men's professional soccer has been played in the United States since 1912 and since 2001 for women's.  Numerous leagues have existed over the years with some recognized by the United States Soccer Federation and some not.  The lists below are the single game attendance records for men's outdoor (60,000+), women's outdoor (20,000+), and men's indoor (18,000+) matches in American club soccer.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Record_attendances_in_United_States_club_soccer</link></item><item><title>Matt Turner (soccer)</title><description>Matthew Charles Turner (born June 24, 1994) is an American professional soccer  player who plays as a goalkeeper for Major League Soccer club New England Revolution, on loan from  Ligue 1 club Lyon, and the United States national team.
Not playing soccer until 14 years old, Turner played for Fairfield University and went undrafted in the 2016 MLS SuperDraft, though signed with Major League Soccer club New England Revolution after a successful preseason trial. After 2 seasons he became the club's primary goalkeeper, later winning the MLS Goalkeeper of the Year award in 2021. In 2022, Turner joined Premier League club Arsenal and the following year moved to Nottingham Forest. In his second season, he went on loan with Crystal Palace, where he won the FA Cup in 2025.
Turner made his debut for the United States in January 2021 at age 27, quickly becoming the team's starting goalkeeper. With the U.S., he won the CONCACAF Gold Cup in 2021 and the CONCACAF Nations League in 2023 and 2024, winning the best goalkeeper award for the 2021 and 2023 competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matt_Turner_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>List of men's footballers with 1,000 or more official appearances</title><description>In association football, 52 players have played at least 1,000 official matches at all age levels. Regarding B teams and reserve teams, appearances for such teams are only included if made in the primary football pyramid and not in reserve divisions. Appearances made in youth football are not deemed to be official. War-time results are also excluded if they were later regarded as unofficial by the relevant Football Association(s); if they were included, Billy Meredith would be the first ever player to have played in 1,000 official matches, and Stanley Matthews would also make the list.
English goalkeeper Peter Shilton is generally considered the record holder for the most appearances, making 1,387 appearances between the 1960s and 1990s, including a national record of 125 appearances for England, and in 1996 became the first footballer to make 1,000 league appearances.
Regarding amateur football, in March 2022, Robert Carmona from Uruguay was reported as having played around 2,200 official matches.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_men%27s_footballers_with_1,000_or_more_official_appearances</link></item></channel></rss>