<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>The Soccer Tournament 2024</title><description>The Soccer Tournament 2024, also referred to as TST 2024, was the second annual edition of The Soccer Tournament. The tournament was held from 5–10 June 2024 in Cary, North Carolina. There were two tournaments, one each for men and women, with both having a $1 million prize for the winners.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Soccer_Tournament_2024</link></item><item><title>The Soccer Tournament 2025</title><description>The Soccer Tournament 2025, also referred to as TST 2025, is the third annual edition of The Soccer Tournament. The tournament is occurring from June 4-9 2025 in Cary, North Carolina.  There are two tournaments, one each for men and women, with both having a $1 million prize for the winners.  There are 64 teams over 134 matches for the six days of competition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Soccer_Tournament_2025</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT), officially recognized as USA by FIFA, represents the United States in men's international soccer. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA since 1914 and was a founding member of CONCACAF since 1961. It was also affiliated with NAFC, which was a predecessor confederation of CONCACAF and the governing soccer body in North America from 1946 to 1961.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cup titles, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth place in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Quinn Sullivan (soccer)</title><description>Quinn Krippendorff Sullivan (born March 27, 2004) is an American professional soccer player who plays as an attacking midfielder or winger for Major League Soccer club Philadelphia Union.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quinn_Sullivan_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>Canada men's national under-17 soccer team</title><description>The Canada U-17 men's national soccer team (also known as Canada Under-17s or Canada U-17s) represents Canada in international soccer at this age level. They are overseen by the Canadian Soccer Association, the governing body for soccer in Canada.
Many of Canada's current internationals have played at one or more of these age levels early in their career, often working with the same coaches and teammates throughout their progression into the senior squad. The team has qualified for nine out of nineteen FIFA U-17 World Cups.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_men%27s_national_under-17_soccer_team</link></item></channel></rss>