<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>List of men's footballers with 1,000 or more official appearances</title><description>In association football, 52 players have played at least 1,000 official matches at all age levels. Regarding B teams and reserve teams, appearances for such teams are only included if made in the primary football pyramid and not in reserve divisions. Appearances made in youth football are not deemed to be official. War-time results are also excluded if they were later regarded as unofficial by the relevant Football Association(s); if they were included, Billy Meredith would be the first ever player to have played in 1,000 official matches, and Stanley Matthews would also make the list.
English goalkeeper Peter Shilton is generally considered the record holder for the most appearances, making 1,396 appearances between the 1960s and 1990s, including a national record of 125 appearances for England, and in 1996 became the first footballer to make 1,000 league appearances. However, in March 2022, Robert Carmona from Uruguay was reported as having played around 2,200 official matches.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_men%27s_footballers_with_1,000_or_more_official_appearances</link></item><item><title>2025 Copa América of Beach Soccer</title><description>The 2025 Copa América of Beach Soccer (known natively in Spanish as the Copa América de Futbol Playa) will be the fifth edition of the Copa América of Beach Soccer, the international beach soccer competition organised by CONMEBOL for the men's national teams of South America. It will be held in Chile between 22 February and 2 March 2025.
For the second time, the tournament will act as the South American qualification for the FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup following CONMEBOL's decision to determine its representatives in the World Cup via the Copa America instead of its specific qualifying tournament that ran until 2021. The top three teams will qualify for the 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup held in Seychelles. Brazil are the defending champions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_Copa_Am%C3%A9rica_of_Beach_Soccer</link></item><item><title>List of Intercontinental Cup (football) matches</title><description>The Intercontinental Cup was an association football club competition contested annually from 1960 to 2004 between the winners of the European Cup and the South American Copa Libertadores. The competition was endorsed by both the Union of European Football Associations (UEFA) and the Confederación Sudamericana de Fútbol (CONMEBOL) and, until 1979, it was played over two legs. From 1980, its format was changed to a single match traditionally held in Tokyo, Japan, due to its new sponsorship. The Intercontinental Cup was discontinued in 2004 in favour of the FIFA Club World Cup, which includes the champion clubs from all of the Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) member confederations.
In its first nine editions, the competition's winner was decided on a points system; if necessary, a play-off match would be held to determine the outcome in the event of a draw. In 1968, the system was changed so that aggregate score would dictate the winning club. The away goals rule was applied if the tie was level after both legs.
Nacional and Peñarol (Uruguay), Boca Juniors (Argentina), Real Madrid (Spain), and A.C. Milan (Italy) hold the record for the most victories, each team having won the competition three times; Milan and Independiente (Argentina) have the most runner-up places (four). Overall, 25 different clubs won the competition during its 45 editions. Argentinian clubs won the most cups, with nine trophies among them; Italian clubs won the second most (seven), and Brazilian teams are third with six victories. The most successful confederation is CONMEBOL, teams representing the confederation having won the competition 22 times and been runners-up 21 times. Teams representing the European football confederation UEFA have won the competition 21 times and been runners-up 22 times. The last Intercontinental Cup was won by 2004 European champions Porto of Portugal, who beat Colombian side Once Caldas by 8–7 in a penalty shootout, after the match finished 0–0.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Intercontinental_Cup_(football)_matches</link></item><item><title>Major League Soccer on television</title><description>Major League Soccer has been broadcast live in the United States nationally since the league's inception in 1996 and in Canada since 2007. As of the 2023 season, Apple Inc. is the primary global rights holder and streams every regular season and playoff match on MLS Season Pass – a service in the Apple TV app. Some matches are also broadcast on television via Fox Sports in the United States, and Bell Media (via TSN and RDS) in Canada.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Major_League_Soccer_on_television</link></item></channel></rss>