<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>United States men's national under-23 soccer team</title><description>The United States U-23 men's national soccer team, also known as the United States men's Olympic soccer team, is a youth soccer team operated under the auspices of U.S. Soccer. Its primary role is qualification into and competition at the quadrennial Olympic Football Tournament, the next of which is to be held during the 2024 Summer Olympics in Paris, France. The team's most recent major tournament was the 2020 edition at the Tokyo Olympics, in which the United States team did not qualify. Their most recent qualification was the tournament at the 2008 Summer Olympics, where the team was eliminated in the group stage.
In accordance with FIFA regulations, the roster can be augmented with three "overage" players during Olympic competition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_under-23_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Soccer on Fox Sports</title><description>Fox currently airs soccer matches in the United States. These matches are from the FIFA World Cup, the FIFA Women's World Cup, the UEFA European Championship, the Gold Cup, Copa América, MLS, and Liga MX. Fox formerly aired the UEFA Champions League and UEFA Europa League, the Premier League, the Bundesliga, the Serie A, and the FA Cup.

On October 22, 2011, FIFA awarded English-language rights to its tournaments to Fox from 2015 through 2022, including the 2018 and 2022 FIFA World Cup, and the 2015 (which would mark Fox's first professional FIFA tournament broadcast) and 2019 FIFA Women's World Cup, replacing ESPN and ABC. In February 2015, the contract was extended to 2026, in what was reported to be compensation for the re-scheduling of the 2022 World Cup to late-November/mid-December (which conflicts with the regular seasons of most major U.S. leagues, including the NFL) due to the climate of the host country. Fox's coverage could end after the 2026 FIFA World Cup as ESPN is interested in the 2030 FIFA World Cup

Fox replaces ESPN as the new home of the UEFA national tournaments. This six-year agreement will including the next two editions of European Championship as well as the UEFA Nations League, UEFA qualifying competitions, and all friendly matches controlled by UEFA. FuboTV will stream matches via sublicensing from Fox. At least one match per matchday will air on FOX.

Fox exclusively airing most of CONCACAF Clubs and Nations Championship until 2022-2025, including Gold Cup, Champions League, and both Men's and Women's Olympic Qualifying tournament.

Fox reached a long-term agreement with CONMEBOL for airing their South American men's and women's soccer tournament, highlighted with Copa América and Copa América Femenina also including World Cup and Olympic qualifiers. This six-year agreement will kick-off this June with 2021 Copa América.

In May 2018, Fox Sports acquired the rights to Tijuana, Monterrey, and Santos home matches. These matches started airing across Fox Sports in late July 2018, with the exception of Santos matches which will begin in 2019. In July 2022, their coverage was expanded with addition of Juárez home matches. Matches are broadcast on FS1, FS2, Fox Deportes, and the Bally Sports regional networks in the Western U.S.

Fox aired weekly Major League Soccer (MLS) matches on Sunday afternoons and evenings. Rob Stone hosted in the studio alongside studio analysts Alexi Lalas and Maurice Edu. John Strong and Stuart Holden called the weekly matches from site. (See Major League Soccer on television.) Most of the coverage moved to Apple TV+ after 2022. Fox will still continue to air games as sole linear partner through the 2026 season.

Fox acquired the rights to the Coupe de France in 2023 from beIN Sports.

In August 2020, Fox Sports became the first American broadcast partner of the Canadian Premier League.

Fox aired the Bundesliga since 2015 and aired all 306 league games and relegation playoffs via FS1, FS2, and Fox Soccer Plus. The pre-game and halftime show is hosted by Ian Joy or Kate Abdo, and two pundits (rotation). The lead commentator was Keith Costigan. The 2019–20 season was the networks' last broadcasting the Bundesliga as ESPN picked up the rights.

Fox has aired the German DFL-Supercup since 2015 and only airs select tournament matches.

Fox Soccer aired the English Premier League from 2000 to 2013. In the later years of their coverage, Fox had a studio pregame show first hosted by Christian Miles until 2011, then by Rob Stone. Studio analysts were Warren Barton, Eric Wynalda, and Keith Costigan. Commentary was provided by former corporate sibling Sky Sports.

Fox previously aired the English FA Cup since 2014, until their rights expired in 2018. ESPN has since acquired these rights. FA Cup coverage was hosted by Rob Stone or Kate Abdo alongside a rotation of analysts including Warren Barton, Alexi Lalas, and Mario Melchiot. Lead world feed broadcast team for FA Cup was Martin Tyler and Stewart Robson.

Fox formerly aired the UEFA Champions League and the UEFA Europa League from 2009–18. Rob Stone hosted UEFA Champions League coverage alongside a rotation of analysts including Warren Barton, Brad Friedel, Eric Wynalda, Stuart Holden, and Alexi Lalas. Lead broadcast team for non World-Feed broadcasts of UEFA Champions League from 2013–14 was Gus Johnson and Eric Wynalda, then the World-Feed broadcasts, and finally John Strong and Stuart Holden or Brad Friedel replaced them as lead commentator from 2016–18. Ian Joy or Kate Abdo hosted UEFA Europa League coverage alongside analysts Stuart Holden, Warren Barton, and Mario Melchiot. Lead broadcast team for Europa League coverage was Keith Costigan and Alexi Lalas. For World-Feed broadcasts, Tony Jones and David Pleat call both UEFA Champions League Final and UEFA Europa League Final.

Through their MLS deal, Fox shared the right to USMNT and USWNT matches with ESPN/ABC. John Strong and Stuart Holden were the main USMNT commentators with studio coverage hosted by Rob Stone alongside analysts Alexi Lalas and Maurice Edu. USWNT commentators were JP Dellacamera with analyst Aly Wagner and studio coverage was hosted by Rob Stone, Sara Walsh, or Jenny Taft with analysts Leslie Osborne, Heather O'Reilly, Christie Pearce Rampone, and Alexi Lalas. This coverage has ended after 2022 when these rights moved to Turner Sports.

Presenters

Studio analysts

Play-by-play announcers

Color commentators

Reporters

Official website</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_Fox_Sports</link></item><item><title>List of United States men's national soccer team head coaches</title><description>The role of the United States men's national soccer team coach was first established in 1916 with the appointment of Thomas Cahill. Thirty-nine men have occupied this position.
The following tables include various statistics for head coaches of the United States men's national soccer team (featuring matches, wins, losses, ties, goals for, goals against, and goal differential along with goals for average and goals-against average) from the team's inception in 1916 through the July 1, 2024, match against Uruguay.
The result percentage is based on the formula used by U.S. Soccer in their U.S. Soccer Media Guide, found on page 78.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team_head_coaches</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. FC Cincinnati are the reigning Supporters' Shield holders; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and is scheduled to end on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprises all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup Playoffs are scheduled to begin in October and conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS will only send 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allows most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS will be part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Canada men's national soccer team</title><description>The Canada men's national soccer team (French: Équipe du Canada de soccer masculin) represents Canada in international soccer competitions since 1924. They are overseen by the Canadian Soccer Association, the governing body for soccer in Canada. They have been a member of FIFA since 1948 and of CONCACAF since 1961.
Canada participated in its second World Cup in 2022 after finishing first in CONCACAF qualifying. Canada competed in its first Copa América in 2024, finishing fourth.
Previously, their top achievements were to win the 1985 CONCACAF Championship to qualify for the 1986 FIFA World Cup and winning the 2000 CONCACAF Gold Cup to qualify for the 2001 FIFA Confederations Cup. Canada is the only national team aside from regional powerhouses Mexico and the United States to win a Gold Cup. Canada also won a gold medal in the 1904 Summer Olympics.
Canada will co-host, along with the United States and Mexico, the 2026 World Cup.

Soccer was being played in Canada with the Dominion Football Association (1877) and Western Football Association (1880) acting as precursors to the modern-day Canadian Soccer Association. In 1885, the WFA sent a team to New Jersey to take on a side put forth by the American Football Association, the then-unofficial governing body of the sport in the United States. In an unofficial friendly, Canada defeated the United States 1–0 in East Newark, New Jersey. The American team won 3–2 in a return match one year later. In 1888, a team represented the WFA in a tour of the British Isles, earning a record of nine wins, five draws, and nine losses. The squad comprised 16 Canadian-born players with the only exception being tour organizer David Forsyth, who had immigrated to Canada one year after his birth.

In 1904 Galt F.C. represented the WFA at the Olympic Games in St Louis, Missouri. As just one of three teams competing, Galt defeated two American clubs, Christian Brothers College (7–0) and St. Rose (4–0) to win the tournament. The Toronto Mail and Empire of November 18, 1904, reports that "Immediately after the game, the Galt aggregation, numbering about 50 persons, retired to the office of James W. Sullivan, chief of the Department of Physical Culture, where they received their prize. After a short talk by Mr. James E. Conlon of the Physical Culture Department, Mayor Mundy, of the City of Galt, presented each player on the winning team with a beautiful gold medal." The medals are clearly engraved with the name of the company in St. Louis that made them.
In 1905, a British team of touring amateurs nicknamed the "Pilgrims" toured Canada, with their match against Galt billed as the "championship of the world". The match was played in front of 3500 fans in Galt, now part of Cambridge, Ontario, and ended in a 3–3 draw. Earlier the Pilgrims had been beaten 2–1 by Berlin Rangers, in the city now known as Kitchener.

The Canadian national team toured Australia in 1924, playing a series of "test" friendlies against their hosts, including their first official match, a 3–2 friendly defeat to the Australian national team in Brisbane, Queensland on June 7, 1924. Canada also played Australia at the Jubilee Oval, Adelaide on Saturday July 12, 1924, and defeated them by 4 goals to 1. In 1925, Canada played their old rivals, the United States, in Montreal, winning 1–0 on Ed McLaine's goal. In a return match in November 1925 in Brooklyn, New York, Canada was defeated 1–6. One year later, Canada lost 2–6 to the Americans in the same city before playing four internationals in a 1927 tour of New Zealand.
The New Zealand tour included a total of 22 games, of which Canada won 19 with only 2 defeats. Most of the games were against local combined teams although Canada also played New Zealand in four occasions (scores: 2–2, 2–1, 0–1, 4–1).

Following the lead of British soccer associations, Canada withdrew from FIFA in 1928 over a dispute regarding broken time payments to amateur players. They rejoined the confederation in 1946 and took part in World Cup qualifying in the North American Football Confederation (NAFC) (a precursor to CONCACAF) for the first time in 1957, the first time they had played as a national team in 30 years. Under the guidance of head coach Don Petrie, Canada defeated the United States in Toronto 5–1 in their opening game, but lost two games in Mexico (failing to play a home game due to financial reasons) 0–2 and 0–3 before defeating the U.S. 3–2 in St. Louis. Mexico advanced as group winners, meaning that Canada missed out on the World Cup in 1958 in Sweden.
Canada withdrew from World Cup qualifying for 1962 and did not enter a team for 1966. They did compete in soccer however at the 1967 Pan American Games, their first time to do so in the sixth edition of the games, which they hosted in Winnipeg. Canada finished fourth place, helped somewhat by defending champion Brazil's absence.
A 0–0 draw away to Bermuda meant the Canadians, under coach Peter Dinsdale, could not advance out of the first round of qualifying for the 1970 World Cup. Dinsdale was replaced by Frank Pike. In their second participation in soccer at the Pan Am games, held in Cali, Canada finished second in their opening round group (to hosts Colombia). In the final group round however, they managed only one win (over Colombia) and finished next to last.
Canada again failed at the first hurdle in qualifying for the 1974 World Cup. Under German head coach Eckhard Krautzun, they finished second in a home and away qualifying group for the 1973 CONCACAF Championship (to Mexico). For the 1975 Pan Am Games, Canada, along with most of the larger Pan Am countries, sent their Olympic team, which was amateur (and senior aged), to compete. After narrowly qualifying out of the first round, the Canucks were soundly defeated by Costa Rica, Cuba, and Mexico, conceding a total of 14 goals while scoring none. At the Summer Olympics at home the following year, under head coach Colin Morris, the amateur Canadian side failed to get out of the first round, losing both of their games. This despite the brilliant play of Jimmy Douglas, who scored a goal against a Dynamo Kyiv-dominated Soviet Union side and another goal against North Korea, Canada's only two goals in the tournament.
In their North American qualifying group for the 1977 CONCACAF Championship, with both group winners and runners-up now advancing, Canada, again under head coach Krautzun, qualified as runners-up after defeating the Americans 3–0 in a neutral site one-match play-off, played in Port-au-Prince. In the championship, played in Monterrey and Mexico City, Mexico won all five of their matches with a plus 15 goals difference to win the tournament handily. Canada finished fourth.
Matters were different however at the next CONCACAF championship, in 1981, played in Tegucigalpa. Canada entered the tournament raising eyebrows by winning their qualifying group over Mexico and the United States, even achieving a 1–1 draw against Mexico at the Azteca Stadium with Gerry Gray scoring from a direct free kick in the 88th-minute. In the final round, the Canadians opened strongly with a 1–0 win over El Salvador, with Mike Stojanovic the goal-scorer, and a 1–1 draw with Haiti, with Stojanovic scoring again. They next lost to the hosts Honduras 1–2 and then drew Mexico 1–1 with Ian Bridge scoring the equalizer via a corner kick.  A win in their final game against Cuba would have put them through to Spain, but they were held to a 2–2 draw, allowing El Salvador to qualify as tournament runners-up.
1981 through 1985 saw Canada continue to develop under the guidance of English coach Tony Waiters. After a strong performance at the 1984 Summer Olympics, Waiters would see the Maple Leafs through to their first World Cup finals appearance in 1985. A 1–1 away draw to Guatemala was key in allowing them to eliminate Los Chapines in the first round group. The second round was also closely contested, in part as this Canadian squad was strong defensively but had limited ability to score goals. The Canucks managed to eke out a 1–0 away win over Honduras, thanks to a George Pakos winner, hold Costa Rica scoreless in San José, and then in their final game, one they needed to draw to qualify, beat Los Catrachos a second time, 2–1 in St. John's, Newfoundland, with Pakos and Igor Vrablic the goal scorers. The victory not only secured their first World Cup finals berth, but also the crown of CONCACAF champions for the first time, although Mexico did not compete, having already qualified automatically for the World Cup as hosts.
At the 1986 FIFA World Cup, Canada impressed defensively in their first game against France, only conceding a late Jean-Pierre Papin goal after Papin had missed several earlier chances.
However, Canada could not build on their stubborn performance against France, losing their next two matches to both Hungary and the Soviet Union 0–2, finishing the group in last place with zero points.
Four Canadian players (Chris Chueden, Hector Marinaro, David Norman and Vrablic) were involved in a match fixing betting scandal at the Merlion Cup tournament in Singapore two months after the World Cup. The four players were suspended by the Canadian Soccer Association for "bringing the game into disrepute". Norman was reinstated in 1992 after admitting his involvement in the scandal. Vrablic never played for Canada again.

Qualification for 1990 lasted all of two matches for Canada, a home-and-away series with Guatemala, played in October 1988. The Central Americans won the first game 1–0 in Guatemala City while Canada prevailed in Vancouver 3–2. Tied on goal difference, Los Chapines advanced on away goal rule.
1990 saw Canada take part in the first North American Nations Cup, hosting the three-team tournament. Mexico and Canada sent their full squads, but the United States sent a 'B' team. Canada won the tournament after a 1–0 win over the United States on May 6 and a 2–1 win over Mexico on May 13. All three Canadian goals were scored by John Catliff, the tournament's top scorer.
Canada came close to qualifying for the World Cup again in 1994 under the guidance of a defender on the 1986 team, Bob Lenarduzzi. They entered the tournament at the second round stage and advanced as group runners-up. Canada competed strongly in the final qualifying round, drawing their first match in Tegucigalpa after a controversial penalty allowed the Hondurans to draw even, winning their next two, over El Salvador and Honduras in Vancouver, losing convincingly at Azteca Stadium, and winning 2–1 in San Salvador. They went into their final group match against Mexico, in Toronto, needing a win to win the group and thus qualify directly for the World Cup. Canada went up 1–0 on a goal credited to Alex Bunbury off a free kick, but Mexico scored twice to win, 2–1. The loss meant Canada finished second and advanced to an intercontinental play-off series where they needed to win two rounds to qualify for the 1994 FIFA World Cup. The Reds went up against Oceania Football Confederation's champions Australia. Canada won the first leg 2–1 in Edmonton. Australia led the second leg 2–1 at the end of 90 minutes, sending the tie to extra time. There was no score in the extra 30 minutes, meaning the series was decided by a penalty shootout which Australia won 4–1 to eliminate Canada from contention. Australia went on to lose 2–1 on aggregate to Argentina, who advanced to the World Cup.
With the World Cup to be played in the United States, Canada had the opportunity to play a number of high-profile squads in tune-up matches. The highlight of this set of matches—played against Morocco, Brazil, Germany, Spain, and the Netherlands all within 13 days—was Canada holding eventual World Cup champions Brazil to a 1–1 draw at Commonwealth Stadium, on a 69th-minute equalizer by Eddy Berdusco, on Canada's only real scoring chance in the game.
With three countries set to qualify out of CONCACAF for the 1998 World Cup, and with Canada handily winning their second round group over El Salvador, Panama, and Cuba, expectations were high for a second qualification in 12 years in the spring of 1997. The aging Canadians, however, fared miserably, losing their opening game to Mexico 0–4 and the following one to the U.S. 0–3. In their next two matches, against El Salvador and Jamaica, they could only manage two 0–0 draws in Vancouver. A 1–0 win over Costa Rica in Edmonton in their next match thanks to a goal by Berdusco gave Canada some hope at the halfway point but losses to both Jamaica and El Salvador away ended any aspirations as they finished bottom of the group with 6 points from 10 games and a −15 goal difference. Having overseen two consecutive World Cup campaigns ending in the side failing to qualify, Lenarduzzi stepped down in 1997 and was replaced by interim head coach Bruce Twamley.

The Canadian Soccer Association turned to another German to lead the senior national team in 1998 with the signing of Holger Osieck. Success came quickly with Canada winning the CONCACAF Gold Cup in February 2000. After emerging from the first round on a coin-toss tiebreaker with invited side Republic of Korea, the Canucks scored a quarter-final upset win over Mexico. The win set the stage for an unprecedented run to the final, where Canada defeated Colombia 2–0 at Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum. Canada swept the awards ceremony, with goalkeeper Craig Forrest winning MVP honours, Carlo Corazzin securing the Golden Boot, and Richard Hastings named Rookie of the Tournament.
Expectations were again high following the winter's result, but the campaign sputtered. A positive 1–0 away result in Havana in June was followed by a listless 0–0 home draw against Cuba. For the semi-final round two out of four teams advanced. Canada was eliminated from World Cup contention after finishing third in the semi-final round. Canada managed just one goal in 6 games while conceding 8 to finish third in the standings, well adrift of advancing sides Trinidad and Tobago and Mexico.
Winning the Gold Cup earned Canada a place in the 2001 Confederations Cup, where the highlight was holding Brazil to a 0–0 draw. The Gold Cup victory also won them an invitation to compete in the Copa América 2001. When security concerns prompted the cancellation of the tournament, Canada disbanded their training camp. The tournament was then reinstated and held on schedule. The Canadian Soccer Association announced they would not be able to participate in the reinstated tournament.
Canada had another strong showing in the 2002 CONCACAF Gold Cup, losing to the United States in the semi-finals in penalties, and then defeating South Korea in the third-place game, 2–1. There was a Gold Cup held the following year so as to hold the event in years between the World Cup and the Olympics, and Canada was eliminated in the first round on goal difference. Head coach Osieck had seen the side progress. The coach resigned in September 2003 and former player Colin Miller was put in charge as an interim.
2004 marked the beginning of 2006 World Cup qualification and a new era under the guidance of former Canadian skipper Frank Yallop. Things began brightly, with the Canadians dispatching of Belize handily in the Premilinary Round, 8–0 on aggregate, in a home-and-home series. Matters turned, however, with Canada finishing bottom in a group featuring Costa Rica, Guatemala, and Honduras. They got only 5 points from 6 matches and a −4 goal difference. Hard times continued under Yallop as the Canucks again went out at the first barrier in the Gold Cup, losing to both the U.S. and Costa Rica, while defeating Cuba. The coach stayed on through 2005 into the following summer, overseeing a series a friendlies against European sides. He resigned on June 7, 2006, finishing with a win-lose record of 8–9–3.
Things turned around under interim coach Stephen Hart's guidance. Canada opened their 2007 CONCACAF Gold Cup campaign with a 2–1 win over Costa Rica. A 1–2 upset loss to upstarts Guadeloupe was followed by a 2–0 victory over Haiti, securing Canada first-place in their group. They next beat Guatemala 3–0 in their quarter-final match setting up a semi-final showdown with the host Americans. Substitute Iain Hume scored for Canada in the 76th minute to cut the United States' lead to 2–1. After the United States were reduced to ten men, Canada pressed for the equalizer but were denied when Atiba Hutchinson's stoppage-time goal was incorrectly flagged offside by linesman Ricardo Louisville and Canada was eliminated.
The team faced criticism for its poor handling of goalkeeper Greg Sutton, who suffered a concussion during a practice prior to the start of the Gold Cup. Without a doctor accompanying the team, Sutton instead saw a local physician who cleared him to practice, resulting in Sutton suffering post-concussion syndrome. Sutton was lost to his professional club Toronto FC for nearly a year.
Prior to the Gold Cup on May 18, 2007, the Canadian Soccer Association announced that former national team player Dale Mitchell would take over as head coach of the senior team after the 2007 FIFA U-20 World Cup. Mitchell had previously served as an assistant coach under Coach Frank Yallop.  Under Mitchell, Canada drew friendlies with Iceland and against Costa Rica, lost 0–2 to South Africa, had a 1–0 win over Martinique, and a 0–2 defeat to Estonia. Optimism grew, however, as Canada played well in a 2–3 loss to Brazil.
Despite defeating Saint Vincent and the Grenadines 7–1 on aggregate in a second-round series—they had had a bye in the first—Canada did not play at the level they had at the Gold Cup and were eliminated from qualifying for the 2010 World Cup. They conceded an equalizer shortly after scoring the opening goal in a 1–1 draw to Jamaica at BMO Field, conceded two second-half goals in quick succession in a 1–2 home loss to Honduras at Saputo Stadium, and then lost away to Mexico and Honduras. They finished last in the four-team group with just 2 points from 6 matches. On March 27, 2009, head coach Dale Mitchell was fired. The president of the Canadian Soccer Association, Dominic Maestracci, said that "the Canadian Soccer Association is committed to the future of our men's national team program. We have made this decision to move the program in a new direction." Technical director Stephen Hart was renamed as interim head coach. On December 9, 2009, Hart was named as head coach.

Stephen Hart's first competitive action as the full-time head coach was a poor showing at the 2011 CONCACAF Gold Cup, not managing to get out of the group stage. However, during the early stages qualifying for the 2014 World Cup, Canada topped their group in the second round but were eliminated in the third round of CONCACAF qualifying, finishing one point behind Honduras and Panama after losing 8–1 in Honduras on the final match day.
After a series of interim coaching changes following Stephen Hart's dismissal on October 12, 2012 Benito Floro replaced Colin Miller as Canada's coach on August 1, 2013. Being a coach with top-flight management experience in La Liga, he was expected to help Canada raise its competitiveness prior to 2018 FIFA World Cup qualification. In the midst of Floro's player identification and restructuring phase, the team experienced many difficulties including a 958-minute goal-scoring drought, which was finally broken by Atiba Hutchinson in a 1–1 draw with Bulgaria on May 23, 2014. Despite showing improvement with two draws in Europe, Canada continued to shed FIFA points having gone winless for nearly two years, and sank to their lowest ever FIFA ranking of 122 in August 2014. Canada ended a 16-match winless streak on September 10, 2014, defeating Jamaica 3–1 in Toronto.
Canada was drawn into the 2018 FIFA World Cup second round of qualifying against Dominica in June 2015. Canada entered the second round of 2018 World Cup qualifying against Dominica with a game at Windsor Park in Dominica which they won 2–0 with goals from Cyle Larin and a penalty converted by Russell Teibert. In the return leg at BMO Field in front of 9,749 fans they defeated Dominica 4–0 with two goals from Tosaint Ricketts and one each from Tesho Akindele and Cyle Larin.
The team did not score a single goal and finished last in their group in the 2015 CONCACAF Gold Cup after two 0–0 draws to El Salvador and Costa Rica, while also suffering a 1–0 loss against Jamaica.
Canada then advanced to the third round of 2018 World Cup qualifying against Belize, winning 4–1 on aggregate and advancing to the fourth round of 2018 World Cup qualifying. Canada was drawn into a group against Honduras, El Salvador and Mexico. They played their first pair of matches in the fourth round on November 13 and 17, 2015. The first match was played in Vancouver at BC Place against Honduras, resulting in a 1–0 win for Canada thanks to a deflected goal by Cyle Larin. The crowd of 20,108 set a new record for the Canadian men's team in the province of British Columbia.  In their next game on November 17, away at El Salvador, Canada drew with El Salvador 0-0 as Julian De Guzman broke Canada's record for most caps for the national team with his 85th cap, passing Paul Stalteri's record of 84 caps. With this result in Canada's last game of 2015, they ended off the year conceding just three goals in their final 12 games and in 14 games overall, they ended off with a record of 6 wins, 6 draws, and 2 losses.
On March 25, 2016, in a World Cup qualifier against Mexico at BC Place Stadium in Vancouver, 54,798 people were recorded in the stadium which set a new attendance record for a Canadian national team of any sport. Ultimately, however, Canada lost the game 3–0, but remained in second place in the group, keeping them in contention for World Cup qualification. On September 6, 2016, after not being able to qualify for the fifth round of the 2018 World Cup qualifying despite a 3–1 win over El Salvador, head coach Benito Floro was sacked on September 14, ending his reign as coach of the national team.

Canada announced Octavio Zambrano as the new coach of the national team on May 16, 2017, replacing Michael Findlay who was the interim coach after Floro's departure. He guided Canada to a quarterfinal finish at the 2017 CONCACAF Gold Cup, with the team getting out of the group stage for the first time since 2009. However, on January 8, 2018, Zambrano was let go and was replaced with John Herdman, who previously was the head coach of the Canadian women's national team.
Under Herdman, Canada qualified for the top division in the inaugural season of the CONCACAF Nations League following an undefeated qualifying campaign. Competing in CONCACAF Nations League A, Canada earned a 2–0 victory over the United States at BMO Field, Canada's first win against their American rivals since 1985. However, Canada would fall to a 4–1 defeat against the United States in the away leg and failed to qualify for the Nations League Finals.

Canada's national team was marked by the arrival of a golden generation of new young players, led by the first Canadian UEFA Champions League winner Alphonso Davies of Bayern Munich, the most expensive Canadian soccer player in history, Jonathan David who joined Lille for a €30-million fee in 2020 and the establishment of the Canadian Premier League, the first fully professional soccer league in the country. In the first round of World Cup qualifying, Canada finished with a 4–0–0 record to win Group B and progress to the second round. The second round was two leg home-and-away tie against Haiti which Canada won 4–0 on aggregate with a 1–0 win in the away leg and a 3–0 win in the home leg, the latter being played at SeatGeek Stadium in Chicago due to COVID-19 restrictions in Canada. The victory over Haiti led to Canada qualifying for the third and final round of World Cup qualifying for the first time since 1997.

Canada began the third round of World Cup qualifying unbeaten in its first eleven matches, finishing 2021 with its first win over Mexico in over 20 years to finish the year at the top of the table. It also ended the year 40th in the FIFA World Rankings, its highest-ever position to date, earning the team the honour of "Most Improved Side" after having started the year ranked 72nd.
On March 27, 2022, Canada defeated Jamaica 4–0 on Matchday 13 to qualify for the 2022 FIFA World Cup in Qatar. This ended a 36-year drought since the first and only time Canada played in the FIFA World Cup, in 1986. The speed of the team's ascent was such that it was subsequently revealed that neither the federation nor kit supplier Nike had anticipated them qualifying, and as a result they would be the only team in Qatar to not receive a special kit for the occasion. Defender Sam Adekugbe remarked "I think that just shows that no one really believed in us. I don't think Canada believed."

In Canada's first match of the tournament against Belgium on November 23, Davies failed to score an early penalty in an eventual 1–0 loss, despite Canada dictating most of the play, and failing to convert any of their 22 shots. Four days later, Davies scored Canada's first ever goal at the FIFA World Cup, in a game against Croatia. Croatia came back to win 4–1, eliminating Canada from the tournament after two matches. Canada were defeated 2–1 by Morocco in their final group match on December 1, finishing in last place in their group with zero points. Post-event assessments of Canada's performance were mixed, with many saying that opportunities had been missed, while also creating possibilities for the future 2026 FIFA World Cup that Canada would co-host.

Canada automatically qualified for the 2026 World Cup as co-host in February 2023. They also qualified to the 2023 CONCACAF Nations League Finals by winning Group C. A 2–0 victory over Panama on June 15, 2023 saw the national team reach its first event final in 23 years, where they lost to the United States 2–0. Following this, many of the team's established players opted not to attend the 2023 CONCACAF Gold Cup held later that same summer. After some difficulties in the group stage, Canada reached the quarter-final of the tournament, losing to the United States in a penalty shootout. The summer championships marked the end of Herdman's tenure with Canada Soccer, with his departure coming at the end of August to manage Toronto FC of Major League Soccer, amidst media discussion of conflicts with the federation over funding and playing opportunities.
Interim coach Mauro Biello was tasked with guiding the team through the quarter-finals of the 2023–24 CONCACAF Nations League A in November 2023, where victory in a two-legged aggregate match or away goals rule against Jamaica would both send them to the following spring's semi-finals and qualify them to participate in CONMEBOL's 2024 Copa América. After defeating Jamaica 2–1 in the away leg, Canada needed only a draw in the home match at BMO Field to advance. Leading halfway through, the team collapsed to lose 3–2 in the second half and 3–2 on away goals, as a result missing both the Nation's League semi-final and immediate qualification to the Copa América. The loss to Jamaica prompted considerable criticism of the team, Biello, and the federation, with The Athletic opining that Canada's "humiliating loss" should be considered its worst defeat since falling 8–1 to Honduras in World Cup qualification in 2012. As a result, the qualifying play-off for a final place in the Copa América was scheduled on March 23, 2024 against Trinidad and Tobago, which they later won 2–0.
In May 2024, Canada Soccer hired Jesse Marsch to serve as Herdman's permanent replacement as coach. Due to ongoing financial difficulties, the money to pay Marsch was found via donations from MLS clubs CF Montreal, Toronto FC, and Vancouver Whitecaps FC and other private parties. This drew media attention due to the unusual arrangement of the naming rights to the coaching position being given as part of the arrangement, called the "MLS Canada Men's National Team Head Coach". In advance of the Copa América, Marsch's first matches with the team were two friendlies against high-profile opponents, first a lopsided 4–0 loss to the Netherlands, and then a goalless draw with second-ranked France that was generally considered a major success. Canada began Group A play at the Copa against world number one-ranked Argentina, a 2–0 loss that nevertheless was generally considered a credible showing. They defeated Peru 1–0, with David scoring the team's first goal of the Marsch era to earn the country's first victory over a South American team since the 2000 Gold Cup final. A draw with Chile saw Canada finish second in the group and advance to the knockout stage, where they defeated Venezuela 4–3 on penalties after a 1–1 draw in regulation time to reach a semi-final rematch with Argentina. After another 2–0 loss to the Argentines, Canada played Uruguay in the third-place match. They led 2–1 for the final ten minutes of regulation, but allowed a tying goal in stoppage time, and lost 4–3 on penalties to finish fourth.

Canada has a rivalry with the United States. The United States-Canada rivalry stems from a generally friendly rivalry between the two nations. The two teams frequently face each other in the Gold Cup. The United States currently leads the series 18-10-11 (W-L-T). Historically, the United States has been the stronger side, having qualified for 11 World Cups while Canada qualified for two. Until recently, Canada was not seen as a competitive rival by a number of American fans as it had not beaten the United States in a 34-year stretch. That streak was snapped on October 15, 2019, when Canada defeated the United States 2–0 at BMO Field in Toronto. The following month, on November 15, the United States beat Canada 4–1 in Orlando. Since then, matches between the two have been very competitive. The United States defeated Canada 1–0 in a 2021 Gold Cup matchup in Kansas City. In 2022 World Cup qualifying, Canada earned a 1–1 draw in Nashville and defeated the United States 2–0 in Hamilton. 
On June 18, 2023 the United States defeated Canada 2-0 in the 2022-23 CONCACAF Nations League final, marking the first time the two nations faced each other in the final of a major CONCACAF tournament. Three weeks later, the U.S. eliminated Canada 3–2 on penalties in the 2023 CONCACAF Gold Cup quarter-final.

BMO Field is Canada's largest natural turf stadium, followed by Saputo Stadium, in Montreal. Canada played their 2018 FIFA World Cup qualifiers at BC Place in Vancouver. During 2022 FIFA World Cup qualifying, Canada used BMO Field in Toronto, Commonwealth Stadium in Edmonton, and Tim Hortons Field in Hamilton. Due to travel restrictions during the COVID-19 pandemic, Canada played their home games for the first and second rounds of 2022 World Cup qualifying in stadiums in the United States.

The following is a list of match results in the last twelve months, as well as any future matches that have been scheduled.
  Win
  Draw
  Loss
  Fixture

 

 
 

As of May 29, 2024

Caretaker managers are listed in italics.

The following 26 players were selected for the 2024 Copa América.  
Caps and goals as of July 13, 2024, after the match against  Uruguay.

The following players have also been called up within the last twelve months.

As of July 13, 2024, after the match against  Uruguay.
Players in bold are still active with the national team.

  Champions    Runners-up    Third place     Tournament played fully or partially on home soil  

*Denotes draws include knockout matches decided via penalty shoot-out.

*Denotes draws include knockout matches decided via penalty shoot-out.

After 1988, Olympic soccer was contested by the U–23 team.

Key
 
The following table shows Canada's all-time official international record per opponent:

As of July 13, 2024

Major competitions

CONCACAF Championship / Gold Cup
Champions (2): 1985, 2000
Third place (2): 2002, 2007
CONCACAF Nations League
Runners-up: 2022–23
Other competitions

North American Nations Cup
Winners: 1990
Summer Olympics
Winners: 1904
CONCACAF Olympic Qualifying Tournament
Runners-up: 1984
Canada Cup 
Runners-up: 1995

Canada Soccer Association
CONCACAF
National teams
Men's
Canada men's national under-23 soccer team
Canada men's national under-20 soccer team
Canada men's national under-17 soccer team
Canada men's national beach soccer team
Canada men's national futsal team
Women's
Canada women's national soccer team
Canada women's national under-20 soccer team
Canada women's national under-17 soccer team

Kloke, Joshua (October 4, 2022). The Voyageurs: The Canadian Men's Soccer Team's Quest to Reach the World Cup. Dundurn Press. ISBN 978-1459750456.

Official website 
FIFA profile
Canada Soccer records and results for 2024
RSSSF archive of most capped players and highest goalscorers
International results until 1999</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>2024 National Women's Soccer League season</title><description>The 2024 National Women's Soccer League season is the twelfth season of the National Women's Soccer League, the top division of women's soccer in the United States. Including the NWSL's two professional predecessors, Women's Professional Soccer (2009–2011) and the Women's United Soccer Association (2001–2003), it is the 18th overall season of FIFA and USSF-sanctioned top division women's soccer in the United States. The league has 14 teams following the addition of expansion teams Bay FC and Utah Royals—the latter being the revival of a team that had played in the league from 2018 to 2020.
The season began with the 2024 NWSL Challenge Cup, a supercup match between the reigning playoff champion (NJ/NY Gotham FC) and NWSL Shield winner San Diego Wave FC, on March 15, 2024. The regular season began the following day and will run until November 3; it will pause for a month between July 8 and August 18 for the 2024 Summer Olympics. Each team will play 26 matches, an increase of four from the 2023 season. The playoffs will comprise the top eight teams and run from November 9 to November 23. The 2024 season is the first under a new broadcast agreement with CBS Sports, ESPN, Amazon Prime Video and Scripps Sports; a total of 118 matches will be televised or streamed.
In addition to league play, 2024 marks the debut of the NWSL x Liga MX Femenil Summer Cup, an international competition between clubs from the NWSL and Liga MX Femenil of Mexico. It is scheduled to be played from July to October.

Note: All teams use Nike as their kit manufacturer as part of a league-wide sponsorship agreement renewed in November 2021.

The initial determining factor for a team's position in the standings is most points earned, with three points earned for a win, one point for a draw, and zero points for a loss. If two or more teams tie in total points total when determining rank, playoff qualification, and seeding, the NWSL uses the following tiebreaker criteria, going down the list until all teams are ranked.

Greater goal difference across the entire regular season (against all teams, not just tied teams).
Most total wins across the entire regular season (against all teams, not just tied teams).
Most goals scored across the entire regular season (against all teams, not just tied teams).
Head-to-head results (total points) between the tied teams.
Head-to-head most goals scored between the tied teams.
Fewest disciplinary points accumulated across the entire regular season (against all teams, not just tied teams).
Coin flip (if two teams are tied) or drawing of lots (if three or more teams are tied).

Considering each week to end when the NWSL releases their weekly standing tweet 

Legend: Gold = first place; green = playoff position; Red = last place.

Ranked from highest to lowest average attendance.

Updated through July 10

Updated through June 30

As of July 10, 2024.

In a change of format, the Challenge Cup will be played as a one-off super cup, contested by the winners of the previous season's NWSL Championship, NJ/NY Gotham FC, and NWSL Shield, San Diego Wave FC.

It is scheduled to be played from July to October.

As of July 12, 2024

Official website</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_National_Women%27s_Soccer_League_season</link></item><item><title>Beach soccer</title><description>Beach soccer, also known as beach football, sand football or beasal, is a variant of association football played on a beach or some form of sand.
Football has long been played informally on beaches, but the introduction of beach soccer was an attempt to codify rules for the game in 1992 by the founders of Beach Soccer Worldwide, a company set up to develop the sport and responsible for the majority of its tournaments.
The first international matches were played in 1993 for men and 2009 for women. As of July 2023, there are 193 men's and 64 women's clubs and 101 men's and 23 women's national teams sorted in the Beach Soccer Worldwide Rankings.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beach_soccer</link></item><item><title>Miles Robinson (soccer)</title><description>Miles Gordon Robinson (born March 14, 1997) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a center-back for Major League Soccer club FC Cincinnati and the United States national team.
Born in Arlington, Massachusetts, Robinson began his career with FC Boston Bolts before playing college soccer with the Syracuse Orange. After two seasons with Syracuse, Robinson was drafted with the second overall pick in the 2017 MLS SuperDraft by expansion club Atlanta United. He initially did not feature for the side, and was loaned out to the Charleston Battery in 2017, followed by reserve affiliate Atlanta United 2 in 2018. From the 2019 season, Robinson began appearing as a regular starter for the club following the arrival of Frank de Boer as head coach.
Robinson made his senior debut for the United States in September 2019. In July 2021, he was selected as part of the 23-man squad for the CONCACAF Gold Cup. In the final against Mexico, Robinson scored the winner in extra-time to give the United States the championship.

Robinson was raised in Arlington, Massachusetts. His interest in soccer began when watching his older sister, Rebecca, play in local matches and he began playing organized soccer when he was four years old. He attended Arlington High School, where he played for the school's basketball team. During his junior season, Robinson was the Middlesex League co-MVP and lead his team in scoring, assists, rebounds, and steals. John Bowler, his basketball coach at Arlington, praised Robinson's abilities on the court: "His IQ, where he is supposed to be and changing speeds, is just unbelievable. Even though you know he's quick, he'll lull you to sleep. If you relax for a second, with one step, he's right by you."
In soccer, Robinson was part of the youth team at FC Boston Bolts, meaning he couldn't participate with the soccer team at Arlington High School. Brian Ainscough, the chief executive officer for the Bolts, singled out Robinson's build and potential at a young age: "He was this kid that was 5-foot-9, with a size-13 shoe, looking like Bambi... We’re lucky we have him as a soccer player, so be happy with that."

In 2015, Robinson committed to playing college soccer at Syracuse University, joining Ian McIntyre's Orange. He made his debut for the side on August 28, 2015, starting in a 2–1 opening day defeat against the Hofstra Pride. On September 19, Robinson scored his first goal for Syracuse in a 3–1 away defeat against the Wake Forest Demon Deacons. As a freshman, Robinson started all 25 matches for Syracuse, scoring four goals. In November 2015, following a victory over Notre Dame, Syracuse qualified for the NCAA Tournament with a record best for the program sixth seed. Robinson started for Syracuse in their first three matches of the tournament, leading the Orange to the College Cup in Kansas City. On December 11, Robinson started in Syracuse's opening College Cup match against the Clemson Tigers. He helped the Orange keep a clean sheet through extra time, however the side would be knocked out 4–1 in the penalty shootout.
Prior to the NCAA Tournament, Robinson earned a spot in the Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC) All-Tournament Team.
During his sophomore season, Robinson earned the ACC Defensive Player of the Year award, starting all 17 matches for Syracuse, scoring another four goals. He once again helped Syracuse qualify for the 2016 NCAA Tournament but couldn't prevent the side from falling 1–0 against the North Carolina Tar Heels in the third round. On December 10, 2016, Robinson was named into the National Soccer Coaches Association NCAA Division I Men's All-America First Team, being joined by future Atlanta United teammates Gordon Wild and Julian Gressel.

Following the 2015 college season, Robinson joined FC Boston, the semi-professional outfit of his youth club FC Boston Bolts, in the Premier Development League. He made his debut on May 21, 2016, against F.A. Euro, starting in the 3–1 away victory. Robinson played six matches during his time with FC Boston and following the season, was named as the top defender among college prospects by the United Soccer League.

On January 4, 2017, Robinson elected to leave Syracuse early and signed a Generation Adidas contract with Major League Soccer, allowing him to be selected in the 2017 MLS SuperDraft. Robinson was selected as the second overall pick in the draft on January 13 by expansion side Atlanta United, just behind first pick Abu Danladi.

On May 23, 2017, after only appearing on the bench for Atlanta United, Robinson joined United Soccer League club Charleston Battery on a short-term loan. He made his professional debut for Charleston two days later in their 1–0 away victory over Bethlehem Steel, partnering with Taylor Mueller. On July 26, Robinson scored his first goal for the Battery, an 11th-minute opener in a 2–2 draw against the Pittsburgh Riverhounds.

On June 14, 2017, Robinson returned from his loan with Charleston Battery temporarily to make his debut for Atlanta United in their U.S. Open Cup match against the Battery themselves. He started next to Anton Walkes as Atlanta United won 3–2. This would be Robinson's only appearance for Atlanta United in his debut professional season.
Robinson began the next season on the bench for Atlanta United against the Vancouver Whitecaps FC on March 17, 2018. On March 24, Robinson appeared for Atlanta United 2, the club's reserve affiliate in the United Soccer League, against New York Red Bulls II, starting in the 3–1 victory. On April 7, Robinson made his first league appearance after Leandro González Pírez was suspended. Starting for head coach Tata Martino in a back three against Los Angeles FC, Atlanta won 5–0 at home. He made only 14 appearances for Atlanta United in 2018, two of which came in the 2018 MLS playoffs. On November 11, due to an injury to starter Jeff Larentowicz, Robinson was included in the starting line-up for Atlanta United against New York City FC in the Eastern Conference semifinals second-leg. He held his own in the back three as Atlanta United won 3–1 and advanced on aggregate. Robinson was then selected to the bench for Atlanta United in MLS Cup 2018 against the Portland Timbers, but he did not come off the bench as his side won 2–0, winning the championship.
Following the 2018 season, Robinson had a breakthrough season in 2019 under new head coach Frank de Boer. He made his North American debut on February 21 against Herediano in the CONCACAF Champions League. He started alongside González Pírez and Michael Parkhurst as Atlanta United were defeated 3–1 away. He started the second leg matchup as well which saw Atlanta United win 4–0, advancing 5–3 on aggregate. Under de Boer, Robinson became a solid starter for Atlanta United's defense, as he started in 33 out of 34 matches during the regular season. On June 18, Robinson scored his first competitive goal for Atlanta United in their 3–2 victory over the Columbus Crew in the U.S. Open Cup.
On August 14, 2019, Robinson came on as a substitute in Atlanta United's 3–2 victory over Mexican side América in the Campeones Cup. He was then selected to start in the U.S. Open Cup Final on August 27 against Minnesota United, as Atlanta United won 2–1. This was Robinson's second major trophy. Following the end of the regular season, Robinson finished third in the voting for MLS Defender of the Year, finishing behind Ike Opara and Walker Zimmerman. He was then selected into the MLS Best XI for the 2019 season. On October 8, 2019, Robinson signed a new contract with Atlanta United, keeping him with the club until 2023.
In October 2019, while away with the United States national team, Robinson suffered a hamstring injury which would rule him out of the MLS Cup Playoffs, ending his season.
The next season, following his recovery, Robinson suffered a quad strain during the club's pre-season match against Leones Negros. The injury meant that Robinson would miss Atlanta United's opening round matches against Motagua in the Champions League and their first two league matches against Nashville SC and FC Cincinnati. Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, play was temporarily suspended until July, when Atlanta United entered the MLS is Back Tournament. Robinson was listed in the squad as healthy. He made his first competitive appearance of the season on July 11 in their opener against the New York Red Bulls, starting as Atlanta were defeated 1–0. He made 18 appearances during the 2020 season, but couldn't help the club avoid missing the playoffs for the first time in club history.
On August 4, 2021, Robinson was selected to represent Major League Soccer in the MLS All-Star Game against the Liga MX All-Stars. He came on as a substitute during the match on August 25 at Banc of California Stadium in Los Angeles as the MLS All-Stars won 3–2 in the penalty shootout.
On May 7, 2022, Robinson tore his left Achilles tendon during an MLS match against the Chicago Fire. He underwent surgery on May 9, 2022, with the recovery expected to prevent him from playing in the upcoming 2022 World Cup.

On January 3, 2024, Robinson signed as a free agent with FC Cincinnati on a one-year deal, with Cincinnati having the option to extend the deal for another year.

Robinson has represented the United States at the under-20 and under-23 levels. In 2013, he was invited to train with the under-18 side. Following his freshman season at Syracuse, Robinson was called into the under-20 side by Tab Ramos. In July 2016, Robinson started in every match for the under-20's during the 2016 NTC Invitational.
On March 19, 2019, Robinson was named by Jason Kreis into the under-23 side which would play three friendlies that month in preparation for 2020 Olympic qualification. He made his debut for the team on March 22 against Egypt, coming on as a halftime substitute in the 2–0 defeat. In February 2021, Robinson was selected again by Kreis into the preliminary roster prior for qualification but was not released by Atlanta United as they were preparing for the upcoming 2021 season.
On August 28, 2019, Robinson was called into the senior national team by Gregg Berhalter for two September friendlies against Mexico and Uruguay. He proceeded to make his international debut on September 6 against Mexico at MetLife Stadium, coming on as a 58th-minute substitute in a 3–0 defeat. In December 2019, after returning to Atlanta United injured, thus missing the MLS playoffs, his club declined to release Robinson for the January 2020 friendlies. He would return to the national team setup in January 2021, being called into camp that month. On January 31, Robinson scored his first international goal against Trinidad and Tobago, the fifth in a 7–0 victory in Orlando.
In July 2021, Robinson was named into the 23-man United States squad for the 2021 CONCACAF Gold Cup. Going into the tournament, Robinson was expected to be the starting center-back. He would go on to start in all six matches for the United States, playing every minute of the competition. In the United States' second group stage match against Martinique, Robinson scored the third goal in a 6–1 victory. On August 1, Robinson started for the United States in the Gold Cup final against Mexico. After the match went into extra-time tied 0–0, Robinson scored the winning goal in the 117th minute, a header that came off a free kick from Kellyn Acosta, giving the United States a 1–0 victory and their first final victory against Mexico since 2007.

As of match played July 13, 2024

As of match played March 21, 2024

As of match played March 21, 2024. United States score listed first, score column indicates score after each Robinson goal.

Atlanta United

MLS Cup: 2018
U.S. Open Cup: 2019
Campeones Cup: 2019
United States

CONCACAF Gold Cup: 2021
CONCACAF Nations League: 2022–23, 2023–24
Individual

ACC Defender of the Year: 2016
MLS Best XI: 2019, 2021
CONCACAF Gold Cup Best XI: 2021
MLS All-Star: 2021, 2024

Miles Robinson at Soccerway.com
Miles Robinson at WorldFootball.net
Miles Robinson at Soccerbase.com
Miles Robinson at National-Football-Teams.com
Miles Robinson at FBref.com
Miles Robinson at Major League Soccer
Miles Robinson at FC Cincinnati
Miles Robinson at Atlanta United FC (archived)
Miles Robinson at U.S. Soccer</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miles_Robinson_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>Quinn Sullivan (soccer)</title><description>Quinn Krippendorff Sullivan (born March 27, 2004) is an American professional soccer player who plays as an attacking midfielder or winger for Major League Soccer club Philadelphia Union.

Sullivan, who is a dual citizen, began his youth career at Fishtown A.C. and then transferred to the Philadelphia Union academy where he attended the prestigious YSC Academy School. He made his professional debut at the age of 16 years old with the club's reserve team, Philadelphia Union II, on July 18, 2020, against the Pittsburgh Riverhounds. He came on as a substitute in the second half.
Sullivan officially signed for the first team on November 12, 2020, as a homegrown player alongside childhood teammate Brandan Craig. Sullivan's contract began as a rostered player for the 2021 season. His first minutes for the Union were late-game substitutions during the Union's first CONCACAF Champions League campaign. Sullivan made his first league start for the Union on June 26 against Chicago Fire, where he scored his first goal to equalize the match at 1–1. His first professional goal for the Union earned Goal of the Week honors, and he subsequently added another GOTW.

Sullivan has represented the United States under-20 team in 19 occasions.
Overall he has scored 10 goals in those appearances and added five assists. In the lead up to the CONCACAF Championship he scored a hat trick as a substitute in a come from behind win over River Plate's reserve team and added another goal in a 2–2 tie versus the Argentina U20's.
In CONCACAF U20 group play, Quinn scored a hat trick in a 3–0 win against Cuba to finish top of the group. He also scored a brace (2 goals) against Nicaragua in the quarterfinals and another goal against the host team, Honduras, in the semifinal. He has tallied three assists and a drawn pk in tournament play as well.

Sullivan comes from a soccer family: his father, Brendan, played for five clubs over a six-year professional career in the A-League. Prior to that, Brendan Sullivan was an All-Ivy selection at University of Pennsylvania and starred at St. Joseph's Prep in Philadelphia. He then went on to coach at his alma mater. Quinn's mother, Heike, played Division I soccer and captained the University of Pennsylvania women's team. Quinn's younger brother Cavan is a U.S. youth international who also plays for Philadelphia Union. His two other brothers, the younger twins Declan and Ronan, are also youth soccer players, with both currently attending YSC Academy and playing for MLS NEXT affiliate FC DELCO.
His cousin is Chris Albright, an American international who played two seasons for the Union, and his grandfather is Larry Sullivan, who served as the head coach at Villanova from 1991 to 2007. Sullivan's uncle, Bryan Sullivan, was a Division I goalkeeper at Philadelphia Textile and was also on the coaching staff at Villanova.
His maternal grandmother is Bangladeshi and his maternal grandfather is Klaus Krippendorff.

As of match played July 7, 2024

Philadelphia Union

MLS Cup runner-up: 2022
United States U20

CONCACAF U-20 Championship: 2022
Individual

CONCACAF U-20 Championship Best XI: 2022

Profile at the USSDA website</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quinn_Sullivan_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>Soccer-specific stadium</title><description>Soccer-specific stadium is a term used mainly in the United States and Canada to refer to a sports stadium either purpose-built or fundamentally redesigned for soccer and whose primary function is to host soccer matches, as opposed to a multi-purpose stadium which is for a variety of sports. A soccer-specific stadium may host other sporting events (such as lacrosse, American football and rugby) and concerts, but the design and purpose of a soccer-specific stadium is primarily for soccer. Some facilities (for example SeatGeek Stadium, Toyota Stadium and Historic Crew Stadium) have a permanent stage at one end of the stadium used for staging concerts.
A soccer-specific stadium typically has amenities, dimensions and scale suitable for soccer in North America, including a scoreboard, video screen, luxury suites and possibly a roof. The field dimensions are within the range found optimal by FIFA: 110–120 yards (100–110 m) long by 70–80 yards (64–75 m) wide. These soccer field dimensions are wider than the regulation American football field width of 53+1⁄3 yards (48.8 m), or the 65-yard (59 m) width of a Canadian football field. The playing surface typically consists of grass as opposed to artificial turf, as the latter is generally disfavored for soccer matches since players are more susceptible to injuries. However, some soccer specific stadiums, such as Portland's Providence Park and Creighton University's Morrison Stadium, do have artificial turf.
The seating capacity is generally between 18,000 and 30,000 for a Major League Soccer franchise, or smaller for college or minor league soccer teams. This is in comparison to the much larger American football stadiums that mostly range between 60,000 and 80,000 in which the original North American Soccer League teams played and most MLS teams occupied during the league's inception. As opposed to gridiron-style football stadiums, where the front row of seats is elevated several feet above the field of play to allow spectators to see over the heads of substitute players and coaches on the sidelines, soccer-specific venues typically have the front row closer to the level of the pitch.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer-specific_stadium</link></item></channel></rss>