<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Congressional Soccer Match</title><description>The Congressional Soccer Match (CSM) is an annual event held in Washington, D.C., that features Members of Congress, Hill staffers, corporations, and community members to participate in a soccer tournament.
The event consists of an Embassy tournament, the Congressional Soccer Match, and a Congressional Staff vs Lobbyist Match.
The event is hosted by the United States Soccer Foundation. As one of the Foundation’s annual charity events, all proceeds from the event support the Foundation’s life-changing programs that help children in underserved communities embrace active and healthy lifestyles while nurturing their personal growth through trained coach-mentors.
As of 2024, the defending champions are the Republicans.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Congressional_Soccer_Match</link></item><item><title>United States men's national under-20 soccer team</title><description>The United States U-20 men's national soccer team is controlled by the United States Soccer Federation. The highest level of competition in which the team competes is the FIFA U-20 World Cup, which is held every two years.
The United States' best finish came in the 1989 FIFA World Youth Championship, when the U.S. beat Iraq in the quarterfinal before losing to Nigeria in overtime in the semifinal and Brazil in the third-place match. Steve Snow tied for second in the tournament with three goals.
The U.S. reached the quarterfinals in 1993 but lost to Brazil. After missing out in 1995, the U.S. began a run of six consecutive qualifications in 1997, reaching the second round in five consecutive tournaments. Of those tournaments, the best U.S. performance came in 2003, when the U.S. reached the quarterfinal and led Argentina 1–0 in the final minutes before falling 2–1 in extra time. The U.S. also reached the quarterfinal of the 2007 Cup before losing 2–1 in extra time to Austria.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_under-20_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Sophia Smith (soccer, born 2000)</title><description>Sophia Olivia Smith (born August 10, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a forward for Portland Thorns FC of the National Women's Soccer League (NWSL) and the United States national team. She played college soccer at Stanford University, helping the Cardinal win the national championship in 2019. Smith was the first overall pick in the 2020 NWSL College Draft.
In 2022, Smith was named NWSL Most Valuable Player (MVP) and U.S. Soccer Female Player of the Year. She earned MVP honors at the 2022 NWSL Championship after helping the Thorns win the title. In 2023, she won the NWSL Golden Boot for most goals in the season.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sophia_Smith_(soccer,_born_2000)</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. FC Cincinnati are the reigning Supporters' Shield holders; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and is scheduled to end on October 19, with a pause from mid-July to mid-August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprises all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup Playoffs are scheduled to begin in October and conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS will only send 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allows most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS will be part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, the best result ever by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups (seven consecutive appearances between 1990 and 2014), a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016. The team's head coach is Gregg Berhalter, who was re-appointed in June 2023.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>The Soccer Tournament 2024</title><description>The Soccer Tournament 2024, also referred to as TST 2024, was the second annual edition of The Soccer Tournament. The tournament was held from 5–10 June 2024 in Cary, North Carolina. There were two tournaments, one each for men and women, with both having a $1 million prize for the winners.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Soccer_Tournament_2024</link></item><item><title>Chris Richards (soccer)</title><description>Christopher Jeffrey Richards (born March 28, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a center-back or defensive midfielder for Premier League club Crystal Palace and the United States national team.
A youth player for FC Dallas in his home country, Richards began his professional career with Bundesliga club Bayern Munich, initially playing for the club's reserve team. After loan spells at 1899 Hoffenheim, he was signed by Crystal Palace in 2022.
A former youth player for his country, Richards received his first senior call-up for the United States in 2020, winning the CONCACAF Nations League in 2023 after scoring in the final.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Richards_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>The Soccer Tournament</title><description>The Soccer Tournament (TST) is a seven-a-side association football tournament played in the United States, established by TBT Enterprises, creator of The Basketball Tournament (TBT). TST was announced on October 11, 2022 to feature 32 teams with a $1 million winner-take-all prize. TST is partly owned by Golden State Warriors point guard Chris Paul.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Soccer_Tournament</link></item></channel></rss>