<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT), officially recognized as USA by FIFA, represents the United States in men's international soccer. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA since 1914 and was a founding member of CONCACAF since 1961. It was also affiliated with NAFC, which was a predecessor confederation of CONCACAF and the former governing soccer body in North America from 1946 to 1961.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarter-finals at the 2002 World Cup. The U.S. will host 2026 alongside Mexico and Canada.
The United States are the second most successful national team in its confederation, winning 10 CONCACAF continental titles (seven CONCACAF Gold Cups and three CONCACAF Nations League titles). The United States finished fourth place in two Copa América editions (1995 and 2016). Globally, the United States finished runners-up in the 2009 FIFA Confederations Cup, beating top-ranked European champions Spain in the semi-final and losing to Brazil in the final.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Soccer in the United States</title><description>Soccer is the fourth most popular sport in the United States behind American football, basketball, and baseball, respectively. 27% of the US sports fans show an interest in soccer.
The United States Soccer Federation (USSF) governs most levels of soccer in the United States, including the national teams, professional leagues, and amateur leagues, being the highest soccer authority in the country. The National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) governs most colleges; secondary schools are governed by state-level associations, with the National Federation of State High School Associations (NFHS) setting the rules at that level. The match regulations are generally the same between the three governing bodies although there are many subtle differences.
As of May 2015, over 24.4 million people play soccer in the United States. In 2017, Gallup reported that soccer was the third-most watched team sport in the U.S., behind only basketball and American football. 
The highest-level of men's professional soccer in the United States is Major League Soccer (MLS). The league's predecessor was the major professional North American Soccer League (NASL), which existed from 1968 until 1984. MLS began to play in 1996 with 10 teams and has grown to 29 teams (26 in the United States and 3 in Canada), with further expansion planned to at least 30 teams. The MLS season runs from February to November, with the regular-season winner awarded the Supporters' Shield and the post-season winner awarded the MLS Cup. With an average attendance of over 20,000 per game, MLS has the third-highest average attendance of any sports league in the United States after the National Football League (NFL) and Major League Baseball (MLB), and is the seventh-highest attended professional soccer league worldwide. MLS uses franchised clubs similar to other major American sports leagues, rather than the promotion and relegation model used for club soccer in European nations.
The first women's professional soccer league in the United States was formed by Tracey Higgins after the success of the 1999 Women's World Cup. The Women's United Soccer Association (WUSA) ran from 2001 to 2003 and featured many of the World Cup stars, including Mia Hamm, Michelle Akers and Brandi Chastain. Its successor Women's Professional Soccer (WPS) ran from 2009 to 2012. Currently, the National Women's Soccer League (NWSL) is the top professional league in the country; it was formed in 2012 with play starting in 2013. The NWSL season runs from spring to early fall (typically April – October).
American soccer fans follow the American national teams in international competition. The 2015 FIFA Women's World Cup final drew a record 26.7 million viewers, greater than the final games of the 2014 World Series or the 2015 NBA Finals, and the 2010 Men's World Cup final drew 26.5 million viewers. The women's national team has won four Women's World Cup titles and five gold medals at the Summer Olympics and the men's national team played in every World Cup from 1990 to 2014 and returned to the World Cup in 2022.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_in_the_United_States</link></item></channel></rss>