<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. Inter Miami CF won the 2024 Supporters' Shield; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and is scheduled to end on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs are scheduled to begin in October and conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS are part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.
The United States will be the host country for the 2025 FIFA Club World Cup. MLS clubs can qualify as a host nation club; however, the criteria for selection has not been announced. MLS clubs have also been able to qualify through the 2021–2024 editions of the CONCACAF Champions Cup/CONCACAF Champions League. Seattle Sounders FC have qualified as the 2022 CONCACAF Champions League winners.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>Chris Richards (soccer)</title><description>Christopher Jeffrey Richards (born March 28, 2000) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a center-back or defensive midfielder for Premier League club Crystal Palace and the United States national team.
A youth player for FC Dallas in his home country, Richards began his professional career with Bundesliga club Bayern Munich, initially playing for the club's reserve team. After loan spells at 1899 Hoffenheim, he was signed by Crystal Palace in 2022.
A former youth player for his country, Richards received his first senior call-up for the United States in 2020, winning the CONCACAF Nations League in 2023 after scoring in the final.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Richards_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup qualification (UEFA)</title><description>The 2025 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup will be the 13th edition of the FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup, the premier international beach soccer championship contested by men's national teams of the member associations of FIFA. Overall, this will be the 23rd edition of a world cup in beach soccer since the establishment of the Beach Soccer World Championships which ran from 1995 to 2004 but was not governed by FIFA; the World Cup took place annually until 2009 when it then became a biennial event.
It will take place in Victoria, capital of Seychelles, between 1 and 11 May 2025. This will be the first time that Seychelles has hosted a FIFA tournament, and the first Beach Soccer World Cup to be played in Africa.
Brazil are the defending champions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_FIFA_Beach_Soccer_World_Cup</link></item><item><title>David Wagner (soccer)</title><description>David Wagner (born 19 October 1971) is a professional football manager and former player who was most recently the manager of EFL Championship club Norwich City.
Wagner grew up in West Germany. He made his professional debut with Eintracht Frankfurt in 1990 and played as a striker for several clubs in the first and second division of German football. Son of an American stepfather and German mother, Wagner played for the United States national team, earning eight caps from 1996 until 1998.
From 2011 to 2015 Wagner managed Borussia Dortmund II. In November 2015 took the manager's position at Huddersfield Town, whom he led to the Premier League via the 2017 EFL Championship play-off final. He left Huddersfield in January 2019, and then had brief spells at Bundesliga club Schalke 04 and Swiss Super League club Young Boys.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Wagner_(soccer)</link></item></channel></rss>