<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Olivia Smith (soccer)</title><description>Olivia Smith (born August 5, 2004) is a Canadian professional soccer player who plays as a forward for Women's Super League club Arsenal and the Canada national team.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olivia_Smith_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>Quinn Sullivan (soccer)</title><description>Quinn Krippendorff Sullivan (born March 27, 2004) is an American professional soccer player who plays as an attacking midfielder or winger for Major League Soccer club Philadelphia Union and the United States national team.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quinn_Sullivan_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>Australia men's national under-23 soccer team</title><description>The Australia national under-23 soccer team represents Australia in international under-23 soccer and at the Olympic Games. The team is controlled by the governing body for soccer in Australia, Football Australia (FA), which is currently a member of the Asian Football Confederation (AFC) and the regional ASEAN Football Federation (AFF) since leaving the Oceania Football Confederation (OFC) in 2006. The team's official nickname is the Olyroos.
Australia's first two appearances in the Olympic Games saw the senior men's team participate, but in 1992 the eligibility was restricted to players under the age of 23, while in 1996, it was decided to allow teams to choose three over-age players in the final Olympic squads.
The team has represented Australia at the Olympic Games on six occasions, in 1992, 1996, 2000, 2004, 2008 and 2020 games. The team also represented Australia at the AFC U-23 Championship tournaments in 2013, 2016, 2018 &amp; 2020.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Australia_men%27s_national_under-23_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>2025 Euro Beach Soccer League</title><description>The 2025 Euro Beach Soccer League is the 28th edition of the Euro Beach Soccer League (EBSL), the annual, premier competition in European beach soccer contested between men's national teams. It is organised by Beach Soccer Worldwide (BSWW).
This season, the competing teams continue to take part in two divisions: the top tier (Division A) and the bottom tier (Division B).
Portugal are the defending champions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_Euro_Beach_Soccer_League</link></item><item><title>Zimbabwe Premier Soccer League</title><description>Zimbabwe Premier Soccer League is the top professional division of the Zimbabwe Football Association. It was founded in 1980, as a successor to the 1962 formed Rhodesia National Football League. It is currently sponsored by Delta Beverages under the Castle Lager brand and hence is known as Castle Lager Premier Soccer League. The current sponsorship deal runs from 2011 and is worth $3.6 million.
The league consists of 18 teams listed below, that play a total of 34 matches. The season runs from April to November. Most matches are played during weekends on Saturdays and Sundays. Postponed matches are played midweek. At the end of the season four teams are relegated into the lower division and an equal number promoted.
The end of season winner qualifies for the CAF Champions League, while the Cup of Zimbabwe winners gains entry into the CAF Confederation Cup, though clubs from the league do not always participate if they qualify. The current champions are Simba Bhora who won the 2024 Zimbabwe Premier Soccer League.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zimbabwe_Premier_Soccer_League</link></item></channel></rss>