<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Congressional Soccer Match</title><description>The Congressional Soccer Match (CSM) is an annual event held in Washington, D.C., that features Members of Congress, Hill staffers, corporations, and community members to participate in a soccer tournament.
The event consists of an Embassy tournament, the Congressional Soccer Match, and a Congressional Staff vs Lobbyist Match.
The event is hosted by the United States Soccer Foundation. As one of the Foundation’s annual charity events, all proceeds from the event support the Foundation’s life-changing programs that help children in underserved communities embrace active and healthy lifestyles while nurturing their personal growth through trained coach-mentors.
As of 2024, the defending champions are the Republicans.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Congressional_Soccer_Match</link></item><item><title>United States men's national under-23 soccer team</title><description>The United States U-23 men's national soccer team, also known as the United States men's Olympic soccer team, is a youth soccer team operated under the auspices of U.S. Soccer. Its primary role is qualification into and competition at the quadrennial Olympic Football Tournament, the next of which is to be held during the 2024 Summer Olympics in Paris, France. The team's most recent major tournament was the 2020 edition at the Tokyo Olympics, in which the United States team did not qualify. Their most recent qualification was the tournament at the 2008 Summer Olympics, where the team was eliminated in the group stage.
In accordance with FIFA regulations, the roster can be augmented with three "overage" players during Olympic competition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_under-23_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Canada men's national soccer team</title><description>The Canada men's national soccer team (French: Équipe du Canada de soccer masculin) represents Canada in international soccer competitions since 1924. They are overseen by the Canadian Soccer Association, the governing body for soccer in Canada. They have been a member of FIFA since 1948 and a member of CONCACAF since 1961.
Their most significant achievements are winning the 1985 CONCACAF Championship to qualify for the 1986 FIFA World Cup and winning the 2000 CONCACAF Gold Cup to qualify for the 2001 FIFA Confederations Cup. Canada is the only national team aside from regional powerhouses Mexico and the United States to win a Gold Cup. Canada also won a gold medal in the 1904 Summer Olympics. 
Canada participated in its second World Cup in 2022, is participating in its first Copa América in 2024, and will co-host, along with the United States and Mexico, the 2026 World Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>OneSoccer</title><description>OneSoccer is a Canadian category-B exempt English language television channel and English and French language subscription over-the-top video streaming service. The service broadcasts programming related to soccer including live and pre-taped games, recap shows, and more. It is the main rightsholder of the Canadian Soccer Association, including holding the rights to the Canadian Premier League, Canadian Championship, and national team matches. It is rightsholder for various CONCACAF competitions, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup and CONCACAF Champions Cup. In 2024, ownership of OneSoccer was transferred from Mediapro Canada to Timeless Inc.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OneSoccer</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season is the ongoing 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams are divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This is the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025. FC Cincinnati are the reigning Supporters' Shield holders; the Columbus Crew are the reigning MLS Cup champions.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and is scheduled to end on October 19, with a pause from mid-July to mid-August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprises all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup Playoffs are scheduled to begin in October and conclude with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS will only send 8 senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allows most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
This is the second season that Apple and MLS will be part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Miles Robinson (soccer)</title><description>Miles Gordon Robinson (born March 14, 1997) is an American professional soccer player who plays as a center-back for Major League Soccer club FC Cincinnati and the United States national team.
Born in Arlington, Massachusetts, Robinson began his career with FC Boston Bolts before playing college soccer with the Syracuse Orange. After two seasons with Syracuse, Robinson was drafted with the second overall pick in the 2017 MLS SuperDraft by expansion club Atlanta United. He initially did not feature for the side, and was loaned out to the Charleston Battery in 2017, followed by reserve affiliate Atlanta United 2 in 2018. From the 2019 season, Robinson began appearing as a regular starter for the club following the arrival of Frank de Boer as head coach.
Robinson made his senior debut for the United States in September 2019. In July 2021, he was selected as part of the 23-man squad for the CONCACAF Gold Cup. In the final against Mexico, Robinson scored the winner in extra-time to give the United States the championship.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miles_Robinson_(soccer)</link></item><item><title>2024 National Women's Soccer League season</title><description>The 2024 National Women's Soccer League season is the twelfth season of the National Women's Soccer League, the top division of women's soccer in the United States. Including the NWSL's two professional predecessors, Women's Professional Soccer (2009–2011) and the Women's United Soccer Association (2001–2003), it is the 18th overall season of FIFA and USSF-sanctioned top division women's soccer in the United States. The league has 14 teams following the addition of expansion teams Bay FC and Utah Royals—the latter being the revival of a team that had played in the league from 2018 to 2020.
The season began with the 2024 NWSL Challenge Cup, a supercup match between the reigning playoff champion (NJ/NY Gotham FC) and NWSL Shield winner San Diego Wave FC, on March 15, 2024. The regular season began the following day and will run until November 3; it will pause for a month between July 8 and August 18 for the 2024 Summer Olympics. Each team will play 26 matches, an increase of four from the 2023 season. The playoffs will comprise the top eight teams and run from November 9 to November 23. The 2024 season is the first under a new broadcast agreement with CBS Sports, ESPN, Amazon Prime Video and Scripps Sports; a total of 118 matches will be televised or streamed.
In addition to league play, 2024 marks the debut of the NWSL x Liga MX Femenil Summer Cup, an international competition between clubs from the NWSL and Liga MX Femenil of Mexico. It is scheduled to be played from July to October.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_National_Women%27s_Soccer_League_season</link></item><item><title>United States men's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, the best result ever by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups (seven consecutive appearances between 1990 and 2014), a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016. The team's head coach is Gregg Berhalter, who was re-appointed in June 2023.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item></channel></rss>