<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC is scheduled to join the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>Canada men's national under-17 soccer team</title><description>The Canada U-17 men's national soccer team (also known as Canada Under-17s or Canada U-17s) represents Canada in international soccer at this age level. They are overseen by the Canadian Soccer Association, the governing body for soccer in Canada.
Many of Canada's current internationals have played at one or more of these age levels early in their career, often working with the same coaches and teammates throughout their progression into the senior squad.
The team has qualified for eight out of nineteen FIFA U-17 World Cups.
The team also competes in the CONCACAF U-17 Championship.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_men%27s_national_under-17_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>Soccer on ESPN/ABC</title><description>Soccer on ESPN and ABC is a number of programs that currently airs soccer matches in the United States. These matches are from European competitions.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_ESPN/ABC</link></item><item><title>List of men's footballers with 1,000 or more official appearances</title><description>In association football, 52 players have played at least 1,000 official matches at all age levels. Regarding B teams and reserve teams, appearances for such teams are only included if made in the primary football pyramid and not in reserve divisions. Appearances made in youth football are not deemed to be official. War-time results are also excluded if they were later regarded as unofficial by the relevant Football Association(s); if they were included, Billy Meredith would be the first ever player to have played in 1,000 official matches, and Stanley Matthews would also make the list.
English goalkeeper Peter Shilton is generally considered the record holder for the most appearances, making 1,396 appearances between the 1960s and 1990s, including a national record of 125 appearances for England, and in 1996 became the first footballer to make 1,000 league appearances. However, in March 2022, Robert Carmona from Uruguay was reported as having played around 2,200 official matches.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_men%27s_footballers_with_1,000_or_more_official_appearances</link></item><item><title>2021 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2021 Major League Soccer season was the 26th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada. The 2021 season included the addition of Austin FC as an expansion club, which took the league to 27 teams.
Due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, the season was originally scheduled to begin on April 3, as opposed to the normal late February or early March start. This was later pushed back to April 16, the latest ever start to an MLS season, due to negotiations with the MLS Players Association for a new collective bargaining agreement. The regular season concluded on November 7. The 2021 MLS Cup Playoffs began on November 20, and concluded with MLS Cup 2021 on December 11.
At the beginning of the season, COVID-19 cross-border restrictions imposed by the Canadian government has also made the Canadian teams to play their home matches in the United States from the start of the season, while also sharing stadiums with other American MLS teams. On July 14, MLS announced that a select Toronto FC and CF Montréal matches would be played in Canada while working with the Canadian government on how the matches were to be held. Nearly a week later, the MLS announced that the Canadian teams would play home matches in Canada in August 2021.
The Columbus Crew were the defending champions, having defeated Seattle Sounders FC in MLS Cup 2020 but was eliminated from playoffs during the regular season, while the Philadelphia Union were the defending Supporters' Shield winners. The New England Revolution won their first Supporters' Shield, in the process breaking the record for most regular season points collected. New York City FC won their first ever MLS Cup, beating Portland Timbers in the decider.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2021_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>Canada women's national soccer team</title><description>The Canada men's national soccer team (French: Équipe du Canada de soccer masculin) represents Canada in international soccer competitions since 1924. They are overseen by the Canadian Soccer Association, the governing body for soccer in Canada. They have been a member of FIFA since 1948 and of CONCACAF since 1961.
Canada participated in its second World Cup in 2022 after finishing first in CONCACAF qualifying. Canada competed in its first Copa América in 2024, finishing fourth.
Previously, their top achievements were to win the 1985 CONCACAF Championship to qualify for the 1986 FIFA World Cup and winning the 2000 CONCACAF Gold Cup to qualify for the 2001 FIFA Confederations Cup. Canada is the only national team aside from regional powerhouses Mexico and the United States to win a Gold Cup. Canada also won a gold medal in the 1904 Summer Olympics.
Canada will co-host the 2026 World Cup along with the United States and Mexico.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item></channel></rss>