<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>Football at the 2024 Summer Olympics – Women's tournament</title><description>The women's football tournament at the 2024 Summer Olympics is held from 25 July to 10 August 2024. It is the eighth edition of the women's Olympic football tournament. Together with the men's competition, the 2024 Summer Olympics football tournament is held at seven stadiums in seven cities in France. The final will be held at Parc des Princes in Paris.
Canada were the defending champions, but were eliminated by Germany in the quarter-finals.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Football_at_the_2024_Summer_Olympics_%E2%80%93_Women%27s_tournament</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team results</title><description>The United States women's national soccer team was founded in 1985.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_women%27s_national_soccer_team_results</link></item><item><title>Soccer on Fox Sports</title><description>Fox currently airs soccer matches in the United States. These matches are from the FIFA World Cup, the FIFA Women's World Cup, the UEFA European Championship, the Gold Cup, Copa América, MLS, and Liga MX. Fox formerly aired the UEFA Champions League and UEFA Europa League, the Premier League, the Bundesliga, the Serie A, and the FA Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_Fox_Sports</link></item><item><title>Canada women's national soccer team</title><description>The Canada men's national soccer team (French: Équipe du Canada de soccer masculin) represents Canada in international soccer competitions since 1924. They are overseen by the Canadian Soccer Association, the governing body for soccer in Canada. They have been a member of FIFA since 1948 and of CONCACAF since 1961.
Canada participated in its second World Cup in 2022 after finishing first in CONCACAF qualifying. Canada competed in its first Copa América in 2024, finishing fourth.
Previously, their top achievements were to win the 1985 CONCACAF Championship to qualify for the 1986 FIFA World Cup and winning the 2000 CONCACAF Gold Cup to qualify for the 2001 FIFA Confederations Cup. Canada is the only national team aside from regional powerhouses Mexico and the United States to win a Gold Cup. Canada also won a gold medal in the 1904 Summer Olympics.
Canada will co-host, along with the United States and Mexico, the 2026 World Cup.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>United States men's national under-23 soccer team</title><description>The United States U-23 men's national soccer team, also known as the United States men's Olympic soccer team, is a youth soccer team operated under the auspices of U.S. Soccer. Its primary role is qualification into and competition at the quadrennial Olympic Football Tournament, the next of which is to be held during the 2028 Summer Olympics in Los Angeles. The team's most recent major tournament was the 2024 edition at the Paris Olympics, in which the team made it to the quarter-finals before being eliminated by Morocco.
In accordance with FIFA regulations, the roster can be augmented with three "overage" players during Olympic competition.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_under-23_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>List of El Clásico matches</title><description>This is a list of all matches contested between the Spanish football clubs Barcelona and Real Madrid, a fixture known as El Clásico.
The club name in bold indicates a win for that team. The score is given at full-time and half-time (in brackets), and in the goals columns, the goalscorer and time when goal was scored is noted.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_El_Cl%C3%A1sico_matches</link></item><item><title>United States women's national soccer team</title><description>The United States men's national soccer team (USMNT) represents the United States in men's international soccer competitions. The team is governed by the United States Soccer Federation, which is a member of FIFA and CONCACAF.
The U.S. has appeared in eleven FIFA World Cups, including the first in 1930, where they reached the semifinals; their third-place finish, which was later awarded through overall tournament records, is the best result by a team from outside UEFA and CONMEBOL. They returned in 1934 and 1950, defeating England 1–0 in the latter, but did not qualify again until 1990. As host in 1994, the U.S. received an automatic berth and lost to Brazil in the round of 16. They qualified for the next five World Cups, a feat shared with only seven other nations. The U.S. reached the quarterfinals at the 2002 World Cup, and eliminated top-ranked Spain in the 2009 Confederations Cup semifinals before losing to Brazil in the final.
The United States also competes in continental tournaments, including the CONCACAF Gold Cup, CONCACAF Nations League and Copa América. The U.S. has won seven Gold Cups, three Nations League titles, and finished fourth in two Copa América editions in 1995 and 2016.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_men%27s_national_soccer_team</link></item><item><title>2015 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup</title><description>The 2015 FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup was the eighth edition of the FIFA Beach Soccer World Cup, the premier international beach soccer competition for men's national teams, which has been organized by FIFA since 2005. Overall, this was the 18th edition of a world cup in beach soccer since the establishment of the Beach Soccer World Championships which ran from 1995 to 2004 but was not governed by FIFA. It was also the third edition to take place under the biennial system introduced in 2009.
The tournament took place from 9 to 19 July 2015 at Praia da Baía in Espinho, Portugal, after the country's bid was selected by the FIFA Executive Committee on 28 May 2013, from among twelve proposals. This was the second time that Portugal hosted a FIFA competition, after the 1991 FIFA World Youth Championship. Fifteen teams advanced through their respective continental qualification competitions to join the host team in the final tournament. The final draw occurred on 28 April 2015 at the Espinho Multimedia Auditorium, setting up a total of 32 matches that were played at the Espinho Stadium – a purpose-built temporary venue with a capacity of 3,500 – and attended by a total of 96,300 people.
After missing the previous edition, Portugal reached the final – eliminating two-time defending champions Russia in the semi-finals – and defeated first-time finalists Tahiti 5–3 to claim their second world title and their first in the FIFA era. Alan and Madjer were the only two surviving players from the Portuguese squad that won their previous world title in 2001 to also win these championships.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2015_FIFA_Beach_Soccer_World_Cup</link></item></channel></rss>