<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Important Soccer Matches Today</title><link>http://example.com/soccer_matches</link><description>RSS feed of important soccer matches that happened on this day in history.</description><item><title>2025 Big 12 Conference women's soccer tournament</title><description>The 2025 Big 12 Conference women's soccer tournament was the postseason women's soccer tournament for the Big 12 Conference held from November 3 to November 8, 2025.  The conference announced the 7-match tournament would be held at Garvey-Rosenthal Soccer Stadium in Fort Worth, Texas with the Championship game at Betty Lou Mays Soccer Field in Waco, Texas.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_Big_12_Conference_women%27s_soccer_tournament</link></item><item><title>Soccer on CBS Sports</title><description>Soccer on CBS Sports is a number of television programs that have aired soccer matches in the United States on CBS, CBS Sports Network, Paramount+ (formerly CBS All Access) and CBS Sports Golazo Network. These matches are from International, European, and American competitions.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soccer_on_CBS_Sports</link></item><item><title>2025 ACC women's soccer tournament</title><description>The 2025 Atlantic Coast Conference women's soccer tournament was the post season women's soccer tournament for the Atlantic Coast Conference, held from November 2 through November 9, 2025. The five-match tournament took place at campus sites for the quarterfinals and First Horizon Stadium in Cary, North Carolina for the semifinals and final. The higher seed hosted the campus site matches. The six-team single-elimination tournament consisted of three rounds based on seeding from regular season conference play. The Florida State Seminoles were the five-time defending champions. The Seminoles were unable to defend their title, as they lost in a penalty shoot-out in the First Round. The final was contested by the first seed Stanford and second seed Notre Dame, who were also the first and second ranked teams in the United Soccer Coaches Poll at the time of the match. The teams played to a 2–2 draw, and Stanford prevailed 5–4 in the ensuing penalty shoot-out. This was Stanford's first ACC tournament title, after they joined the conference last year. It was also the first title for head coach Paul Ratcliffe. As tournament champions, Stanford earned the ACC's automatic berth into the 2025 NCAA Division I women's soccer tournament.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_ACC_women%27s_soccer_tournament</link></item><item><title>2024 Major League Soccer season</title><description>The 2024 Major League Soccer season was the 29th season of Major League Soccer (MLS), the top professional soccer league in the United States and Canada, and the 46th season overall of a national first-division league in the United States.
The league's 29 teams were divided into the Eastern and Western conferences. This was the first season since the 2016 season to have no new expansion teams joining MLS; San Diego FC joined the league in 2025.
Pre-season matches ran from January 19 through February 17. The regular season began on February 21 and ended on October 19, with a pause from late July to late August for the 2024 Leagues Cup, which comprised all MLS and Liga MX teams. The 2024 MLS Cup playoffs began on October 22 and concluded with MLS Cup 2024 on December 7. MLS only sent eight senior squads to the 2024 U.S. Open Cup as part of a compromise with the USSF that allowed most teams to be represented by MLS Next Pro teams.
The Columbus Crew were the reigning MLS Cup champions and FC Cincinnati were the Supporters' Shield holders; St. Louis City SC were the reigning Western Conference champions. In their fifth season in the league, Inter Miami CF won the Supporters' Shield for the first time, earning an league-record 74 points. The LA Galaxy won a record sixth MLS Cup, and a first since 2014, after defeating the New York Red Bulls 2–1 at Dignity Health Sports Park in Carson, California.
This was the second season that Apple and MLS were part of a ten-year partnership for the broadcast and streaming rights to all MLS and Leagues Cup games, as well as select MLS Next and MLS Next Pro games, on the MLS Season Pass service within the Apple TV app.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Major_League_Soccer_season</link></item><item><title>2024 SEC women's soccer tournament</title><description>The 2024 SEC women's soccer tournament was the postseason women's soccer tournament for the Southeastern Conference held from November 3 to November 10, 2024. The tournament was held at the Ashton Brosnaham Soccer Complex in Pensacola, Florida.  The twelve-team single elimination tournament consisted of four rounds based on seeding from regular season conference play.  The Georgia Bulldogs are the defending champions. The Bulldogs were unable to defend their crown as the seventh seed, losing to second seed Arkansas in the Quarterfinals.  third seed Texas went on to win the tournament with a 2–1 overtime victory over Arkansas in the final. The conference championship is the first SEC title for the Texas women's soccer program, and first for head coach Angela Kelly.  However, Kelly has won four previous SEC tournament titles with Tennessee. This is Texas' fourth overall conference title, as the won three Big 12 tournament titles before moving to the SEC. As tournament champions, Texas earned the Southeastern Conference's automatic berth into the 2024 NCAA Division I women's soccer tournament.</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_SEC_women%27s_soccer_tournament</link></item><item><title>2024 Big 12 Conference women's soccer tournament</title><description>The 2024 Big 12 Conference women's soccer tournament is the postseason women's soccer tournament for the Big 12 Conference held from October 30 to November 9, 2024.  The conference announced the 11-match tournament would be held at CPKC Stadium in Kansas City, Missouri for the 2024 and 2025 season.  It also would expand to twelve teams with the addition of Arizona, Arizona State, Colorado and Utah.
The 12-team single-elimination tournament will consist of the top four seeds receiving a bye into the quarterfinals and seeds five through twelve playing in a bracket style tournament.

</description><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2024_Big_12_Conference_women%27s_soccer_tournament</link></item></channel></rss>